<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Press Releases - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/press-releases/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/press-releases/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 07:39:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Press Releases - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/press-releases/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FUN Token Unveils 2025 Roadmap to Transform Gaming Into a Rewarding Digital Economy</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/fun-token-2025-roadmap/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 07:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=686406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>FUN Token, a pioneer at the intersection of Web3 and gaming, has revealed its ambitious roadmap for 2025–2026, marking a new stage in the development of digital gaming. With a clear mission to improve the gaming experience, FUN is building a closed-loop, player-first ecosystem where games are more than play—they’re a pathway to real value. &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fun-token-2025-roadmap/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fun-token-2025-roadmap/">FUN Token Unveils 2025 Roadmap to Transform Gaming Into a Rewarding Digital Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>FUN Token, a pioneer at the intersection of Web3 and gaming, has revealed its ambitious roadmap for 2025–2026, marking a new stage in the development of digital gaming. With a clear mission to improve the gaming experience, FUN is building a closed-loop, player-first ecosystem where games are more than play—they’re a pathway to real value.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfIDOiP4bZd-HcSmDuLj4n7CL0xJ7vfXyflpKZ7tJabJugLDV6xz-aIvo_RPdCHG7EsToU816Yf532aHjvpxKH69UacwRjcoJDcixyCqGg6pkQQ9skPdJsFKsbqd8QGPDs53V8B?key=cIkVlVZE-tvvxIWrQQ42lGBx" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gaming-is-broken-fun-token-offers-an-alternative-approach"><strong>Gaming is broken— </strong><strong>FUN Token offers an alternative approach</strong></h2>



<p>In a world where players are bombarded with ads and pushed into endless in-app purchases, FUN flips the script. The team is building a player-first ecosystem where gamers get paid to play. No more paywalls, no more attention traps—just seamless gameplay, real rewards, and a token economy that values your time and skill. FUN Token is re-empowering the player and redefining what gaming should be.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-mission-play-with-purpose-earn-with-fun"><strong>Mission: Play with purpose, earn with FUN</strong></h2>



<p>At the heart of the FUN Token project is a simple but transformative idea: empower gamers to earn tangible value doing what they love. By embedding FUN as the core currency across a growing portfolio of games, the team aims to unify the fragmented Web3 gaming space into a seamless, rewarding experience for players worldwide.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-core-strategy-how-fun-is-redefining-the-game"><strong>The core strategy: How FUN is redefining the game</strong></h2>



<p>The <a href="https://funtoken.io/road-map" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">FUN roadmap</a> is anchored on four powerful pillars:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Closed-loop ecosystem:</strong> One wallet. One login. Endless games. FUN is creating a frictionless environment where players can move effortlessly between titles, with all progress, rewards, and identity preserved.</li>



<li><strong>Token utility &amp; buy-and-burn engine:</strong> Players earn FUN tokens in-game. Revenues from those games are then used to buy FUN on the open market and burn it—reducing supply and boosting token value over time.</li>



<li><strong>Gamified rewards &amp; retention:</strong> XP systems, loot boxes, streaks, and seasonal quests all reward active participation. FUN is building for stickiness—turning casual players into loyal, lifetime users.</li>



<li><strong>Strategic partnerships:</strong> By integrating FUN into third-party titles, the team is positioning the token as the <strong>&#8220;Universal Currency of the Gamingverse.&#8221;</strong> One token to connect them all.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-fun-grand-plan-from-foundation-to-domination"><strong>The FUN Grand Plan: From foundation to domination</strong></h2>



<p>&nbsp;The roadmap is structured and focused on measurable growth.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-q2-2025-launch-the-foundation"><strong>Q2 2025 – Launch the foundation</strong></h3>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Release 10 mobile games across Android and iOS</li>



<li>Launch web-based FUN Wallet</li>



<li>Introduce Unified Login for cross-game access</li>



<li>Kickstart the &#8220;Earn-While-You-Play&#8221; movement</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-q3-2025-spark-the-network-effect"><strong>Q3 2025 – Spark the network effect</strong></h3>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Add 10 more viral/hyper-casual games</li>



<li>Reach 1M+ players and 100K+ wallet users</li>



<li>Launch achievement systems and daily missions</li>



<li>Begin Buy-and-Burn token mechanics</li>



<li>Establish first wave of third-party game partnerships</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-q4-2025-scale-the-ecosystem"><strong>Q4 2025 – Scale the ecosystem</strong></h3>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Expand to 30 total games</li>



<li>Hit 5M+ users, 500K+ wallets</li>



<li>Launch mobile FUN Wallet (iOS &amp; Android) with staking and rewards</li>



<li>Introduce NFTs, leaderboards, and community quests</li>



<li>Onboard mid-size external studios</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-q1-2026-dominate-web3-gaming"><strong>Q1 2026 – Dominate Web3 gaming</strong></h3>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Grow to 40 games across genres</li>



<li>Reach 10M+ players, 1M+ wallet holders</li>



<li>Add multi-chain and fiat support in FUN Wallet</li>



<li>Integrate FUN into external game economies</li>



<li>Host the inaugural <strong>Global FUN Gaming Summit</strong></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-universe-of-fun-awaits"><strong>A universe of FUN awaits</strong></h2>



<p>FUN Token invites players, developers, and investors to join the movement and be part of the ecosystem that’s set to reshape the future of entertainment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-fun-token"><strong>About FUN Token</strong></h2>



<p>FUN Token is on a mission to become the default digital currency of gaming. Powered by Web3 technology and backed by a vibrant, self-sustaining economy, FUN is creating a unified ecosystem where every game, action, and user contributes to a dynamic gaming universe. Learn more at <a href="https://funtoken.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website.</a></p>



<p>FUNToken.io Socials: <a href="https://x.com/FUNtoken_io" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a> | <a href="https://t.me/officialFUNToken">Telegram</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fun-token-2025-roadmap/">FUN Token Unveils 2025 Roadmap to Transform Gaming Into a Rewarding Digital Economy</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/funtoken__pr_720.jpg" medium="image" width="720" height="480" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/funtoken__pr_720.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gate.io Celebrates 12th Anniversary with a Major Brand Upgrade: Opening the Gateway to the Future of Crypto</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-12th-anniversary-brand-upgrade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=686054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Global leading cryptocurrency exchange Gate.io is marking a significant milestone—its 12th anniversary—by unveiling a comprehensive brand upgrade, including the debut of its new official Chinese name, &#8220;Damen&#8220; (大门, meaning &#8220;The Gate&#8220;).  Under the theme &#8220;12 Years, One Gate, One World&#8221;, Gate.io reflects on its journey of growth and transformation, while embracing a bold new vision &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-12th-anniversary-brand-upgrade/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-12th-anniversary-brand-upgrade/">Gate.io Celebrates 12th Anniversary with a Major Brand Upgrade: Opening the Gateway to the Future of Crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Global leading cryptocurrency exchange <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44396/?ch=GM_Gate12bein_20250411&amp;utm_campaign=TR_96Ojxagz&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> is marking a significant milestone—its 12th anniversary—by unveiling a comprehensive brand upgrade, including the debut of its new official Chinese name, &#8220;<em>Damen</em>&#8220;<em> </em>(大门, meaning &#8220;<em>The Gate</em>&#8220;). </p>



<p>Under the theme &#8220;12 Years, One Gate, One World&#8221;, Gate.io reflects on its journey of growth and transformation, while embracing a bold new vision for the future, showcasing its ambition to build a more open, diverse, and innovative Web3 ecosystem for users worldwide.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-12-years-of-innovation-establishing-prestigious-global-leadership"><strong>12 Years of Innovation: Establishing Prestigious Global Leadership</strong></h2>



<p>Since its inception in 2013, <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44396/?ch=GM_Gate12bein_20250411&amp;utm_campaign=TR_96Ojxagz&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> has emerged as a blockchain innovation powerhouse, offering reliable and versatile digital asset trading services. Today, Gate.io has grown into a top global leading crypto exchange, serving over 22 million users globally, consistently ranking among the top three exchanges by liquidity and ranking top 2 in 24-hour spot trading volume. </p>



<p>The platform supports over 3,800 cryptocurrencies across spot trading, futures, leverage, and other financial products, offering a wide range of investment opportunities.</p>



<p>Among the keystones cementing Gate.io&#8217;s dominance in crypto space, GateToken (GT), Gate.io&#8217;s native platform token, has been a cornerstone of its ecosystem since the launch of GateChain&#8217;s mainnet in 2019. GT reached an all-time high of $25.960, with a total market capitalization surpassing $2.94 billion, propelling its market rank into the global Top 40.</p>



<p>Moreover, Gate.io&#8217;s established crypto financial ecosystem has also played a crucial role in driving industry transparency. As the first mainstream exchange to commit to 100% proof of reserves, it partnered with U.S. audit firm Armanino LLP, leveraging the Merkle Tree open-source framework for regular asset reserve disclosures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As of January 17, 2025, Gate.io&#8217;s total reserves exceeded $10 billion, ranking fourth globally, with an above-average reserve ratio of 128.58%, ensuring verifiability and security for user assets.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-cross-industry-partnerships-expanding-web3-s-global-influence"><strong>Cross-Industry Partnerships: Expanding Web3&#8217;s Global Influence</strong></h2>



<p>Gate.io is actively fostering cross-industry partnerships to elevate the crypto industry&#8217;s global reach. In 2024, Gate.io partnered with FC Internazionale Milano, or Inter, marking a new era of integration between crypto and traditional sports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the Official Sleeve Partner for Inter, Gate.io&#8217;s brand images have been prominently featured at San Siro Stadium, Serie A, and UEFA Champions League matches. Through VIP events and joint activities, Gate.io is bringing crypto closer to football enthusiasts, building a global fan community, and exploring new possibilities for sports and digital assets.</p>



<p>In the first quarter of 2025, Gate.io announced a landmark sponsorship deal with Oracle Red Bull Racing in Formula 1, becoming the team&#8217;s exclusive cryptocurrency exchange partner. As an eight-time F1 world champion, Oracle Red Bull Racing is synonymous with excellence and speed, a vision that aligns with Gate.io&#8217;s cutting-edge innovation in digital finance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This partnership is a strategic milestone, accelerating blockchain adoption and expanding Web3 solutions to a broader global audience.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-strategic-brand-upgrade-embracing-a-new-identity-for-the-future"><strong>Strategic Brand Upgrade: Embracing A New Identity for the Future</strong></h2>



<p>Over the past 12 years, Gate.io has witnessed the rapid evolution of the crypto industry and proactively adapted to market shifts. From a Bitcoin trading platform to a comprehensive blockchain ecosystem, Gate.io is now embracing its next evolution with the introduction of the new Chinese Name &#8220;<em>Damen</em>&#8220;<em> </em>(meaning &#8220;<em>The Gate&#8221;</em>).&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new brand identity symbolizes openness, fairness, and innovation, reflecting Gate.io&#8217;s commitment to bridging the global crypto economy with cutting-edge technology and trusted financial infrastructure.</p>



<p>More than just a name change, this brand evolution marks a strategic upgrade—shifting from a traditional exchange to a fully integrated Web3 ecosystem. Under this new vision, Gate.io is focused on enhancing user experience, driving technological innovation, and expanding decentralized finance solutions, making blockchain technology more accessible, secure, and intuitive for users worldwide.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-commemorating-12-years-with-exclusive-events-in-dubai"><strong>Commemorating 12 Years with Exclusive Events in Dubai</strong></h2>



<p>To celebrate this milestone, Gate.io will host a series of flagship events in Dubai on April 29-30, 2025, to join hands with global users and industry partners. The 12th Anniversary Celebration is expected to attract over a thousand top global investors, blockchain entrepreneurs, project teams, and industry leaders, joining Gate.io in celebrating this significant occasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Adding to the festivities, SPORT3 DUBAI 2025 will introduce a unique blend of sports and blockchain, creating a dynamic and engaging atmosphere for industry professionals to connect. Through this initiative, Gate.io aims to foster cross-industry collaboration, encourage meaningful dialogue, and drive innovation in blockchain-powered sports applications.</p>



<p>Twelve years of trust, growth, and groundbreaking innovation have brought Gate.io to this defining moment. From the &#8220;Gateway to Crypto&#8221; over a decade ago to pioneering the next chapter of blockchain evolution, the platform remains committed to its mission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Standing at the crossroads of a new era, Gate.io embraces its new transformation, not just a rebrand, but as a renewed commitment to empowering users, advancing technology, and shaping the future of the blockchain ecosystem. As Gate.io unveils its next chapter, it continues to open the gateway to crypto for global users, bridging today&#8217;s world with the boundless possibilities of the crypto future.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. Please note that virtual assets may depreciate in value fully or partially, and are susceptible to significant fluctuations. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please note<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> is not licensed or regulated by the Virtual Asset Regulatory Authority (VARA) and hence not permitted to conduct virtual asset related activities in/from Dubai. The products and/or services mentioned herein are only available to persons outside Dubai. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-12th-anniversary-brand-upgrade/">Gate.io Celebrates 12th Anniversary with a Major Brand Upgrade: Opening the Gateway to the Future of Crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-87.png" medium="image" width="2494" height="1390" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-87.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stake Ethereum, Win Rewards: COCA Launches 1 ETH Giveaway</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/coca-launches-1-eth-giveaway/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crypto Airdrop News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>COCA Wallet introduces an exclusive staking incentive, rewarding 10 lucky users with 0.1 ETH each — just for staking a minimum of 0.1 ETH. COCA, the non-custodial crypto super app, today announced the launch of its “Stake &#38; Win” campaign in partnership with Everstake, a global non-custodial staking provider, offering users the opportunity to win &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coca-launches-1-eth-giveaway/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coca-launches-1-eth-giveaway/">Stake Ethereum, Win Rewards: COCA Launches 1 ETH Giveaway</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>COCA Wallet introduces an exclusive staking incentive, rewarding 10 lucky users with 0.1 ETH each — just for staking a minimum of 0.1 ETH.</strong></p>



<p>COCA, the non-custodial crypto super app, today announced the launch of its “Stake &amp; Win” campaign in partnership with Everstake, a global non-custodial staking provider, offering users the opportunity to win a share of 1 ETH simply by staking Ethereum via the COCA Wallet. This follows the successful debut of Ethereum staking in partnership with Everstake.</p>



<p>Running from <strong>April 11 to June 11, 2025</strong>, the campaign invites users to stake at least <strong>0.1 ETH</strong> in a single transaction. Those who do are automatically entered to win one of <strong>10 rewards of 0.1 ETH each</strong>—no additional steps required.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-campaign-highlights"><strong>Campaign Highlights:</strong></h2>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Start Date:</strong> April 11, 2025<br></li>



<li><strong>End Date:</strong> June 11, 2025<br></li>



<li><strong>Winners Announced:</strong> June 16, 2025<br></li>



<li><strong>Minimum Stake:</strong> 0.1 ETH<br></li>



<li><strong>Prize Pool:</strong> 1 ETH total, split among 10 winners (0.1 ETH each)<br></li>



<li><strong>Eligibility:</strong> Must be 18+ and hold staked ETH for at least one month</li>
</ul>



<p>For the terms of the Campaign, please refer to the <a href="https://everstake.one/sweepstakes-general-rules" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sweepstake General Rules</a>. Participation in this Campaign is strictly optional and is also subject to the Terms of Use and Privacy Notice.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-fair-play-first"><strong>Fair Play First</strong></h2>



<p>To ensure fairness, COCA will disqualify entries exhibiting suspicious or manipulative behavior, including fund shuffling between personal accounts or use of multiple wallet identities.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Staking should be both secure and rewarding,” said Vasili Palau, CEO of COCA. “We’re making it easier than ever for users to earn with their crypto, and now we’re giving them a chance to win too—just by doing what they already love.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This giveaway is part of COCA’s broader mission to make decentralized finance intuitive and accessible. By combining industry-leading MPC-based security, anonymous biometric backups, and a seamless user interface, COCA is redefining the crypto wallet experience.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-get-started-now"><strong>Get Started Now</strong></h2>



<p>Download the COCA Wallet, stake your ETH, and you could be among the lucky 10 to walk away with extra crypto.</p>



<p><img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f517.png" alt="🔗" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> Get Started: <a href="https://www.coca.xyz">&nbsp;</a><a href="https://www.coca.xyz" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.coca.xyz</a></p>



<p>Need help getting started? Follow the step-by-step guide to staking ETH in the COCA Wallet here:<a href="https://www.coca.xyz/post/how-to-stake-and-unstake-eth-in-coca-wallet" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">How to Stake and Unstake ETH in COCA Wallet</a></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-coca"><strong>About COCA</strong></h2>



<p>COCA is a next-gen non-custodial crypto super app supporting over 350 tokens across 14 blockchains. With powerful staking options, global crypto cards, and advanced MPC security, COCA empowers users to manage, grow, and spend their crypto assets—all from one secure, intuitive platform.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-everstake"><strong>About Everstake</strong></h2>



<p>Everstake, founded in 2018 by blockchain engineers, is a leading global non-custodial staking provider for both institutional and retail clients, on a mission to make staking accessible to everyone. Operating across 80+ networks with 735,000+ delegators, it delivers institutional-grade infrastructure with 99.9% uptime. Through strategic partnerships with industry leaders, Everstake strengthens the staking ecosystem and provides white-label staking solutions, enabling businesses to easily integrate staking into their platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Everstake is a software platform that provides infrastructure tools and resources for users but does not offer investment advice or investment opportunities, manage funds, facilitate collective investment schemes, provide financial services or take custody of, or otherwise hold or manage, customer assets. Everstake does not conduct any independent diligence on or substantive review of any blockchain asset, digital currency, cryptocurrency or associated funds. Everstake’s provision of technology services allowing a user to stake digital assets is not an endorsement or a recommendation of any digital assets by it. Users are fully and solely responsible for evaluating whether to stake digital assetsю</p>



<p>For more information, visit: <a href="https://www.everstake.one" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">www.everstake.one</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coca-launches-1-eth-giveaway/">Stake Ethereum, Win Rewards: COCA Launches 1 ETH Giveaway</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-16.10.20.png" medium="image" width="944" height="500" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-16.10.20.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Gold to Crypto: The Rise of Tokenized Gold and RWA Assets Amid Market Uncertainty</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/tokenized-gold-rwa-rise-market-uncertainty/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 09:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTX (Huobi) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a leading global digital asset trading platform, HTX provides a secure and efficient trading environment, notably through its XAUT/USDT trading pair. In light of recent market volatility, HTX emphasizes its role in supporting investors seeking stable assets within the Real-World Assets (RWA) sector. The platform offers diverse financial instruments, enabling wider participation in crypto &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/tokenized-gold-rwa-rise-market-uncertainty/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/tokenized-gold-rwa-rise-market-uncertainty/">From Gold to Crypto: The Rise of Tokenized Gold and RWA Assets Amid Market Uncertainty</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a leading global digital asset trading platform, HTX provides a secure and efficient trading environment, notably through its XAUT/USDT trading pair. In light of recent market volatility, HTX emphasizes its role in supporting investors seeking stable assets within the Real-World Assets (RWA) sector. The platform offers diverse financial instruments, enabling wider participation in crypto gold investments, designed to mitigate risks during periods of market uncertainty.</p>



<p>The cryptocurrency market has recently experienced significant turbulence, with total market capitalization falling below $2.7 trillion and a 7% single-day decline on April 7, driven by U.S. policy-induced volatility.&nbsp; In times of heightened market uncertainty, gold traditionally serves as a recognized safe haven. With the closing price of gold stood at $3,037 per ounce, gold-backed crypto assets have similarly&nbsp; demonstrated resilience. Assets such as XAUT (Tether Gold), representing&nbsp; &#8220;crypto gold&#8221;, available on HTX, are increasingly favored by investors seeking portfolio diversification and stability.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-macroeconomic-pressures-drive-demand-for-gold-and-tokenized-alternatives"><strong>Macroeconomic Pressures Drive Demand for Gold and Tokenized Alternatives</strong></h2>



<p>Recent U.S. policy announcements, including the imposition of&nbsp; a 10% &#8220;minimum benchmark tariff&#8221; on global imports and retaliatory tariffs, precipitated substantial market instability.&nbsp; The U.S. Nasdaq index experienced a 12% market capitalization contraction within two days, marking a significant global decline. . This turbulence has extended to the crypto market, causing substantial declines in major assets like Bitcoin and Ethereum.（ As of the release time on April 10th, tariff-related policies have been paused, leading to a rebound in the cryptocurrency market .）<br><br>In this context, gold and tokenized gold assets, particularly XAUT, have showcased stability, reinforcing their status as secure investment tools.&nbsp; XAUT&#8217;s blockchain-enabled infrastructure provides immediate gold delivery and global access, streamlining investment compared to traditional gold futures.</p>



<p>Increased strategic reserve demand, with global central banks accumulating over 1,000 tons of gold in three consecutive years, and institutional interest in tokenized gold for U.S. dollar credit risk mitigation, further bolster the appeal of assets like XAUT. Its transparent 1:1 physical gold backing and on-chain traceability make it a strategic asset for sovereign wealth funds and multinational corporations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-xaut-demonstrates-resilience-amidst-market-uncertainty"><strong>XAUT Demonstrates Resilience Amidst Market Uncertainty</strong></h2>



<p>XAUT, a gold-backed token issued by Tether, is pegged to 1 troy ounce of London Bullion Market Association (LBMA) accredited physical gold and fully backed by Tether&#8217;s gold reserves. As traditional gold prices rise, XAUT demonstrates parallel performance. According to<a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/currencies/tether-gold/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> CoinMarketCap data</a>, when the overall crypto market plunged on April 7, XAUT fell by just 0.08</p>



<p>%.<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfoqys8XZshq84Scb97iqigrxTewb3M53zY0FkYpKP_-f1az0QyRKyzmVfLTDAVqHAvJSgSf29bwBKDGgvYeHt2Y6BXmc9GqpklAAeNfLe1sNTTqq2NEj9e83MndnVPyoskF_lwbg?key=esAsiQ6u3qrPdx2MsT3idlzQ" width="525" height="351"></p>



<p><a href="https://www.htx.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Image from HTX&#8217;s data on April 7</strong></a></p>



<p>HTX provides access to the superior liquidity and 24/7 trading of crypto gold assets, along with their seamless integration into the DeFi ecosystem. Fractional ownership and instant transaction settlement, available through HTX, address the challenges of traditional gold investments.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfzi7NF2bZO-OoD4TbnUDbZT4JfarxBg92LZGJrmp9df44c5rzf2dpFVFekfMJ6CqXBSMakXXMTGyHsDXgpjohwLIBgzpUCQzLwkVkkaAVJfykwNdipuLiQ2kl7AD9BO8pnu_2W1A?key=esAsiQ6u3qrPdx2MsT3idlzQ" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-rwa-era-tokenization-of-real-world-assets-gains-momentum"><strong>The RWA Era: Tokenization of Real-World Assets Gains Momentum</strong></h2>



<p>XAUT&#8217;s resilience during market downturns underscores both gold&#8217;s safe-haven status and the accelerating development of Real-World Assets (RWA) within the crypto space. This rapidly expanding sector, encompassing stablecoins, tokenized treasury bills, and on-chain representations of traditional assets like gold and real estate, is fueled by increasing institutional and investor adoption of blockchain for enhanced liquidity and accessibility.<br><br>Looking ahead, the RWA sector is poised for accelerated growth, unlocking substantial opportunities for traditional asset tokenization. Crypto gold assets, such as XAUT, provide crucial asset allocation stability during market fluctuations. HTX, with its secure and liquid ecosystem, serves as a crucial gateway for individual and institutional investors seeking stability and growth in an evolving market, and enter the new era of RWA assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Note: Data in this article is as of April 7, 2025. The market involves risks, and investment should be made with caution.)</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-htx"><strong>About HTX</strong></h2>



<p>Founded in 2013, HTX has evolved from a virtual asset exchange into a comprehensive ecosystem of blockchain businesses that span digital asset trading, financial derivatives, research, investments, incubation, and other businesses.</p>



<p>As a world-leading gateway to Web3, HTX harbors global capabilities that enable it to provide users with safe and reliable services. Adhering to the growth strategy of &#8220;Global Expansion, Thriving Ecosystem, Wealth Effect, Security &amp; Compliance,&#8221; HTX is dedicated to providing quality services and values to virtual asset enthusiasts worldwide.</p>



<p>To learn more about HTX, please visit<a href="https://square.htx.com/zh/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> HTX Square</a> or<a href="https://www.htx.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> https://www.htx.com/</a>, and follow HTX on<a href="https://x.com/HTX_Global?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor"> </a><a href="https://x.com/HTX_Global?ref_src=twsrc%5Egoogle%7Ctwcamp%5Eserp%7Ctwgr%5Eauthor" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">X</a>,<a href="https://t.me/htxglobalofficial" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Telegram</a>, and<a href="https://discord.com/invite/htx-official" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Discord</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/tokenized-gold-rwa-rise-market-uncertainty/">From Gold to Crypto: The Rise of Tokenized Gold and RWA Assets Amid Market Uncertainty</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-10-в-12.13.51.png" medium="image" width="984" height="472" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-10-в-12.13.51.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fetch.ai and Nuklai Highlight the Rise of Autonomous AI Agents at Decentral House</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/fetch-ai-nuklai-autonomous-agents-decentral-house/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 08:26:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685546</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a compelling evening that brought together Web3 leaders, technologists, and innovators, Decentral House welcomed over 100 participants for a deep dive into the convergence of AI and blockchain, two of the most transformative technologies shaping the future. Titled “AI Agents &#38; Web3: The Future is Taking Shape”, the event featured prominent speakers Maria Minaricova, &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fetch-ai-nuklai-autonomous-agents-decentral-house/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fetch-ai-nuklai-autonomous-agents-decentral-house/">Fetch.ai and Nuklai Highlight the Rise of Autonomous AI Agents at Decentral House</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a compelling evening that brought together Web3 leaders, technologists, and innovators, Decentral House welcomed over 100 participants for a deep dive into the convergence of AI and blockchain, two of the most transformative technologies shaping the future.</p>



<p>Titled “<strong>AI Agents &amp; Web3: The Future is Taking Shape</strong>”, the event featured prominent speakers Maria Minaricova, Director at Fetch.ai Foundation, and Mattijs de Vries, Founder of Nuklai, who explored the practical applications of autonomous AI agents within decentralized ecosystems.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ai-agents-beyond-the-buzz">AI Agents: Beyond the Buzz</h2>



<p>Autonomous agents, software entities capable of making decisions, executing transactions, and communicating with other agents or systems are rapidly transitioning from conceptual to operational.</p>



<p>During her keynote, Maria Minaricova positioned these agents as fundamental building blocks of tomorrow’s internet infrastructure.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“People say data is the new oil but we believe it’s the new oxygen,” <strong>said Minaricova.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“AI Agents today are like websites in the early 2000s: those who understand and experiment with them now will be the ones defining the digital economy of the future.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Her remarks underscored Fetch.ai’s core mission: to create open, decentralized systems where autonomous agents enhance coordination, reduce inefficiencies, and unlock new economic models.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-building-smart-data-infrastructure">Building Smart Data Infrastructure</h2>



<p>Joining Minaricova on stage was Mattijs de Vries, whose company Nuklai is building data collaboration frameworks designed to power the next generation of AI systems.</p>



<p>He emphasized the importance of building intelligent infrastructure that allows machines to learn and interact securely via blockchain.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Data today is fragmented, underutilized, and often locked in silos. By connecting AI and blockchain, we’re building environments where data doesn’t just sit, it becomes actionable.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Both speakers agreed: autonomous systems are no longer theoretical. They are being deployed today, and the momentum is accelerating.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-decentral-house-a-home-for-innovation-in-the-heart-of-geneva">Decentral House: A Home for Innovation in the Heart of Geneva</h2>



<p>This event is part of Decentral House’s ongoing mission to position Geneva as a European capital for blockchain innovation, connecting legal, financial, and technological communities in one ecosystem.</p>



<p>Located at the crossroads of diplomacy and finance, Decentral House serves as a hub for Web3 professionals, offering workspace solutions, startup support, and a curated calendar of thought leadership events.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Our goal is to build a community where ideas are tested, launched, and scaled — not just discussed,”” said Elli Koch from Decentral House.</p>
</blockquote>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Bringing in projects like Fetch.ai and Nuklai reflects our drive to turn new ideas into action and move technology forward..”</p>
</blockquote>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-next-steps-from-insight-to-implementation">Next Steps: From Insight to Implementation</h2>



<p>Following the panel, participants engaged in a lively Q&amp;A and networking session, sparking conversations around quantum computing, regulatory frameworks, and ethical AI deployment. The evening ended with a shared sentiment:</p>



<p>The future is happening now, and those who lean in early will shape what comes next.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"/>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-fetch-ai-foundation">About Fetch.ai Foundation</h2>



<p><a href="https://fetch.ai" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fetch.ai</a> is a decentralized platform that enables the creation and deployment of autonomous agents for data sharing, automation, and decentralized transactions. By combining machine learning and blockchain, Fetch.ai enables real-time optimization of complex systems such as transportation, supply chains, and energy grids.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-nuklai">About Nuklai</h2>



<p><a href="https://www.nukl.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Nuklai</a> is building collaborative data infrastructure for AI-powered systems. The company focuses on unlocking the full value of data through decentralization, community ownership, and advanced knowledge graphs to train intelligent agents.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-decentral-house">About Decentral House</h2>



<p>Decentral House, powered by <a href="https://storm.partners/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">STORM Partners</a>, is Geneva’s premier innovation hub dedicated to the Web3 industry. Offering coworking spaces, business domiciliation, and a rich program of events, Decentral House is designed to foster collaboration and accelerate the adoption of decentralized technologies across Europe and beyond.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fetch-ai-nuklai-autonomous-agents-decentral-house/">Fetch.ai and Nuklai Highlight the Rise of Autonomous AI Agents at Decentral House</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-10-в-11.24.52.png" medium="image" width="756" height="460" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-10-в-11.24.52.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gate Q1 2025 Transparency Report: Sustained Leadership in Crypto Markets with Multiple Metrics Hitting New Highs</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-q1-2025-transparency-report-leadership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Leading global digital asset platform Gate has released its Q1 2025 Transparency Report, showcasing comprehensive breakthroughs across multiple business segments. Core metrics reached historic highs, security infrastructure underwent full-scale upgrades, product offerings expanded significantly, and global strategies accelerated, all reflecting its robust growth momentum and a solidified market foundation. Trading Business Surge: Futures Trading Volume &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-q1-2025-transparency-report-leadership/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-q1-2025-transparency-report-leadership/">Gate Q1 2025 Transparency Report: Sustained Leadership in Crypto Markets with Multiple Metrics Hitting New Highs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Leading global digital asset platform <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44362/?ch=GM_Q1bein_20250410&amp;utm_campaign=TR_8iTMT570&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate</a> has released its Q1 2025 Transparency Report, showcasing comprehensive breakthroughs across multiple business segments. Core metrics reached historic highs, security infrastructure underwent full-scale upgrades, product offerings expanded significantly, and global strategies accelerated, all reflecting its robust growth momentum and a solidified market foundation.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trading-business-surge-futures-trading-volume-up-31-qoq"><strong>Trading Business Surge: Futures Trading Volume Up 31% QoQ</strong></h2>



<p>In Q1 2025, <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44362/?ch=GM_Q1bein_20250410&amp;utm_campaign=TR_8iTMT570&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate</a> maintained its industry leadership with remarkable user growth and trading volume breakthroughs. The platform’s expanding user base underscored its strong market appeal and sustained growth momentum.</p>



<p>Futures Trading saw explosive growth, with the number of traders and overall trading volume surging. Futures trading volume increased by approximately 31% quarter-over-quarter (QoQ).</p>



<p>In Spot Trading, the platform listed over 200 new tokens, reinforcing Gate’s leading edge in asset selection and listing efficiency, providing users with a broader and higher-quality range of investment options.</p>



<p>Gate newly launched the “Refer to Earn” program which integrated social media and interactive campaigns to drive user acquisition and trading activity, fostering sustainable community growth.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-strong-tokenomics-gt-price-hits-historic-high-of-25-96"><strong>Strong Tokenomics: GT Price Hits Historic High of $25.96</strong></h2>



<p>This quarter, Gate’s native token GT delivered stellar performance in Q1 2025, reaching an all-time high of $25.96 on January 25, a 70% increase year-to-date. As the native utility and gas token of GateChain, GT underpins the blockchain’s fundamental transaction infrastructure. GT holders also enjoy exclusive benefits such as LaunchPool airdrops, mining rewards, and staking incentives.</p>



<p>Since GateChain’s 2019 launch, GT has maintained a deflationary burn mechanism, reducing total supply by around 60% from its initial 300 million. This underscores Gate&#8217;s long-term commitment to deflationary tokenomics and reinforces GT&#8217;s value proposition for long-term holders. So far, a total of 177,089,412.23 GT has been burned, with a total burn value of approximately $408,270,578.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-security-first-total-reserves-exceed-10-328-billion"><strong>Security First: Total Reserves Exceed $10.328 Billion</strong></h2>



<p>Gate remains steadfast in safeguarding user assets and information security, further enhancing reserve transparency and platform security. As of January 17, 2025, Gate.io’s total reserves reached $10.328 billion, ranking Top 4 globally among crypto platforms. The reserve ratio stood at 128.58%, exceeding the 100% industry benchmark. Excess reserves totaled $2.296 billion, providing robust protection for user funds.</p>



<p>Gate attached great importance to advancing its global compliance framework, including the acquisition of Coin Master, a licensed exchange in Japan, through one of its entities, further expanding its localized business in the Japanese market.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-launchpool-upgrade-140-projects-launched-with-14m-rewards"><strong>Launchpool Upgrade: 140+ Projects Launched with $14M+ Rewards</strong></h2>



<p>In Q1 2025, Gate Launchpool (formerly Startup Mining) became a premier platform for new token launches. It hosted over 140 projects, including more than 90 free airdrops with a total value exceeding $5.2 million. And the platform launched over 70 mining projects distributing more than $9.2 million in rewards.</p>



<p>The platform introduced a project search function and intelligent strategy filter, enabling users to match optimal mining plans within three minutes. The HODLer Airdrop program lowered its entry threshold to 1 GT, delivering an average annualized return of 43.94%. Demonstrating its agility in responding to market trends, on the listing day of the trending token TRUMP, mining was activated immediately, and stake volume surpassed $25 million within 24 hours, attracting significant user participation and fostering a win-win environment between the platform and project.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gate-pilot-listed-over-1-000-tokens-capturing-multiple-high-yield-memes"><strong>Gate Pilot Listed Over 1,000 Tokens, Capturing Multiple High-Yield Memes</strong></h2>



<p>Leveraging its first-mover advantage and continuous innovation in the Meme sector, Gate Pilot has further solidified its leading position in the field. This quarter, Gate Pilot successfully integrated more than 10 major public blockchains, including Ethereum, Solana, and Base. Nearly 400 tokens were listed this quarter, bringing the total number of listed tokens to over 1,000. Gate Pilot maintains a leading position in the industry and offers users a richer and more diverse range of investment options.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, innovative tools such as “Logo Mode” and Meme Gem Index were launched, significantly enhancing users’ ability to identify tokens and market trends while lowering the barriers to Meme trading.</p>



<p>With its fast listing mechanism, Gate Pilot helped users capture multiple high-yield projects ahead of the market, including quality Meme tokens like Kekius (55x), Trump (45x), YZY (46x), and Mubarak (28x). In addition, the platform partnered with projects such as MemeCity and MemeCore, actively participating in offline industry events to strengthen its leading position in the Meme sector.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-strong-institutional-business-performance-and-continuous-infrastructure-upgrades"><strong>Strong Institutional Business Performance and Continuous Infrastructure Upgrades</strong></h2>



<p>Gate’s institutional business achieved significant breakthroughs in both trading volume and ecosystem development. Institutional clients’ futures and brokerage business trading volumes both saw marked growth. By optimizing trading infrastructure and market depth, latency was reduced by more than 2-fold, significantly improving users’ trading efficiency. Furthermore, futures liquidity improved, and the number of spot and futures market makers increased.</p>



<p>Additionally, Gate introduced the new Fireblocks Off-Exchange solution, offering institutional clients more flexible fund management options. Through joint marketing campaigns with over 20 partners, Gate further expanded its professional client base and strengthened the building of its premium user community, further consolidating Gate’s leading position in the global cryptocurrency field.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-significant-growth-in-quantitative-investment-copy-trading-volume-soared-780"><strong>Significant Growth in Quantitative Investment, Copy Trading Volume Soared 780%</strong></h2>



<p>This quarter, Gate achieved remarkable growth in copy trading, bot strategies, and ETF products. In terms of copy trading, the launch of the Prometheus automatic risk control system created a safer trading environment for users; spot copy trading volume surged by 780%, and the highest yield from a leading user reached 890x, offering users opportunities for excess returns.</p>



<p>Robot products, through continuous optimization of the Ultra AI strategy and intelligent algorithms, have generated over $500 million in cumulative trading revenue for users. The newly launched BotsLive streaming column and weekly strategy recommendations significantly boosted user engagement; the number of new strategies created increased by 404% quarter-on-quarter, and the number of users creating new strategies grew by 193%.</p>



<p>The ETF business also performed strongly, with the platform supporting over 200 ETF leveraged tokens, maintaining a leading position in the industry. By the end of the quarter, ETF trading volume had increased by 40% quarter-on-quarter, and the number of participating users had grown by 197%.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-partnering-with-top-players-to-build-global-blockchain-influence"><strong>Partnering with Top Players to Build Global Blockchain Influence</strong></h2>



<p>In the first quarter of 2025, Gate made simultaneous advances in global brand expansion and blockchain investment. Gate.io announced its official sponsorship of the Oracle Red Bull Racing team in F1, initiating a multi-year strategic partnership. This collaboration is not only a powerful alliance between two industry leaders but also marks the expansion of blockchain technology from the race track to the global stage, promoting Web3 and digital finance concepts to a broader audience through a world-class sports platform.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Gate Ventures joined the newly established Morph Venture Capital Collective alliance, further expanding its blockchain investment landscape. In addition, Gate Ventures invested $20 million in the BNB Incubation Alliance (BIA), jointly initiated by BNB Chain and Binance Labs, demonstrating its firm commitment to advancing the Web3 ecosystem and nurturing the next generation of blockchain innovation projects. By empowering projects with capital, resources, and networks, Gate is taking concrete actions to help bring blockchain technology into the mainstream.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: This content does not constitute an offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making investment decisions.<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit certain services in specific jurisdictions. For more details, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-q1-2025-transparency-report-leadership/">Gate Q1 2025 Transparency Report: Sustained Leadership in Crypto Markets with Multiple Metrics Hitting New Highs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-83.png" medium="image" width="1454" height="812" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-83.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uplink App Onboards 500K Routers Globally in Record Time — Empowering Anyone to Build the Future of the Internet</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/uplink-app-500k-routers-global/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Wi-Fi networks are no longer just about individual connections—they&#8217;re becoming part of a larger, community-powered infrastructure. As DePIN networks take the lead in solving real-world access challenges, global internet coverage is becoming more inclusive, resilient, and rewarding for those who contribute. Uplink, a decentralized connectivity ecosystem, is rapidly expanding its global footprint, driven by the &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/uplink-app-500k-routers-global/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/uplink-app-500k-routers-global/">Uplink App Onboards 500K Routers Globally in Record Time — Empowering Anyone to Build the Future of the Internet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>Wi-Fi networks are no longer just about individual connections—they&#8217;re becoming part of a larger, community-powered infrastructure. As DePIN networks take the lead in solving real-world access challenges, global internet coverage is becoming more inclusive, resilient, and rewarding for those who contribute.</em></p>



<p><a href="https://www.uplink.xyz/?utm_source=avax&amp;utm_medium=blog&amp;utm_campaign=partnership-announcement1124" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Uplink,</a> a decentralized connectivity ecosystem, is rapidly expanding its global footprint,<a href="https://www.uplink.xyz/blog/product-launch-the-uplink-app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> driven by the launch</a> of the next-generation Uplink App. Since the mobile application&#8217;s release on March 24, 2025, users registered more than 500,000 routers worldwide. In total, the Uplink network now boasts over<a href="https://explorer.uplink.xyz/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 650,000 pre-registered and registered routers</a>—laying the groundwork for a decentralized, blockchain-based, and community-driven internet infrastructure.</p>



<p>The Uplink App allows users to register routers, map network reliability, and earn Uplink Points through a gamified rewards system. Unlike traditional bandwidth-sharing platforms, Uplink focuses on crowdsourced network expansion, offering incentives for router verification, referrals, and participation in high-impact &#8220;Surge&#8221; events.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-building-a-decentralized-internet-one-router-at-a-time">Building a Decentralized Internet: One Router at a Time</h2>



<p>The Uplink App is designed to be intuitive, fast, and accessible to anyone with an internet connection. Once users download the app from the App Store or Google Play, they can register their routers by confirming location details, selecting venue types, and verifying network details. From that moment on, registered routers begin earning daily Uplink Points, which will integrate on-chain with the platform&#8217;s upcoming testnet and $ULX token ecosystem.</p>



<p>The key features of the Uplink App include:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Register Wi-Fi Routers:</strong> Seamlessly connect existing routers to the Uplink network and earn rewards.</li>



<li><strong>Verify Network Coverage:</strong> Help map and validate global internet coverage and reliability.</li>



<li><strong>Join Surge Events:</strong> Earn up to 10x points by registering routers in high-priority regions.</li>



<li><strong>Refer New Users:</strong> Invite others to the network and unlock up to one million bonus points through multi-tiered commissions.</li>



<li><strong>Track Rankings and Earnings:</strong> Monitor your progress, compare rankings, and view detailed points analytics through the app and Portal.</li>
</ul>



<p>“Uplink isn&#8217;t just about staying connected—it&#8217;s about empowering users to actively shape the future of internet access,&#8221; said <strong>Carlos Lei, CEO of Uplink</strong>. &#8220;In just three weeks since launching the Uplink App, our community has registered over 500,000 routers worldwide. This is an incredible show of momentum that highlights the power of collective action. And yet, this is only the beginning. The app is just one piece of a much larger vision: a decentralized connectivity ecosystem that puts ownership and opportunity into the hands of users.”</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-rise-of-depin">The Rise of DePIN</h2>



<p>Uplink is part of a growing sector of DePIN applications that are transforming how infrastructure is built, managed, and monetized. DePIN combines blockchain technology with physical infrastructure deployment, allowing decentralized communities to coordinate and fund real-world utilities—whether that&#8217;s internet access, energy grids, or edge computing networks.</p>



<p>Telecommunications, in particular, is emerging as one of DePIN&#8217;s most high-impact verticals. According to Messari, DePIN has the potential to grow 100 to 1,000 times beyond its current market value, reaching a projected market cap of<a href="https://www.coindesk.com/business/2024/04/11/depin-platform-uplink-raises-10m-led-by-framework-ventures" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> $3.5 trillion by 2028</a>. As demand for AI agents, spatial computing, and autonomous technologies continues to rise, the need for dynamic, decentralized internet access has never been greater.</p>



<p>Uplink is uniquely positioned to address this demand by bridging physical infrastructure with blockchain incentives. While traditional telecom providers remain essential to global connectivity, Uplink offers a complementary, community-powered model—scalable, cost-effective, and designed to support network expansion through decentralized participation.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-network-built-for-everyone-to-connect">A Network Built for Everyone to Connect</h2>



<p>Uplink&#8217;s DePIN network is already showing signs of massive grassroots adoption. In addition to hundreds of thousands of registered routers, the platform is expanding rapidly as users continue to register new routers, participate in Surge events, and refer others to join the network.</p>



<p>The Uplink App enables users to register their routers, view router deployments and surge zones around the world through the Explorer, while the Portal allows for in-depth analytics, earnings, router management, and referral analytics. Soon, users will also be able to connect to verified routers for free internet access—no passwords required—through a seamless experience powered by the Uplink network.</p>



<p>From Latin America to Southeast Asia, from rural towns to enterprise hubs and vibrant urban centers, Uplink is driving a bottom-up transformation in global connectivity. Enterprises, telecom providers, and communities are increasingly viewing DePIN as a viable solution to bridge the digital divide, offload traffic, and expand infrastructure.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-next-for-uplink">What&#8217;s Next for Uplink</h2>



<p>As the network continues to scale, Uplink is preparing to activate on-chain functionalities with the rollout of its testnet and mainnet. These milestones will introduce ULX token rewards, governance mechanisms, and deployment on Avalanche as an L1 platform—ensuring security, interoperability, and seamless rewards distribution.</p>



<p>With strategic partnerships in place—including Avalanche, Deutsche Telekom, E.ON, and the Wireless Broadband Alliance—Uplink is paving the way for decentralized telecommunications at scale.</p>



<p>The decentralized future of connectivity is no longer theoretical. It&#8217;s here, and Uplink is building it—router by router, region by region.To join the movement, download the Uplink App on<a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id6739225811" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> iOS</a> or<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.uplink.uplink" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Android</a>, register your router, and help bring decentralized internet access to the world.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/uplink-app-500k-routers-global/">Uplink App Onboards 500K Routers Globally in Record Time — Empowering Anyone to Build the Future of the Internet</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/uplink.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/uplink.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thriving in Turbulent Markets: HTX Margin&#8217;s Key to Success Amid Crypto Volatility</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/htx-margin-success-crypto-volatility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTX (Huobi) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In periods of heightened market volatility, strategic trading beyond simple holding becomes crucial. Margin trading offers a powerful mechanism to enhance capital efficiency and navigate market fluctuations with precision. HTX, a leading cryptocurrency exchange, has established itself as a pioneering platform for both professional traders and enthusiasts seeking to leverage margin trading with competitive costs &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-margin-success-crypto-volatility/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-margin-success-crypto-volatility/">Thriving in Turbulent Markets: HTX Margin&#8217;s Key to Success Amid Crypto Volatility</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In periods of heightened market volatility, strategic trading beyond simple holding becomes crucial. Margin trading offers a powerful mechanism to enhance capital efficiency and navigate market fluctuations with precision. <a href="https://www.htx.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HTX</a>, a leading cryptocurrency exchange, has established itself as a pioneering platform for both professional traders and enthusiasts seeking to leverage margin trading with competitive costs and an advanced risk management framework.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-htx-margin-where-innovation-meets-opportunity"><strong>HTX Margin: Where Innovation Meets Opportunity</strong></h2>



<p>During the first quarter of 2025, HTX’s margin trading operations demonstrated substantial growth. The platform recorded a 60% year-over-year increase in trading volume and a 16% increase compared to the previous quarter. Notably, the number of margin loan users surged by an impressive 565% year-over-year and 79% quarter-over-quarter, indicating a robust appetite for margin trading among both new and experienced crypto traders. HTX&#8217;s performance underscores its effectiveness in navigating volatile market conditions.</p>



<p>HTX&#8217;s robust margin trading growth stems from key competitive advantages, notably its lower loan interest rates and enhanced flexibility compared to other platforms. For example, its USDT margin loan interest rate stood at 3.99% on April 3, below the market average of 4.38%.</p>



<p>Crucially, HTX maintained relatively low and stable rates even during periods of significant market volatility, a contrast to competitors whose rates often experienced sharp increases.. This stability not only reduces costs for users but also provides crucial support for maintaining long-term positions.</p>



<p>Whether you’re quick-scoping for short-term gains or planning your next big move on the charts, HTX’s margin trading tools deliver both flexibility and performance, catering to both short-term trading strategies and long-term investment plans. The platform’s sophisticated risk management system and innovative features are designed to maximize potential gains while effectively mitigating risks</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-technological-advancements-enhance-user-experience-on-htx"><strong>Technological Advancements Enhance User Experience on HTX</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.htx.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HTX</a> didn’t just stop at offering solid margin trading but was on a mission to revolutionize the user experience throughout 2024. Key upgrades include:</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Dynamic Interest Rates (Jan 2024): </strong>Borrowing costs that adjust on the fly, based on real-time demand and the usage of collateral.</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Smart Risk Management (Feb 2024): </strong>A brand-new margin feature and a cutting-edge risk engine that uses smart algorithms to keep volatile markets in check.</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Liquidation in Batches (Mar 2024): </strong>An optimized liquidation process where liquidation is automatically paused when your account&#8217;s risk ratio reaches 150%, minimizing losses during extreme market conditions.</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Insurance Fund (May 2024): </strong>A safety net that automatically covers losses for positions under 20 USDT, making it safer even for smaller players.</p>



<p>These developments are all about cutting trading costs, enhancing security, and creating a more user-centric trading environment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>HTX also boasts the latest upgrade for margin trading &#8211; the merging of the auto borrowing and repayment processes into a one-click &#8220;Auto&#8221; feature. This demonstrates HTX&#8217;s keen understanding of user needs and aims to simplify the trading process.</p>



<p>The revamped trading interface now offers users a clear choice between Manual and Auto modes, reducing complexity and allowing traders to concentrate on their strategies.</p>



<p>This upgrade is proven to the exchange&#8217;s ongoing commitment to improving its margin trading services, focusing on smarter and more convenient trading tools through improvements in both design and functionality.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-looking-ahead-htx-s-next-wave-of-margin-trading-innovation"><strong>Looking Ahead: HTX&#8217;s Next Wave of Margin Trading Innovation</strong></h2>



<p>HTX Margin’s evolution from a basic lending service to a comprehensive margin trading powerhouse—complete with high leverage, dynamic rates, phased liquidation, and an insurance fund—has taken just under two years.</p>



<p>HTX is committed to continuous innovation in this area. In the second quarter of 2025, a comprehensive upgrade to HTX’s margin trading platform is anticipated. This upgrade will introduce the flexibility to seamlessly switch between isolated and cross margin modes, along with advanced tools for intelligent fund allocation and automated risk management.</p>



<p>Plus, a major overhaul of HTX&#8217;s margin trading interface is on the horizon, featuring a new real-time profitability dashboard slated for launch by late Q2 or early Q3. This feature promises to provide a better trading experience and data display, helping you fine-tune strategies and manage your trades like a true crypto veteran.</p>



<p>In a market where volatility is the new normal, HTX&#8217;s margin trading service provides more than just a tool—it offers a strategic advantage. By combining cutting-edge technology with a user-focused approach, HTX is empowering cryptocurrency enthusiasts to not only navigate market uncertainty but to capitalize on opportunities within it.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-margin-success-crypto-volatility/">Thriving in Turbulent Markets: HTX Margin&#8217;s Key to Success Amid Crypto Volatility</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-17.19.01.png" medium="image" width="890" height="500" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-17.19.01.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Football for Future: Gate.io Officially Launches Football Charity Program in Vietnam in Partnership with Inter</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-football-charity-vietnam-inter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 11:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685136</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gate.io, a leading global cryptocurrency exchange, successfully hosted the inaugural event of the Football For Future: Gate.io x Inter Vietnam Football Charity Program in collaboration with FC Internazionale Milano on April 9, 2025. The initiative aims to enhance sports facilities in underprivileged schools across Vietnam, fostering a passion for football and promoting a healthy lifestyle &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-football-charity-vietnam-inter/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-football-charity-vietnam-inter/">Football for Future: Gate.io Officially Launches Football Charity Program in Vietnam in Partnership with Inter</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Gate.io, a leading global cryptocurrency exchange, successfully hosted the inaugural event of the Football For Future: <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44349/?ch=GM_footballbein_20250408&amp;utm_campaign=TR_PgHNuOlR&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> x Inter Vietnam Football Charity Program in collaboration with FC Internazionale Milano on April 9, 2025. The initiative aims to enhance sports facilities in underprivileged schools across Vietnam, fostering a passion for football and promoting a healthy lifestyle among students.<kbd><img decoding="async" width="602" height="336" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcE2YmygiTsPC460TEwjxwdxvsS-Z529IP349gRm5H0Xe0dwvjPAZza9yROQs3zE1HQyOZTlfqcFYALXX-wLwfvs9xsZ9eb9WL6EYYG-u2r6LZWDpEVJmUWwFCqbOGNVLK4lMtWjg?key=FcePla3AKLkDsuG8NY40ThfV"></kbd></p>



<p>After careful evaluation, <a href="https://www.gate.io/announcements/article/44349/?ch=GM_footballbein_20250408&amp;utm_campaign=TR_PgHNuOlR&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> identified Cam Xa Primary School in Hung Yen Province as the first beneficiary of the program. Gate.io led the construction and renovation, transforming an underdeveloped area into an 880m² modern football field equipped with 5cm diamond fiber artificial grass, a lighting system with 250W LED lights, fencing, drainage infrastructure, and other supporting facilities. By the end of March, the project was completed in just over 20 days, ensuring students&#8217; quick access to a safe and professional sports environment.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeAVyr10_APzSMyT-oTfOD83JU2T7l1eBwtBPrOfikE1nu0YiFLc65doA9YDttH-8gWuAjbU_oDJ3p8fz_0U6SeqqAyrL3bZ2Acs7WCN_x0w3AwEYNLm1NZEol0gB1xQ88Jp3rB?key=FcePla3AKLkDsuG8NY40ThfV" alt=""/></figure>



<p>To commemorate the occasion, Gate.io hosted an official inauguration ceremony at the school on the morning of April 9, bringing together students, teachers, and local representatives. The event featured a donation ceremony, students&#8217; cultural performances and a friendly football match for students. Gate.io presented awards to the best players on the field. To their surprise, Inter Women’s Football Team sent out a special video message, encouraging young Vietnamese students to pursue their football dreams.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXczMLyuOavbsZnEtI90OBqZOHlMMfwYVKDryj37c8TTJHEVPbIz_8O7I0pcWNiTbGghzOTb7kQJjInU-3doYt2FTa3TEnx7wqr_s8Pq-B42QpNRE8bmLRLiGrL50CMX5h9mG7n5JQ?key=FcePla3AKLkDsuG8NY40ThfV" alt=""/></figure>



<p>During the event, Kevin Lee, Chief Business Officer of Gate.io, gave a speech and reaffirmed the company’s dedication to social responsibility and fostering young talent through community-driven initiatives. &#8220;We believe that the &#8216;Football for Future&#8217; initiative, with the success of its first project, will not only contribute to the development of football culture in Vietnam but also reaffirm Gate.io’s commitment to social responsibility, supporting the younger generation in unlocking their full potential.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcEO_JuWnTkPrUvX8lY4lCIVaqMlaJbU59zY9P8oog44N3duZ1X7ZeqcxrTgM8l4FnYUQVTXnMedKFVvcM5uZaQJvLYmR_4ED7vbsrGZfNDjoSAFXDU_qfhdRUTMAO1PJo790KKaA?key=FcePla3AKLkDsuG8NY40ThfV" alt=""/></figure>



<p>As an official sleeve sponsor of Inter, Gate.io has already established a strong presence in the global football community. The partnership, launched in the 2024-2025 season, reflects a shared commitment to innovation, community engagement, and a winning spirit. Through this collaboration, Gate.io is not only supporting the development of youth football in Vietnam but also strengthening the connection between Web3 technology and sports. With &#8220;Football for Future&#8221;, Gate.io is taking a meaningful step in giving back to the community, demonstrating how blockchain innovation and global partnerships can create lasting social impact.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXd3uUUcQbwBUye18qasN_TLoglKNjKAHB60RUHjfyQLHP_6xQxY3pv2pwCPF1ys0D2gMCrGzi-Yy1R1JZXIIlrvwUUlbJqfASCLhMWyiT5cwBt8oUeshsoRF-xzBZf-CcunZREq?key=FcePla3AKLkDsuG8NY40ThfV" alt=""/></figure>



<p>This project is part of Gate.io’s broader commitment to empowering communities through sports and education. Following the success of the first initiative, Gate.io plans to extend the &#8220;Football for Future&#8221; program to other schools, providing more students with access to quality sports facilities and training resources, and inspiring the next generation to pursue their dreams both on and off the field.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong></p>



<p>The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-football-charity-vietnam-inter/">Football for Future: Gate.io Officially Launches Football Charity Program in Vietnam in Partnership with Inter</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-77.png" medium="image" width="1574" height="878" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-77.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>HTX DAO Launches $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism, Ushering in a New Era of Decentralized Governance</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/htx-dao-launches-htx-voting-mechanism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 09:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HTX (Huobi) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>HTX DAO recently unveiled its official $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism. This significant development marks a pivotal shift in HTX DAO&#8217;s governance system, transitioning from &#8220;proposal discussion&#8221; to &#8220;on-chain decision-making&#8221;. This launch propels HTX DAO closer to its vision of becoming the &#8220;People’s Exchange&#8221;, setting a new benchmark for financial democratization within the Web3 landscape.  Participate &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-dao-launches-htx-voting-mechanism/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-dao-launches-htx-voting-mechanism/">HTX DAO Launches $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism, Ushering in a New Era of Decentralized Governance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>HTX DAO recently unveiled its official $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism. This significant development marks a pivotal shift in <a href="https://htxdao-1.gitbook.io/htxdao-governance" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HTX DAO&#8217;s governance system</a>, transitioning from &#8220;proposal discussion&#8221; to &#8220;on-chain decision-making&#8221;. This launch propels HTX DAO closer to its vision of becoming the &#8220;People’s Exchange&#8221;, setting a new benchmark for financial democratization within the Web3 landscape. </p>



<p>Participate in Voting: <a href="https://www.htxdao.com/en-us/proposals" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">website</a></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-governance-evolution-from-community-input-to-on-chain-action-nbsp"><strong>Governance Evolution: From Community Input to On-Chain Action</strong>&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Since the inception of the HTX DAO Forum, the community has actively engaged in robust discussions on key areas including asset listings, fee optimization, and ecosystem incentives. The introduction of the $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism now completes the &#8220;proposal-voting-execution&#8221; governance cycle. This crucial step reflects HTX DAO&#8217;s systematic restructuring into a clearly defined “three-layer governance framework”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><strong>Foundation Layer: </strong>The Foundation Layer establishes the governance value of the $HTX token based on a<strong> </strong>&nbsp;“one token, one vote” principle. Serving as both a core trading medium and a vital governance token, $HTX leverages on-chain holding verification on the TRON network, ensuring governance rights are securely vested in actual token holders.</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Execution Layer:</strong> A standardized HIP (HTX Improvement Proposal) process has been established as the formal framework for all governance proposals. Distinct from the initial draft governance process, all proposals submitted via HIP are immutably recorded within the governance system, creating a permanent record of DAO decisions that will serve as a long-term governance reference.</p>



<p>●&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; <strong>Supervisory Layer:</strong> Establishes a committee comprising early initiators, core contributors, and community representatives to ensure balanced ecosystem governance. This body assumes essential decentralized development responsibilities, including governance system construction, financial oversight, and governance support.</p>



<p>In contrast to traditional exchanges with centralized governance, $HTX empowers its holders to directly influence major platform decisions via on-chain voting. This equitable system, where voting power is directly proportional to individual holding amounts, ensures fair governance rights and the equitable distribution of benefits, fostering a truly decentralized governance ecosystem driven by $HTX holders.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-htx-empowering-holders-through-governance-and-rewards"><strong>$HTX: Empowering Holders Through Governance and Rewards</strong></h2>



<p>HTX DAO&#8217;s innovative governance model presents two compelling core advantages for the community: the direct influence granted by holdings and the tangible economic incentive of votes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Holding $HTX provides a direct voice and the means to actively participate in the ecosystem’s governance.. By casting votes, holders directly shape the platform&#8217;s future direction, a revolutionary departure from the traditional CEX model where users often passively adhere to established directives. Future Voting initiatives are anticipated to encompass critical decisions such as asset listings and delistings, participation in “Trade to Earn” events, management of risk reserve funds, and the prioritization of new product feature development.</p>



<p>The HTX DAO governance roadmap reveals future integration of rewards like fee rebates and governance incentives, making participation a profitable activity that encourages long-term $HTX holding. This forward-thinking system design creates a powerful positive feedback loop: “greater involvement → improved decisions → enhanced ecosystem value → direct feedback of rewards”.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-pioneering-a-blended-cefi-defi-governance-paradigm"><strong>Pioneering a Blended CeFi/DeFi Governance Paradigm</strong></h2>



<p>The essence of HTX DAO’s innovation lies within a pioneering <strong>“financial free hub”</strong> governance experiment: it strategically blends the operational efficiency and robust regulatory structure of a centralized exchange (CEX) with the open governance and strong community consensus inherent in a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO). Inspired by successful DAO models like Curve and Velodrome, the launch of HTX DAO&#8217;s voting function is another key step in bridging CEX and DAO principles, with the potential to pioneer a new paradigm of diverse collaboration at the governance layer.</p>



<p>As user sovereignty gains prominence, the DAO mechanism offers a measurable route to financial democratization by linking fee revenue, ecosystem benefits, and other elements to governance participation. Within this &#8220;financial free hub&#8221; experiment, HTX DAO is redefining the relationship between trading platforms and users – evolving from a traditional service provider to a collaborative community that shares in its value.</p>



<p>As every $HTX holder transforms into a crucial decision-making node within the ecosystem, and each individual vote actively contributes to the platform’s continuous evolution, the emergence of a fully autonomous financial ecosystem within the Web3 era can be collectively anticipated and witnessed. HTX DAO’s meticulously designed framework serves as the guide toward a truly decentralized “financial free hub.”</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-htx-dao"><strong>About HTX DAO</strong></h2>



<p>As a multi-chain deployed decentralized autonomous organization (DAO), HTX DAO demonstrates an innovative governance approach. It pioneers a blended CeFi/DeFi paradigm, including listing and community governance, through its focus on building an exchange DAO and a free financial hub ecosystem. Unlike traditional corporate structures, it adopts a decentralized governance structure composed of a diversified group, jointly committed to the success of this organization. This unique ecosystem advocates openness and encourages all DAO participants to propose ideas that can promote the development of HTX DAO.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/htx-dao-launches-htx-voting-mechanism/">HTX DAO Launches $HTX Holding-Based Voting Mechanism, Ushering in a New Era of Decentralized Governance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-12.16.45.png" medium="image" width="986" height="548" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Снимок-экрана-2025-04-09-в-12.16.45.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>KernelDAO Token Launch Preparation: $KERNEL Will Be Live Soon on Binance</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/kernel-live-soon-binance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684780</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>KernelDAO is a leading restaking ecosystem with over $2 billion in Total Value Locked (TVL), operating across 10+ chains. The ecosystem includes Kelp, a top liquid restaking protocol on Ethereum; Kernel, BNB Chain restaking infrastructure integrated with 20+ projects; and Gain, a rewards program offering access to top airdrops and high-yield opportunities. Currently, KernelDAO is &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/kernel-live-soon-binance/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/kernel-live-soon-binance/">KernelDAO Token Launch Preparation: $KERNEL Will Be Live Soon on Binance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://kerneldao.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">KernelDAO</a> is a leading restaking ecosystem with over $2 billion in Total Value Locked (TVL), operating across 10+ chains. The ecosystem includes <strong>Kelp</strong>, a top liquid restaking protocol on Ethereum; <strong>Kernel</strong>, BNB Chain restaking infrastructure integrated with 20+ projects; and <strong>Gain</strong>, a rewards program offering access to top airdrops and high-yield opportunities.</p>



<p>Currently, KernelDAO is reaching a major milestone with the announcement of the Token Generation Event (TGE) of its native token, $KERNEL, and its listing on Binance on April 14th. Additionally, 4% of the total token supply is allocated for the <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/detail/fcb0aca70fe7458197d653f63117d8ff" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Megadrop.</a></p>



<h1 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-about-binance-megadrop">About Binance Megadrop</h1>



<p><a href="https://www.binance.com/en/megadrop" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Megadrop</a> is a new token launch platform where users can receive airdrops of new tokens before they are listed on Binance by temporarily locking BNB in Simple Earn Locked Products (the longer the subscription period, the higher the rewards). Additionally, Binance Megadrop allows users to earn airdrops of new tokens by completing Web3 Quests using Binance Wallet. Access to Binance Megadrop is available via the Binance mobile app.</p>



<p>$KERNEL is the fourth project introduced through Binance Megadrop and, like other tokens, will be listed with strong liquidity across multiple trading pairs. Following the listing on April 14, the project will benefit from extensive support within the Binance ecosystem. In addition to the 4% of the total $KERNEL supply allocated for the Binance HODLer Airdrop, another 4% will be allocated to Binance marketing campaigns, to be distributed six months after the spot listing.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-kernel">About $KERNEL:</h2>



<p><a href="https://blogs.kerneldao.com/blog/tokenomics-token-utility-the-foundation-of-kernel-s-ecosystem" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$KERNEL</a> is the governance and utility token that connects its suite of products—Kelp LRT, Kernel Infrastructure, and Gain. Additionally, the token offers various other utilities, such as the ability to restake $KERNEL and provide rewards to holders from partner protocols and middleware.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-key-details">Key Details</h3>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Token: </strong>$KERNEL</li>



<li><strong>Circulating Supply When Listed on Binance</strong>: 162,317,496 (16.23% of total token supply)</li>



<li><strong>Total and Max Token Supply</strong>: 1,000,000,000 KERNEL</li>



<li><strong>Binance HODLer Airdrop Allocation</strong>: 40,000,000 KERNEL (4.00% of total token supply)</li>



<li><strong>Binance Marketing Campaigns:</strong> 40,000,000 KERNEL (4.00% of total token supply)</li>
</ul>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tokenomics">Tokenomics</h3>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeeRpzSt2km5JWeqimhLn3Jk9c_frIyUKseifrjMgcklc5rARs_J2vhJG4kWBAW3iI_-vyuuVOPdMh6s7ybLWguvPm5qW1M4nl-dHVETS7mVhejVA9VM6FagDtpGaDihvVcPfOv?key=DRZP48IzOk4YDdKLl68T5srv" alt=""/></figure>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Community &amp; Ecosystem Partners:</strong> 60% $KERNEL</li>



<li><strong>Private Sale (for completed and upcoming strategic sales): </strong>20% $KERNEL</li>



<li><strong>Team &amp; Advisors: </strong>20% $KERNEL</li>
</ul>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/kernel-live-soon-binance/">KernelDAO Token Launch Preparation: $KERNEL Will Be Live Soon on Binance</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08-17.24.17.jpeg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08-17.24.17.jpeg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ultimate New Flex in Football Culture: PSG X Matchain Launch 70 Ultra-Limited VIP Silver Cards</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/psg-matchain-vip-silver-cards-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Paris Saint-Germain, in collaboration with blockchain platform Matchain, is set to release just 70 VIP Silver Cards. The ultra-limited membership is redefining what it means to be a modern fan. This is about unlocking legacy. Exclusivity. Ownership. It’s a new kind of relationship between Club and supporter. PSG Silver Card Loyalty Program The Silver Card &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/psg-matchain-vip-silver-cards-launch/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/psg-matchain-vip-silver-cards-launch/">The Ultimate New Flex in Football Culture: PSG X Matchain Launch 70 Ultra-Limited VIP Silver Cards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Paris Saint-Germain, in collaboration with blockchain platform Matchain, is set to release just 70 VIP Silver Cards. The ultra-limited membership is redefining what it means to be a modern fan. This is about unlocking legacy. Exclusivity. Ownership. It’s a new kind of relationship between Club and supporter.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-psg-silver-card-loyalty-program"><strong>PSG Silver Card Loyalty Program</strong></h2>



<p>The Silver Card grants access to an elite circle. With only 70 in existence, it serves as a long-term key to the most coveted and carefully curated experiences PSG has ever offered. This is more than a membership. It’s a signal. A statement. A stake in the future of football culture.</p>



<p>The journey begins with an inaugural drop: a sealed digital Mystery Box that includes exclusive PSG x Jordan Wings apparel and a Money Can’t Buy VIP experience. From pitchside moments to off-the-record access, this is where luxury, legacy, and fandom intersect, designed for those who don’t just support the club, but love it.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-joining-psg-s-inner-circle-nbsp"><strong>Joining PSG’s inner circle.&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>The Silver Card is for those who live and breathe PSG. Designed for a new generation of supporters, this ultra-limited access pass speaks to die-hard fans, cultural tastemakers, and Web3-native collectors. These people know that fandom today means more than just watching from the sidelines. It’s about owning a piece of the legacy and shaping what comes next.</p>



<p>Each Silver Card unlocks a mystery box with premium physical items, digital goods and VIP experiences including:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>A VIP &#8220;Money Can’t Buy&#8221; experience</li>



<li>A rare, PSG-certified digital collectible</li>



<li>Exclusive PSG x Jordan Wings apparel</li>



<li>Access to an exclusive global PSG community</li>



<li>Concierge support to handle everything from booking to experience day</li>
</ul>



<p>Every perk is authenticated and tradable via Matchain’s blockchain infrastructure and Rarible’s NFT marketplace, offering long-term value beyond the moment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-high-value-real-scarcity"><strong>High value. Real scarcity.</strong></h2>



<p>Only <strong>70 Silver Cards</strong> will ever be released. Priced at $10,000 each.</p>



<p>No restocks. No second chances. Once they’re gone, they’re gone.</p>



<p>From pitchside matchday moments to limited-edition PSG x Jordan Wings gear, this is a new era of fan engagement. Whether it’s meeting club legends, unlocking a mystery box of rare experiences, or owning digital collectibles with future value, the Silver Card is built for those who go deeper. It’s not about buying stuff. It’s about owning a moment most fans can only dream of.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-availability"><strong>Availability</strong></h2>



<p>The Silver Card drops soon. Pledge opens April 8: <a href="https://rarible.com/collection/match/0x7289f4e441beb71403f9195f47f6f84ac4e596fa/drops" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website</a></p>



<p>Pledging secures your spot on the waitlist. You’re not buying yet &#8211; just raising your hand for a shot at owning one.</p>



<p>Every pledge comes with a free, limited-edition NFT.</p>



<p>Only 70 Silver Cards will be released.</p>



<p>Once sold out, access closes, unless traded on the secondary market.</p>



<p>For the full experience, visit: <a href="https://en.psg.fr/fans/silvercard" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">website</a></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-paris-saint-germain"><strong>About Paris Saint-Germain </strong></h2>



<p>Founded in 1970, Paris Saint-Germain is the most successful club in France and a leading force on the European stage, combining sporting excellence, innovation and societal commitment to shape the future of sport. Under Qatar Sports Investments (QSI) ownership since 2011, PSG has grown into a multi-sport institution, excelling in men’s and women’s football, handball, judo and Esports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With a global fan base exceeding&nbsp;500 million and a combined following of over&nbsp;220 million across social media, it has become a cultural icon, sitting at the intersection of sport, fashion and entertainment, thanks notably to its partnership with Jordan. In 2024, the Club inaugurated the Paris Saint-Germain Campus, a €300 million state-of-the-art facility.</p>



<p>As The Club of the New Generation, Paris Saint-Germain combines athletic excellence, cultural influence and social impact to shape the future of sport and society.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-about-matchain"><strong>About Matchain</strong></h2>



<p><a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.google.com/url?q%3Dhttps://www.matchain.io%26amp;sa%3DD%26amp;source%3Deditors%26amp;ust%3D1729516201436285%26amp;usg%3DAOvVaw0_tAKEWA3HwNvo1LruQzwp&amp;sa=D&amp;source=docs&amp;ust=1729516201442549&amp;usg=AOvVaw1UsVy1fMMZaTILHza1tFlJ" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Matchain</a>&nbsp;is a blockchain platform that offers advanced AI-driven decentralized identity solutions. It ensures privacy, security, and control over personal data, allowing users to own and monetize their digital information within a secure ecosystem.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/psg-matchain-vip-silver-cards-launch/">The Ultimate New Flex in Football Culture: PSG X Matchain Launch 70 Ultra-Limited VIP Silver Cards</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-3-1.png" medium="image" width="2400" height="1350" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-3-1.png"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
