<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Feature Archives - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/feature/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/feature/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 07:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Feature Archives - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/feature/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>From Dogecoin to D.O.G.E: Is Elon Musk Playing a Billionaire’s Crypto Experiment?</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-doge-elon-musk-crypto-experiment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=686374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk's influence on Dogecoin blurs parody and promotion, raising questions on market manipulation and ethical responsibility.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-doge-elon-musk-crypto-experiment/">From Dogecoin to D.O.G.E: Is Elon Musk Playing a Billionaire’s Crypto Experiment?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Originally launched as a parody of crypto speculation, Dogecoin has since become the kind of speculative asset it was meant to mock — largely due to Elon Musk’s influence. His social media activity and public endorsements have played a central and ongoing role in shaping DOGE&#8217;s trajectory.</strong></p>



<p>BeInCrypto spoke with Erwin Voloder, Head of Policy of the European Blockchain Association, to discuss how Musk blurred the lines between parody and promotion, leading people to assign real-world value to a meme and generating ethical concerns along the way.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-genesis-of-dogecoin"><strong>The Genesis of Dogecoin</strong></h2>



<p>Toward the end of 2013, software engineers Billy Markus and Jackson Palmer joined forces to create <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/buy-dogecoin/">Dogecoin</a>, the first meme coin in crypto history. Its primary purpose was to serve as a lighthearted parody of the chaotic crypto hype. </p>



<p>Born from the &#8220;Doge&#8221; internet meme, which <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/dogecoin-vs-shiba-inu/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">prominently featured a Shiba Inu</a>, the meme coin was intended as a humorous jab at the often illogical nature of crypto speculation.</p>



<p>Despite its satirical origins, Dogecoin quickly gained a dedicated online following—so much so that even Tesla CEO Elon Musk became drawn to it. </p>



<p>Today, he’s considered a key figure in the community, and Dogecoin, contrary to its initial philosophy, has become a speculative asset.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Musk’s involvement transformed Dogecoin from a satirical internet token into a speculative asset class by bestowing it with perceived legitimacy and entertainment value. His tweets and appearances turned Dogecoin into a cultural product rather than a financial one—a kind of performance art with real economic consequences. The irony is that a coin created to mock irrational investing became the poster child of irrational investing,” Voloder told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In addition to symbolic endorsements, Musk has exerted concrete influence. A prime example is Tesla&#8217;s early 2022 <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-reserve-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decision to accept Dogecoin</a> for select merchandise, significantly strengthening its position and indicating its practical potential.</p>



<p>Musk also didn’t hesitate to use social media to convey his love for Dogecoin.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-did-musk-s-tweets-impact-dogecoin-s-market"><strong>How Did Musk&#8217;s Tweets Impact Dogecoin&#8217;s Market?</strong></h2>



<p><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Throughout the years, Elon Musk, a prolific Twitter user even before he bought the platform</span>, has shared numerous posts referencing Dogecoin. Each of these tweets has substantially impacted the meme coin’s visibility and price performance. </p>



<p>When <a href="https://beincrypto.com/doge-dogecoin-price-analysis-04-04-2019/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Musk referred to Dogecoin in an April 2019 tweet</a> as his favorite cryptocurrency, the market went berserk. In two days, the coin&#8217;s price went from $0.002 on April 1 to as high as $0.004.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Dogecoin might be my fav cryptocurrency. It’s pretty cool.</p>&mdash; Elon Musk (@elonmusk) <a href="https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/1113009339743100929?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 2, 2019</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Two years later, Musk&#8217;s X posts declaring &#8220;Dogecoin is the people&#8217;s crypto&#8221; triggered an overnight trading volume surge of over 50%.</p>



<p>Soon enough, retail investors started to follow Musk’s endorsements mindlessly. But it wasn’t all butterflies and roses. Musks’s unpredictable pronouncements also came with extreme volatility.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Musk blurred the line between parody and promotion, which led people to assign real-world value to a meme. Without him, it may have remained a niche internet joke but with him, it became a symbol of speculative absurdity,” Voloder said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>When Musk called Dogecoin ‘a hustle’ on Saturday Night Live in May 2021, the coin lost more than a third of its price in a few hours.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Dogecoin has no clear roadmap, no underlying yield or utility, and limited development activity, meaning its valuation is especially sentiment-driven. In such an environment, a single individual’s actions can drive or destroy market perception, particularly when that individual is one of the world&#8217;s most followed and wealthiest people,” he added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Then, in January 2025, President Trump appointed Musk as the head of a newly created agency tasked with cutting federal spending. </p>



<p>Musk called it the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/elon-musk-doge-to-investigate-sec/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Department of Government Efficiency, or D.O.G.E. for short</a>. The name was intentional, and the internet broke accordingly. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-d-o-g-e-and-the-price-plunge-what-s-the-correlation"><strong>D.O.G.E. and the Price Plunge: What&#8217;s the Correlation?</strong></h2>



<p>President Trump launched the D.O.G.E. department by executive order on his first day on the job. After D.O.G.E. launched its official government website, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/elon-musk-triggers-dogefather-token-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dogecoin’s price surged</a> by 13% in 15 minutes, breaking its previous short-term downtrend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yet, since the official establishment of the Department of Government Efficiency, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-price-tumbles-after-musk-statement/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DOGE&#8217;s price has been freefalling</a>. While valued at $0.36 on January 20, its price has since fallen to $0.15 today.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="2059" height="558" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95.png" alt="dogecoin price chart 2025" class="wp-image-686386" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95.png 2059w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-360x98.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-850x230.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-768x208.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-1536x416.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-2048x555.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-95-150x41.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2059px) 100vw, 2059px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Dogecoin Price Chart Since January 2025. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/dogecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Findings from a recent Finbold <a href="https://finbold.com/over-40-of-dogecoin-millionaires-wiped-out-since-elon-musk-began-d-o-g-e/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a> have also revealed that Musk might now be having the opposite effect on Dogecoin’s value and sentiment.</p>



<p>According to the data, the number of Dogecoin millionaire addresses has plunged by over 41% between January 21 and March 31. In just over two months, the cryptocurrency has decreased by 964 addresses.</p>



<p>Notably, the report indicated a massive proportional decline in the number of the wealthiest Dogecoin addresses. The count of addresses holding $1 million to $9.99 million decreased by 40.21% in Q1 2025. </p>



<p>Even more significantly, the number of addresses holding over $10 million plummeted by 47%, from 400 to 212.</p>



<p>In short, Dogecoin whales are dumping the token. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" width="992" height="1000" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM.png" alt="Over 40% of Dogecoin millionaires have been wiped out since Elon Musk began D.O.G.E." class="wp-image-686377" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM.png 992w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM-357x360.png 357w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM-843x850.png 843w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM-768x774.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM-96x96.png 96w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-at-6.29.13 PM-150x151.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 992px) 100vw, 992px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Over 40% of Dogecoin millionaires have been wiped out since Elon Musk began D.O.G.E. Source: <a href="https://finbold.com/over-40-of-dogecoin-millionaires-wiped-out-since-elon-musk-began-d-o-g-e/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Finbold</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Musk’s influence remains a key variable in Dogecoin’s valuation, and the timing of the drop in high-value addresses closely aligns with his D.O.G.E. announcement, suggesting a correlation. However, attributing the entire reversal to Musk overlooks broader macro factors like rising interest rates, tighter crypto regulation, and waning retail enthusiasm post-2021,” Voloder explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite the difficulty of assessing the precise impact of Elon Musk&#8217;s D.O.G.E. leadership on Dogecoin&#8217;s performance, his significant influence on the cryptocurrency has become evident.</p>



<p>The ethical considerations accompanying Musk’s influence have also become difficult to ignore.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-ethical-concerns-of-a-billionaire-s-influence"><strong>The Ethical Concerns of a Billionaire&#8217;s Influence</strong></h2>



<p>According to Voloder, the Dogecoin case illustrates the perils of parasocial investing, a behavior in which people mistakenly assign credibility to famous personalities based on their celebrity status or charisma.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It further shows the damaging effects of uncritical reliance on endorsements, potentially leading to substantial financial losses for retail investors.</p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/democrats-ethics-probe-trump-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ethics of a billionaire influencing a volatile market</a> like cryptocurrency also present significant complexities.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“On one hand, Musk has the right to express personal views and participate in public discourse, including around assets like Dogecoin. On the other, his outsized influence means that his commentary can trigger real financial harm or euphoria in retail investors who often lack access to sophisticated risk models. Ethically, when you wield that kind of influence, there’s a strong argument for assuming a higher standard of responsibility—especially in a market with minimal guardrails,” Voloder told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Given the unregulated nature of the cryptocurrency industry, it’s currently challenging to pinpoint the degree to which Musk&#8217;s actions can be held responsible.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-does-musk-s-influence-constitute-market-manipulation"><strong>Does Musk&#8217;s Influence Constitute Market Manipulation?</strong></h2>



<p>Although presented as personal opinions, Musk&#8217;s tweets demonstrably affect Dogecoin&#8217;s price, creating a legal gray area regarding potential market manipulation under US securities and commodities laws.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Under SEC rules, market manipulation involves intentional conduct designed to deceive or defraud investors by controlling or artificially affecting market prices. While Dogecoin is not officially deemed a security, and thus outside the SEC&#8217;s traditional remit, the CFTC could still scrutinize it under its anti-manipulation powers for commodities,” Voloder explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Dogecoin case isn’t the first time a high-profile figure has influenced markets in ways that were manipulative, though not explicitly illegal. </p>



<p>Voloder highlighted two instances at different points in the 20th century: when prominent banker JP Morgan steered markets during the panic of 1907 and investor George Soros broke the Bank of England in 1992. </p>



<p>Though their maneuvers were technically legal, they managed to sway market outcomes. However, this was the 20th century, and their impact was proportionally much smaller.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The difference today is that social media provides instantaneous reach to millions of investors, amplifying the potential impact. So even if Musk’s tweets are framed as personal musings, their predictable effect on price can be seen as a form of market signaling—intentional or not,” Voloder told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In fact, the SEC and legal experts are already debating Elon Musk&#8217;s potential influence on Dogecoin&#8217;s financial market activities.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-258-billion-lawsuit"><strong>A $258 Billion Lawsuit</strong></h2>



<p>Elon Musk currently faces a $258 billion class action lawsuit for running a Dogecoin pyramid scheme.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The lawsuit, filed in June 2022, claims that Musk intentionally promoted Dogecoin through his tweets, public appearances, and media interactions, creating hype and driving up demand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to the plaintiffs, this artificial inflation of Dogecoin&#8217;s price allowed Musk and his companies to profit while leaving other investors with substantial losses when the price inevitably declined.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Due to the SEC&#8217;s unclear legal classification of cryptocurrencies like Dogecoin, Voloder anticipates a difficult path for these claims in court. Nevertheless, the lawsuit indicates increased attention to market manipulation by influential figures.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Still, the lawsuit signals increased legal pressure to define where promotional enthusiasm ends and financial misconduct begins. If regulators or courts decide Musk knowingly manipulated the market or misled investors, he could face civil penalties or be forced into settlements. The SEC’s earlier scrutiny of Musk’s Tesla tweets, resulting in a consent decree, shows that regulators are willing to act when market-moving speech crosses certain lines,” Voloder explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Musk&#8217;s influence on Dogecoin continues unabated, and the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-stability-tested-long-term-holders/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">long-term effects on the Dogecoin community</a> remain a subject of debate.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-will-dogecoin-s-community-resilience-endure"><strong>Will Dogecoin&#8217;s Community Resilience Endure?</strong></h2>



<p>The rapid 40% decrease in Dogecoin whale addresses within two months has raised questions about the meme coin&#8217;s future strength and resilience.</p>



<p>However, DOGE&#8217;s fundamental strength still remains intact – it&#8217;s community. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“While the initial hype has faded, Dogecoin still retains a loyal base of enthusiasts, many of whom appreciate its meme-driven culture, low transaction fees, and iconic branding. But the big speculative crowd that initially drove its [all-time high] has largely left the field in absence of sustained bullish narratives or meaningful tech upgrades,” Voloder concluded.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the future, traders will be watching to see if Dogecoin&#8217;s &#8216;cult following&#8217; eventually dwindles or if a strong community will sustain the &#8216;OG meme coin&#8217;.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dogecoin-doge-elon-musk-crypto-experiment/">From Dogecoin to D.O.G.E: Is Elon Musk Playing a Billionaire’s Crypto Experiment?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/bic_Elon_Musk_twitter_dogecoin-covers_coins.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/bic_Elon_Musk_twitter_dogecoin-covers_coins.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will the SEC Approve Staking in Ethereum ETFs? Understanding the Hurdles</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-etf-staking-sec-approval-challenges/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:40:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>US exchanges have proposed Ethereum staking ETFs to the SEC, a move met with cautious optimism pending investor protection assurances.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-etf-staking-sec-approval-challenges/">Will the SEC Approve Staking in Ethereum ETFs? Understanding the Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Since early 2025, exchanges such as Cboe BZX and NYSE Arca have submitted proposals to the US SEC to incorporate staking services into existing spot ETFs. If approved, these funds could accelerate crypto adoption by giving traditional investors streamlined access to ETH.</strong></p>



<p>Brian Fabian Crain, CEO and Co-founder of Chorus One, told <em>BeInCrypto</em> he remains &#8220;cautiously optimistic&#8221; about the proposals gaining approval before the end of President Trump&#8217;s first term. Still, he emphasized that the SEC will likely focus on ensuring strict investor protections before moving forward.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-push-for-staked-ethereum-etfs-in-the-us"><strong>The Push for Staked Ethereum ETFs in the US</strong></h2>



<p>In mid-February, both Cboe BZX Exchange and NYSE Arca took steps towards Ethereum staking ETFs. Cboe BZX filed to amend the 21Shares ETF, while NYSE Arca followed two days later with a similar proposal for Grayscale&#8217;s ETF offerings.</p>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/experts-warn-of-restaking-vulnerabilities/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Staking is a fundamental component of Proof-of-Stake (PoS) blockchains</a>. Instead of relying on energy-intensive mining, such as in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/proof-of-work-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Proof-of-Work blockchains</a> like Bitcoin, PoS networks select participants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These participants act as validators and are in charge of verifying and adding new transactions, or blocks, to the blockchain based on the amount of cryptocurrency they have &#8220;staked&#8221; or locked up.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If approved, these <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/where-to-buy-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum ETFs</a> would allow traditional investors to gain exposure to the cryptocurrency while also earning passive income by contributing to the security of the Ethereum network through staking.</p>



<p>This move would also represent another significant step forward for institutional crypto adoption.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ approval‬‭ of‬‭ an‬‭ Ethereum‬‭ staking‬‭ ETF‬‭ would‬‭ mark‬‭ a‬‭ watershed‬‭ for‬‭ institutional‬‭ adoption.‬‭ Indeed,‬‭ a‬‭ staking-enabled‬‭ ETF‬‭ provides‬‭ a‬‭ regulated,‬‭ easy-to-access‬‭ exposure‬‭ to‬‭ ETH‬‭ that‬ includes‬‭ its‬‭ native‬‭ yield,‬‭ all‬‭ within‬‭ the‬‭ familiar‬‭ ETF‬‭ framework.‬‭ This‬‭ means‬‭ asset‬‭ managers‬‭ and‬ pensions‬‭ could‬‭ gain‬‭ passive‬‭ ETH‬‭ exposure‬‭ without‬‭ handling‬‭ private‬‭ keys‬‭ or‬‭ navigating‬‭ crypto‬‭ exchanges, significantly lowering operational barriers,” Crain told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>It would also enhance Ethereum’s market position relative to other crypto assets.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-can-staking-yield-revitalize-ethereum-s-market-position"><strong>Can Staking Yield Revitalize Ethereum&#8217;s Market Position?</strong></h2>



<p>Throughout much of 2024 and early 2025, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-ethereum-profitability-gap-increasing-for-two-years/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum&#8217;s price appreciation lagged significantly behind Bitcoin</a>. The ETH/BTC ratio hit a record low in early April 2025, indicating that Bitcoin was outperforming Ethereum.</p>



<p>Fluctuations in the broader crypto market <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-price-at-risk-of-decline/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">further complicated Ethereum’s market position</a>. Earlier this month, the network <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-price-faces-its-biggest-crisis/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reached its lowest price in two years</a>, eroding investor confidence.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1320" height="846" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM.png" alt="Ethereum's price performance over the past three months. Source: BeInCrypto." class="wp-image-685927" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM.png 1320w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM-360x231.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM-850x545.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM-768x492.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-5.21.17 PM-150x96.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1320px) 100vw, 1320px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ethereum&#8217;s price performance over the past three months. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/ethereum/">BeInCrypto</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>With increasing support from exchanges and asset managers for an Ethereum-staking ETF, a development of this scale can potentially reposition Ethereum.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“One key differentiator of Ethereum is its ability to generate yield through staking — something Bitcoin doesn&#8217;t offer. Enabling that feature within an ETF makes Ethereum-based products more attractive and competitive. Ethereum’s ~3% annual staking yield is a major draw for investors and a clear distinction from Bitcoin. It means that even if ETH’s price growth trails Bitcoin’s, staked ETH can still deliver higher total returns thanks to the yield. By packaging this yield into an ETF, Ethereum becomes a more compelling investment option for institutions focused on income,” Crain explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Allowing staking within an ETF structure would spur greater ETH demand and investor appetite and enhance Ethereum&#8217;s security by expanding the validator pool and decentralizing staking across a wider range of holders. </p>



<p>Increased total staked ETH would further strengthen the network against attacks.</p>



<p>With other jurisdictions already legally permitting staking services, the United States might see their early adoption as a reason to act quickly and maintain a competitive edge.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-hong-kong-s-staking-approval-impacts-the-us-sec"><strong>How Hong Kong&#8217;s Staking Approval Impacts the US SEC</strong></h2>



<p>This week, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/top-10-blockchain-leaders-nation-singapore/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hong Kong’s Securities and Futures Commission (SFC)</a> announced new guidance allowing licensed crypto exchanges and funds in the city to offer staking services. Platforms must meet strict conditions before providing these services.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‭The‬‭ SFC’s‬‭ framework‬‭ emphasizes‬‭ investor‬ protection‬‭ while‬‭ embracing‬‭ innovation.‬‭ For‬‭ example,‬‭ Hong‬‭ Kong‬‭ requires‬‭ that‬‭ platforms‬‭ retain‬‭ full control of client assets (no outsourcing) and disclose all staking risks transparently,” Crain explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Hong Kong set itself apart from other jurisdictions like <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top-crypto-trading-platforms-singapore/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Singapore</a>, which banned retail staking in 2023, and the previous SEC’s administration on Gary Gensler, which took a historically restrictive approach.</p>



<p>Crain believes this new development will primarily exert competitive pressure on the SEC to follow accordingly.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭As‬‭ a‬‭ major‬ international‬‭ financial‬‭ hub,‬‭ Hong‬‭ Kong’s‬‭ adoption‬‭ of‬‭ regulated‬‭ staking‬‭ sends‬‭ a‬‭ message:‬‭ it‬‭ is‬ possible‬‭ to‬‭ allow‬‭ staking‬‭ in‬‭ a‬‭ compliant‬‭ manner.‬‭ US‬‭ regulators‬‭ often‬‭ watch‬‭ regimes‬‭ like‬‭ Hong‬ Kong‬‭ as‬‭ bellwethers‬‭ for‬‭ emerging‬‭ best‬‭ practices.‬‭ The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ take‬‭ note‬‭ that‬‭ Hong‬‭ Kong‬‭ is‬‭ not‬ only‬‭ allowing‬‭ staking‬‭ but‬‭ even‬‭ paving‬‭ the‬‭ way‬‭ for‬‭ staking‬‭ services‬‭ in‬‭ ETFs‬‭ (the‬‭ SFC’s‬‭ rules‬ mention authorized virtual asset funds can offer staking under certain caps and conditions),” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>‭Incorporating staking into Hong Kong-listed crypto ETFs would put US funds and exchanges at a competitive disadvantage if the SEC maintains its prohibition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When reviewing the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-top-20-list-altcoins-q2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">21Shares and Grayscale applications</a>, the SEC may need to consider that global investors could turn to international markets to access these staking ETF products if the US doesn&#8217;t eventually allow them.</p>



<p>While the competitive aspect is a factor, the SEC will also need to address various complexities inherent in Ethereum staking, which may be obstacles to final approval.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-investment-contract-conundrum"><strong>The &#8220;Investment Contract&#8221; Conundrum</strong></h2>



<p>Among the most important factors the SEC will consider is whether staking programs constitute investment contracts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The previous administration&#8217;s SEC targeted <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-coinbase-kraken-sec-crypto-war/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">centralized exchanges like Kraken and Coinbase</a> for operating staking services considered unregistered profit schemes and violating US securities laws.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In centralized exchanges, users must effectively transfer custody of their cryptocurrency to a third-party entity that manages staking and the distribution of rewards. However, this model is distinct from the process inherent in Ethereum, a decentralized blockchain.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Unlike‬‭ exchange‬‭ staking‬‭ programs‬‭,‬‭ an‬‭ ETF‬‭ staking‬‭ its‬‭ own‬‭ assets‬‭ isn’t‬‭ ‘selling’‬‭ a‬‭ staking‬‭ service‬‭ to‬‭ others,‬‭ it’s‬‭ directly‬‭ participating‬‭ in‬‭ network‬‭ consensus.‬ This‬‭ nuance,‬‭ emphasized‬‭ in‬‭ recent‬‭ filings‬‭ and‬‭ comment‬‭ letters,‬‭ is‬‭ contributing‬‭ to‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ willingness‬‭ to‬‭ reconsider its stance.‬‭ Essentially,‬‭ the‬‭ argument‬‭ is‬‭ that‬‭ staking‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ core‬‭ technical‬‭ feature‬‭ of‬‭ Ethereum,‬‭ not‬‭ an‬‭ ancillary‬‭ investment‬‭ product,” Crain told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While an ETF staking its assets presents a different model, the SEC will look closely for security violations. Addressing this concern requires demonstrating that protocol rewards originate inherently from the decentralized network, not the sponsor&#8217;s business efforts.</p>



<p>This issue, though largely conceptual, is critical; SEC approval hinges on satisfying securities law requirements regarding staking.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, slashing risks are another issue of concern.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-slashing-risks-a-unique-challenge-for-ethereum-staking-etfs"><strong>Slashing Risks: A Unique Challenge for Ethereum Staking ETFs?</strong></h2>



<p>A key difference from traditional commodity funds is that a staking ETF must actively participate in network consensus, exposing it to the potential for slashing.</p>



<p>Slashing is a penalty where a portion of the staked ETH can be destroyed if a validator acts improperly or makes mistakes. For investors, the ETF&#8217;s principal could suffer partial losses due to operational errors, a risk not present in non-staking ETFs.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ assess‬‭ how‬‭ significant‬‭ this‬‭ risk‬‭ is‬‭ and‬‭ whether‬‭ it’s‬‭ been‬‭ mitigated.‬‭ Filings‬‭ note‬‭ that‬‭ the‬‭ Sponsor‬‭ will‬‭ not‬‭ cover‬‭ slashing‬‭ losses‬‭ on‬‭ behalf‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ trust,‬‭ meaning‬‭ investors‬‭ bear‬‭ that‬‭ risk.‬‭ This‬‭ forces‬‭ the‬‭ SEC‬‭ to‬‭ consider‬‭ if‬‭ average‬‭ investors‬‭ can‬‭ tolerate‬‭ the‬‭ possibility‬‭ of‬‭ losing‬‭ funds‬‭ not‬‭ due‬‭ to‬‭ market‬‭ movement‬‭ but‬‭ due‬‭ to‬‭ a‬‭ technical‬‭ protocol‬‭ penalty.‬‭ This‬‭ risk‬‭ must‬‭ be‬‭ transparently disclosed and managed in any approved product,” Crain explained.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Typically, custodians have insurance for <a href="https://beincrypto.com/tech-giants-enhance-cybersecurity-ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">asset loss due to theft or cyberattacks</a>. However, slashing is a protocol-enforced penalty, not traditional &#8220;theft,&#8221; and many custody insurance policies might not cover it. Therefore, the SEC will likely inquire about the safeguards should a slashing event occur.</p>



<p>This novel aspect of Ethereum staking creates certain ambiguities in accounting treatment.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ scrutinize‬‭ how‬‭ the‬‭ custodian‬‭ reports‬‭ on‬‭ staked‬‭ holdings.‬‭ The‬‭ ETF’s‬‭ [net asset value‭ accounting‬‭ needs‬‭ to‬‭ capture‬‭ both‬‭ the‬‭ base‬‭ ETH‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ accumulated‬‭ rewards.‬‭ Custodians‬‭ will likely‬‭ provide‬‭ reporting‬‭ on‬‭ how‬‭ much‬‭ ETH‬‭ is‬‭ staked‬‭ versus‬‭ liquid,‬‭ and‬‭ any‬‭ rewards‬‭ received.‬‭ The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ require‬‭ independent‬‭ audits‬‭ or‬‭ attestations‬‭ confirming‬‭ that‬‭ the‬‭ custodian‬‭ indeed‬‭ holds‬‭ the‬‭ ETH‬‭ it‬‭ claims‬‭ (both‬‭ original‬‭ and‬‭ any‬‭ newly‬‭ awarded‬‭ ETH)‬‭ and‬‭ that‬‭ controls‬‭ around‬‭ staking are effective,” Crain explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Liquidity risks associated with <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/ethereum-restaking-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum staking</a> are another factor to consider.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-further-sec-considerations"><strong>Further SEC Considerations</strong></h2>



<p>A key detail the SEC will examine is that staked ETH lacks instant liquidity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even after the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-on-chain-activity-cranks-shanghai-upgrade/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Shanghai upgrade enabled withdrawals in 2023</a>, the Ethereum protocol still incorporates delays and queues that prevent staked ETH from being instantly liquid upon initiating the unstaking process.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ examine‬‭ how‬‭ the‬‭ fund‬‭ handles‬‭ redemption‬‭ requests‬‭ if‬‭ a‬‭ large‬‭ portion‬‭ of‬‭ assets‬‭ are‬‭ locked‬‭ in‬‭ staking.‬‭ For‬‭ example,‬‭ exiting‬‭ a‬‭ validator‬‭ position‬‭ can‬‭ take‬‭ from‬‭ days‬‭ to‬‭ weeks‬‭ if‬‭ there’s‬‭ a‬‭ backlog‬‭ (due‬‭ to‬‭ the‬‭ network’s‬‭ exit‬‭ queue‬‭ and‬‭ “churn‬‭ limit”‬‭ on‬‭ how‬‭ many‬‭ validators‬‭ can‬‭ unlock‬‭ per‬‭ epoch),” Chain told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>During heavy outflows,‬‭ the‬‭ fund‬‭ might‬‭ not‬‭ immediately‬‭ access‬‭ all‬‭ its‬‭ ETH‬‭ to‬‭ meet‬‭ redemptions.‬‭ The‬‭ SEC‬‭ sees‬‭ this‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ structural‬‭ complexity that could harm investors if not planned for.‬</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In‬‭ a‬‭ worst-case‬‭ scenario,‬‭ if‬‭ the‬‭ ETF‬‭ had‬‭ to‬‭ wait‬‭ days‬‭ or‬‭ weeks‬‭ to‬‭ fully‬‭ exit‬‭ staking‬‭ positions,‬‭ an‬‭ investor‬‭ redeeming‬‭ could‬‭ either‬‭ wait‬‭ longer‬‭ for‬‭ their‬‭ proceeds‬‭ or‬‭ get‬‭ paid‬‭ in-kind‬‭ with‬‭ staked‬‭ ETH‬‭ (which‬‭ they‬‭ then‬‭ must‬‭ figure‬‭ out‬‭ how‬‭ to‬‭ redeem‬‭ themselves).‬‭ This‬‭ isn’t‬‭ a‬‭ typical‬‭ concern‬‭ in‬‭ ETFs‬‭ and‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ potential‬‭ downside‬‭ for‬‭ investors‬‭ expecting high liquidity,” Crain added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Finally, there are also security risks that must be addressed responsibly.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-point-and-click-model"><strong>The &#8220;Point-and-Click&#8221; Model</strong></h2>



<p>Securing custody for Ethereum in an ETF is already crucial, and adding staking will increase the SEC&#8217;s scrutiny.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬The‬‭ SEC‬‭ will‬‭ examine‬‭ how‬‭ the‬‭ ETF’s‬‭ custodian‬‭ secures‬‭ the‬‭ ETH‬‭ private‬‭ keys,‬‭ especially‬‭ since‬‭ those‬‭ keys‬‭ (or‬‭ derivative‬‭ keys)‬‭ will‬‭ be‬‭ used‬‭ to‬‭ stake.‬‭ Normally,‬‭ custodians‬‭ use‬‭ cold‬‭ storage‬‭ for‬‭ crypto‬‭ assets,‬‭ but‬‭ staking‬‭ requires‬‭ keys‬‭ to‬‭ be‬‭ online‬‭ in‬‭ a‬‭ validator.‬‭ The‬‭ challenge‬‭ is‬‭ to‬‭ minimize‬‭ exposure while still participating in staking,” Crain said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Recognizing the vulnerability of keys during validator activation, the SEC will most likely require custodians to use cutting-edge security modules to prevent hacking. Any prior incidents of security breaches involving a custodian would raise serious concerns.</p>



<p>Aiming to lessen these risks, some exchanges have proposed that the ETH for staking remain within the custodian&#8217;s control at all times. This model is largely referred to as a “point-and-click” mechanism.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“NYSE‬‭ Arca’s‬‭ proposal‬‭ to‬‭ allow‬‭ the‬‭ Grayscale‬‭ Ethereum‬‭ Trust‬‭ (and‬‭ a‬‭ smaller‬‭ ‘Mini’‬‭ trust)‬‭ to‬‭ stake‬‭ its‬‭ Ether‬‭ via‬‭ a‬‭ ‘point-and-click’‬‭ mechanism‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ test‬‭ case‬‭ that‬‭ will‬‭ significantly‬‭ inform‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ evaluation‬‭ of‬‭ staking‬‭ in‬‭ an‬‭ ETF‬‭ context.‬‭ The‬‭ point-and-click‬‭ staking‬‭ model‬‭ is‬‭ essentially‬‭ a‬‭ way‬‭ to‬‭ stake‬‭ without‬‭ altering‬‭ the‬‭ fundamental‬‭ custody‬‭ or‬‭ introducing‬‭ extra‬‭ complexities‬‭ for‬‭ investors.‬‭ In‬‭ practice,‬‭ this‬‭ means‬‭ the‬‭ trust’s‬‭ custodian‬‭ would‬‭ simply‬‭ enable‬‭ staking‬‭ on‬‭ the‬‭ held‬‭ ETH‬‭ through‬‭ an‬‭ interface.‬‭ The‬‭ coins‬‭ don’t‬‭ leave‬‭ the‬‭ custody‬‭ wallet,‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ process‬‭ is‬‭ as‬‭ straightforward as clicking a button,” Crain explained.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The proposal directly tackles the SEC&#8217;s security worries by emphasizing that the ETH never leaves the custodian, thereby minimizing the theft risk. Furthermore, it clarifies that the yield is generated automatically by the network, not through the entrepreneurial endeavors of a third party.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-when-will-the-sec-approve-staking-in-ethereum-etfs"><strong>When Will the SEC Approve Staking in Ethereum ETFs?</strong></h2>



<p>Despite the complexities and technical details of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/eth-etf-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staking in Ethereum ETFs</a>, the prevailing political climate in the US could <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-paul-atkins-will-reset-us-crypto-policy/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lead to a more favorable environment</a> for their eventual approval.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“On balance, it now seems more likely than not that the SEC will approve a staking feature for Ethereum ETFs in the relatively near future. A more receptive SEC leadership post-2025, strong political backing for staking in ETPs, and well-crafted proposals addressing earlier concerns — such as the point-and-click model — all tilt the odds toward approval. A year or two ago, the SEC was firmly opposed. Now, the conversation has shifted to ‘how to do this safely,’ which marks a significant change,” Crain told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That said, Crain cautioned that the SEC will not approve an ETF of this kind until it&#8217;s fully satisfied with the investor protections in place. Even so, the overall outlook remains positive.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭Considering‬‭ all‬‭ the‬‭ factors‬‭ discussed,‬‭ the‬‭ outlook‬‭ for‬‭ an‬‭ Ethereum‬‭ staking‬‭ ETF‬‭ approval‬‭ appears‬‭ cautiously‬‭ optimistic.‬‭ The‬‭ likelihood‬‭ of‬‭ eventual‬‭ approval‬‭ is‬‭ growing,‬‭ though‬‭ the‬‭ timing‬‭ remains a subject of debate,” Crain concluded.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the best-case scenario, an Ethereum staking ETF could gain approval by the end of 2025.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethereum-etf-staking-sec-approval-challenges/">Will the SEC Approve Staking in Ethereum ETFs? Understanding the Hurdles</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/bic_ethereum_ETF-covers_positive.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/bic_ethereum_ETF-covers_positive.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corporate Bitcoin Holdings Hit Record Levels in Q1 2025: Will the Trend Continue?</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/corporate-bitcoin-accumulation-continue-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Corporate Bitcoin holdings soared in Q1 2025, led by Tether and Metaplanet. However, US trade policy could affect future acquisitions.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/corporate-bitcoin-accumulation-continue-2025/">Corporate Bitcoin Holdings Hit Record Levels in Q1 2025: Will the Trend Continue?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Bitcoin additions to corporate treasuries have risen during the first quarter of 2025, with industry giants like Tether and Metaplanet reaching record allocations compared to the previous quarter.</strong></p>



<p>However, recent trade policy announcements in the US have cast a shadow over further Bitcoin accumulation. BeInCrypto spoke with representatives from CoinShares, Bitget, Brickken, and IntoTheBlock to explore the sustainability of this trend throughout the year and the likelihood of further corporate adoption.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-which-companies-are-leading-the-bitcoin-treasury-charge"><strong>Which Companies Are Leading the Bitcoin Treasury Charge?</strong></h2>



<p>As Bitcoin&#8217;s path to mainstream adoption gains momentum, more companies are either expanding their BTC holdings or allocating the asset to their corporate treasuries for the first time in 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Moving‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ onto‬‭ corporate‬‭ balance‬‭ sheets‬‭ indicates‬‭ growing‬‭ acceptance‬‭ beyond‬‭ just‬‭ speculative‬‭ trading.‬‭ It‬‭ reflects‬‭ an‬‭ increasing‬‭ view‬‭ of‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ legitimate‬‭ treasury‬‭ reserve‬‭ asset‬‭ and‬‭ a‬‭ potential‬‭ long-term‬‭ store‬‭ of‬‭ value‬‭ for‬‭ institutions.‬‭ This‬‭ marks a maturation into a legitimate asset class,” Juan Pellicer, Senior Research Analyst at IntoTheBlock, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The first quarter of 2025 stood out, with several major industry players making their largest Bitcoin allocations. Tether, the world’s largest stablecoin issuer, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/tether-sell-bitcoin-stablecoin-regulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">gradually acquired 8,888 BTC since January</a>, bringing its total BTC balance to over 100,000. In the previous quarter, the issuer had only added 1,035 to its reserve.</p>



<p>Metaplanet also increased its allocation efforts. The Japanese publicly traded company first started purchasing Bitcoin in May 2024. By December, Metaplanet had accumulated 1,762 BTC, which grew to 4,046 by March 2025.</p>



<p>While other high-profile companies did not break their previous allocation records, they significantly expanded their Bitcoin supply.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-expanding-the-ranks-from-microstrategy-to-gamestop"><strong>Expanding the Ranks: From MicroStrategy to GameStop</strong></h2>



<p>Strategy, formerly known as MicroStrategy, has maintained its consistency with its aggressive accumulation style. So far this year, the company has bought a whopping 53,396 BTC.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬Many firms are also drawing inspiration from Michael Saylor’s high-profile Bitcoin strategy since‬‭ August 2020. Its success has set a precedent, showing how a bold allocation to Bitcoin can‬‭ serve as both a hedge and a long-term growth asset,” Bitget CEO Gracy Chen explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Fold Holdings, for example, has only recently begun acquiring Bitcoin. In early March, the financial services company publicly announced that it had bought 475 BTC, bringing its total accumulation to 1,485.</p>



<p>Corporations outside Web3 are also now joining the trend of acquiring Bitcoin. </p>



<p>Two weeks ago, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/why-gamestop-bitcoin-announcement-left-btc-unmoved/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">video game and electronics retailer GameStop</a> announced an update to its investment policy, revealing the addition of Bitcoin as a treasury reserve asset. Although the company made no immediate commitment to purchase BTC, speculation is high that it will allocate a portion of its $4.8 billion cash balance to the cryptocurrency.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Gamestop is preparing to buy Bitcoin with up to $5 billion of cash sitting on their balance sheet.<br><br>Let the games begin. <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%24GME&amp;src=ctag&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">$GME</a> <a href="https://t.co/sEBRYREAK3">pic.twitter.com/sEBRYREAK3</a></p>&mdash; Anthony Pompliano <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f32a.png" alt="🌪" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@APompliano) <a href="https://twitter.com/APompliano/status/1904934696858820811?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 26, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-factors-driving-corporate-bitcoin-adoption"><strong>Factors Driving Corporate Bitcoin Adoption</strong></h2>



<p>Bitcoin has become increasingly appealing to investors looking for an asset to hedge against inflation. Given BTC’s self-limiting supply, it is not subject to the type of depreciation that can impact fiat currencies.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;The combination of digital innovation and finite supply, with only 21 million coins ever to exist,‬ positions Bitcoin as a modern equivalent of digital gold,” Chen told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>According to Max Shannon, an analyst at CoinShares, this may have led Metaplanet to accumulate record amounts of Bitcoin during the first three months of 2025. Metaplanet has already <a href="https://beincrypto.com/metaplanet-aims-to-acquire-10000-btc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">announced plans to amass 10,000 BTC by the end of the year</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“For‬‭ Japanese‬‭ firms‬‭ facing‬‭ persistent‬‭ yen‬‭ depreciation,‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ serves‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ hard-asset‬‭ hedge.‬‭ Moreover,‬‭ in‬‭ markets‬‭ with‬‭ negative‬‭ real‬‭ yields,‬‭ BTC‬‭ offers‬‭ superior‬‭ long-term‬‭ risk-adjusted‬‭ returns.‬‭ Although‬‭ it‬‭ has‬‭ no‬‭ yield‬‭ it‬‭ offers‬‭ long-term‬‭ upside‬‭ and‬‭ inflation‬‭ resistance‬‭ when‬‭ the‬‭ inflation rates‬‭ (either‬‭ prices‬‭ paid or monetary inflation) are higher than the nominal interest rate,” he said. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Given heightened concerns over spikes in inflation in the United States, Bitcoin has also become more appealing among American investors. Changes in accounting for digital currencies have also made them a more attractive addition to investment portfolios.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-appeal-of-new-accounting-standards"><strong>The Appeal of New Accounting Standards</strong></h2>



<p>In addition to its perceived value as an inflation hedge, Bitcoin&#8217;s attractiveness as a corporate investment has been further amplified by recent modifications to accounting standards in the United States.</p>



<p>In January, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fasb-accounting-rules-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Financial‬‭ Accounting‬‭ Standards‬‭ Board‬‭ (FASB)</a> issued a new rule that enabled companies‬‭ with‬‭ BTC‬‭ in‬‭ their‬‭ treasuries‬‭‬‭ to‬‭ report‬‭ the‬‭ profits‬‭ on‬‭ unrealized‬‭ gains‬‭ from‬‭ their‬‭ digital‬‭ assets. Instead of waiting until they have sold their assets, companies can now report that increase in value as income in their financial statements.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‭Selling‬‭ a‬‭ depreciating‬‭ fiat‬‭ currency‬‭ in‬‭ return‬‭ for‬‭ a‬‭ digital‬‭ hard‬‭ asset‬‭ such‬‭ as‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ that‬‭ is‬‭ also‬‭ liquid‬‭ and‬‭ a‬‭ &#8216;cash‬‭ equivalent&#8217;‬‭ that‬‭ can‬‭ benefit‬‭ from‬‭ the‬‭ new‬‭ FASB‬‭ accounting‬‭ treatment‬‭ (which‬‭ can‬‭ also‬‭ improve‬‭ the‬‭ income‬‭ statement)‬‭ makes‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ an‬‭ attractive‬‭ treasury asset,” Shannon added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite its potential for inflation stability, Bitcoin&#8217;s inherent volatility can also attract investors with a greater risk appetite and companies aiming to diversify their holdings.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-can-bitcoin-s-volatility-be-a-strategic-advantage"><strong>Can Bitcoin&#8217;s Volatility Be a Strategic Advantage?</strong></h2>



<p>Beta measures a stock&#8217;s volatility relative to the overall market. The higher the beta, the more volatile the stock is. </p>



<p>According to Shannon, adding a volatile asset like Bitcoin to the balance sheet increases the beta of the equity. If the price of Bitcoin goes up, the overall investor portfolio can score big.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“This‬‭ can‬‭ enhance‬‭ returns‬‭ for‬‭ investors‬‭ and‬‭ has‬‭ proven‬‭ to‬‭ do‬‭ so.‬‭ The‬‭ volatility‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ equity‬‭ also‬‭ tends‬‭ to‬‭ increase‬‭ which‬‭ improves‬‭ the‬‭ interest‬‭ rate‬‭ on‬‭ convertible‬‭ debt,‬‭ therefore,‬‭ impacting‬‭ the‬‭ capital‬‭ structure‬‭ and‬‭ cost‬‭ of‬‭ capital‬‭ for‬‭ the‬‭ company.‬‭ The‬‭ volatility‬‭ also‬‭ gives‬‭ way‬‭ for‬‭ option‬‭ and‬‭ derivative‬‭ traders‬‭ which‬‭ can‬‭ increase‬‭ the‬‭ volumes‬‭ of the stock and make it a more liquid asset,” Shannon told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Strategy serves as an example of these added benefits. Since the company started accumulating Bitcoin in 2020, it has made significant capital gains.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“[Strategy’s] Bitcoin strategy has led to significant returns. For most firms that acquired Bitcoin‬ prior to the inauguration of President Donald Trump, current market prices have significantly exceeded their original entry points, resulting in notable capital gains. This price appreciation‬‭ remains one of the primary incentives for companies to hold Bitcoin in their treasuries,” Chen explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/metaplanet-bitcoin-investment-losses/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">investors can face higher potential losses</a> during a Bitcoin bear market. Because of this, BTC as a treasury asset may be more appealing to companies looking to diversify or firms large enough to weather the storm.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bitcoin-for-specific-business-cases"><strong>Bitcoin for Specific Business Cases</strong></h2>



<p>The volatility and heightened trading activity accompanying Bitcoin adoption might offer a strategic advantage to particular companies, notably <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-lifeline-struggling-companies/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">those with performance issues</a> or in highly competitive sectors.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Underperforming‬‭ or‬‭ mature‬‭ businesses‬‭ in‬‭ competitive‬‭ markets‬‭ would‬‭ benefit‬‭ from‬‭ an‬‭ asset‬‭ that‬‭ increases‬‭ the‬‭ volatilty‬‭ and‬‭ volumes,‬‭ as‬‭ well‬‭ as‬‭ the‬‭ beta‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ equity,” Shannon told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>To that point, Pellicer added:</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Beyond‬‭ diversification,‬‭ holding‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ might‬‭ be‬‭ seen‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ strategic‬‭ move‬‭ to‬‭ gain‬‭ exposure‬‭ to‬‭ the‬‭ potential‬‭ upside‬‭ of‬‭ a‬‭ growing‬‭ asset‬‭ class.‬‭ It‬‭ reflects‬‭ a‬‭ fundamental‬‭ belief‬‭ in‬‭ Bitcoin&#8217;s‬‭ long-term‬‭ value‬‭ proposition‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ hedge‬‭ against‬‭ monetary‬‭ debasement.‬‭ It‬‭ also‬‭ signals‬‭ a‬‭ strategic‬‭ positioning in a pro-crypto political climate (Trump’s policies).‬”‭</p>
</blockquote>



<p>GameStop is a good example of the former. The retailer’s Q4 2024 earnings report <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-to-buy-bitcoin-after-earnings-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">showed a significant decline in its sales volume</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the worrying financial report, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-bitcoin-purchase-stock-surges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">GameStop’s stock value rose by 12%</a> after signaling that it would add BTC as a treasury reserve asset. Limited crypto exposure is expected to strengthen the company’s financial position in 2025.</p>



<p>In turn, Tether&#8217;s perceived robustness could make it more capable of withstanding Bitcoin&#8217;s significant price volatility.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-leveraging-profits-for-bitcoin-tether-s-financial-strategy"><strong>Leveraging Profits for Bitcoin: Tether&#8217;s Financial Strategy</strong></h2>



<p>As the issuer of the largest stablecoin, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-usdt-wallet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tether</a> generates substantial revenue from transaction fees and managing its vast reserves. This financial strength could provide a buffer to absorb potential losses from Bitcoin price drops.</p>



<p>Demonstrating this financial capacity, Tether allocates 15% of its quarterly net profits to Bitcoin.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“This‬‭ is‬‭ similar‬‭ to‬‭ Dollar‬‭ Cost‬‭ Averaging‬‭ by‬‭ allocating‬‭ 15%‬‭ of‬‭ its‬‭ net‬‭ realized‬‭ operating‬‭ profits‬‭ for‬‭ Bitcoin.‬‭ This‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ relatively‬‭ conservative‬‭ approach‬‭ because‬‭ it‬‭ is‬‭ post-tax‬‭ so‬‭ the‬‭ excess‬‭ cash‬‭ (retained‬‭ earnings)‬‭ that‬‭ accrues‬‭ to‬‭ equity‬‭ can‬‭ be‬‭ used‬‭ for‬‭ a‬‭ higher‬‭ growth‬‭ asset.‬‭ In‬‭ this‬‭ instance,‬‭ there‬‭ are‬‭ not‬‭ huge‬‭ drawbacks‬‭ because‬‭ the‬‭ company‬‭ is‬‭ well‬‭ capitalised‬‭ with‬‭ $7 billion‬‭ in‬‭ net‬‭ equity,‬‭ so‬‭ its‬‭ prudent‬‭ risk‬‭ management.‬‭ However,‬‭ there‬‭ are‬‭ still‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/black-swan-meaning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">black‬‭ swans</a>‬‭ where‬‭ cash‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ better needed than Bitcoin,” Shannon explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite its inherent unpredictability, Bitcoin&#8217;s observed long-term decline in volatility over recent years has supported the rationale for including it –even in small amounts– within a well-diversified portfolio.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Bitcoin‬‭ has‬‭ improved‬‭ the‬‭ risk-adjusted‬‭ returns‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ 60/40‬‭ portfolio‬‭ since‬‭ 2017.‬‭ [It] still‬‭ has‬‭ volatility‬‭ risk‬‭ which‬‭ companies‬‭ may‬‭ not‬‭ be‬‭ willing‬‭ to‬‭ absorb,‬‭ however,‬‭ the‬‭ volatility has historically trended down and could continue this into the future,” Shannon added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While acknowledging Bitcoin&#8217;s advantages, Shannon finds it increasingly challenging to foresee if corporate asset accumulation will maintain the same rapid pace in Q2 as it did at the beginning of the year.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-market-disruptions-will-corporate-appetite-wane"><strong>Market Disruptions: Will Corporate Appetite Wane?</strong></h2>



<p>Though only in its second week, April has proven to be a hard month for financial markets. The cryptocurrency sector <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-recovery-trump-liberation-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">experienced the most pronounced impact</a>.</p>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-crypto-mining-trump-liberation-day-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump’s recent Liberation Day celebration</a> sent stocks on a downward spiral as investors braced themselves for incoming uncertainty. During the two days that followed Trump’s tariff announcements, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-black-monday-liquidations-april-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over $1 billion in long and short positions were wiped out</a> by the weekend volatility.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="341" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-850x341.png" alt="" class="wp-image-684891" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-850x341.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-360x145.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-768x308.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-1536x617.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-2048x822.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-08-at-10.32.34 PM-150x60.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin (BTC) Price Performance. Source:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">BeInCrypto</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Amid this new wave of anxiety, Shannon anticipates that companies will prioritize more pressing concerns over further Bitcoin accumulation.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ longer-term‬‭ trend‬‭ points‬‭ to‬‭ further‬‭ balance‬‭ sheet‬‭ accumulation,‬‭ however,‬‭ its‬‭ hard‬‭ to‬‭ call‬‭ quarter‬‭ over‬‭ quarter.‬‭ Based‬‭ on‬‭ the‬‭ current‬‭ volality‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ markets,‬‭ and‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tariff‬‭ implications</a>‬‭ on‬‭ margins,‬‭ I‬‭ suspect‬‭ operational‬‭ issues‬‭ will‬‭ be‬‭ front‬‭ of‬‭ mind‬‭ rather than Bitcoin accumulation,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, current corporate interest in Bitcoin could lead other companies to follow their lead.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-beyond-speculative-trading"><strong>Beyond Speculative Trading</strong></h2>



<p>According to Brickken market analyst Emmanuel Cardozo, Bitcoin allocation efforts will continue throughout the second quarter of 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I’d say we’re likely to see a similar, if not faster, pace of Bitcoin accumulation in Q2 2025 from companies like Strategy, Metaplanet, and Tether. Strategy’s been a consistent buyer, adding to‬‭ their holdings regularly, and I don’t see them stopping,” he explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In Tether’s particular case, whether the company decides to increase or decrease the percentage of revenue it invests in further Bitcoin purchases will depend on how well USDT will perform.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬Tether’s profit allocation strategy means their buys will depend on how USDT performs, but with‬‭ stablecoin demand growing, they’ll probably keep adding at a steady pace considering the‬ ‭ pro-crypto policies possibly coming from Trump’s administration,” Cardozo added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Despite current uncertainties over the US’s trade policies, he believes more corporations will pursue Bitcoin as a treasury asset.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“This corporate adoption wave signals a real shift in how institutional investors see‬‭ Bitcoin. It’s not just a speculative play anymore, but rather treating it like a serious asset to hold‬‭ long-term.‬ It’s a sign Bitcoin’s moving‬‭ from a niche investment to a mainstream part of corporate finance, and I think we’ll see more‬‭ institutions follow suit as they get comfortable with the idea of Bitcoin as a core piece of their‬‭ strategy,” Cardozo concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Ultimately, the decision about whether Bitcoin meaningfully improves treasury performance during economic turmoil will depend on each company&#8217;s specific circumstances.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-an-uncertain-future"><strong>An Uncertain Future</strong></h2>



<p>Corporate Bitcoin accumulation has reached new heights during the first quarter of 2025, but recent political and economic developments can either stump or further accelerate future advancements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bitcoin’s price responded violently to Trump’s Liberation Day announcements, dropping below $75,000. While corporations that have already added Bitcoin as a treasury asset may be confident in the cryptocurrency’s long-term benefits, other companies may take a more conservative approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Until the future of global trade relations becomes clearer, these circumstances may dampen short-term accumulation for newer corporations. Those confident in Bitcoin’s promise as a long-term store of value are already getting a headstart.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/corporate-bitcoin-accumulation-continue-2025/">Corporate Bitcoin Holdings Hit Record Levels in Q1 2025: Will the Trend Continue?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BIC_bitcoin_highs__alltimehigh_growing-covers_positive.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/BIC_bitcoin_highs__alltimehigh_growing-covers_positive.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto as a Lifeline: How Digital Assets Help Ukrainians Navigate Financial Chaos Amid War</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/crypto-lifeline-ukraine-navigate-finance-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684371</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the face of war, digital assets have become a vital lifeline for Ukrainians, ensuring financial autonomy and facilitating global aid efforts amid conflict and displacement.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-lifeline-ukraine-navigate-finance-war/">Crypto as a Lifeline: How Digital Assets Help Ukrainians Navigate Financial Chaos Amid War</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Cryptocurrencies have offered a safety net to people living in contexts of war, displacement, and economic duress. In countries like Ukraine, the accessibility, low transaction costs, and lack of intermediaries associated with digital assets have given citizens a measure of control over their finances since the start of the Russian invasion.</strong></p>



<p>BeInCrypto spoke with representatives from Hacken, Rewump, Grassroots Economics, and Namada &amp; Anoma on the challenges displaced populations face‬‭ in‬‭ accessing‬‭ traditional‬‭ financial‬‭ services and how digital assets can act as a lifeline.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-did-war-cripple-access-to-traditional-finance-for-ukrainians">How Did War Cripple Access to Traditional Finance for Ukrainians?</h2>



<p>Since Russia invaded Ukraine in February 2022, Ukrainians’ access to financial services has been extremely limited. Many bank branches were forced to close due to security concerns, damage, or the inability of staff to reach work. Ukraine’s national bank imposed limits on cash withdrawals at ATMs.</p>



<p>Russian strikes have purposefully targeted the country’s electricity grid, leaving Ukrainians in the dark and without access to a stable internet connection. The nation has grown accustomed to regular outages, which limit access to mobile banking and heighten reliance on cash.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬When‬‭ war‬‭ erupts,‬‭ it&#8217;s‬‭ not‬‭ just‬‭ physical‬‭ infrastructure‬‭ that‬‭ collapses—electricity‬‭ goes‬‭ out,‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/russia-bans-crypto-mining-in-occupied-ukraine/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">cities‬‭ are‬‭ occupied</a>,‬‭ and‬‭ daily‬‭ life‬‭ grinds‬‭ to‬‭ a‬‭ halt.‬‭ In‬‭ times‬‭ of‬‭ extreme‬‭ uncertainty,‬‭ panic‬‭ sets‬‭ in.‬‭ People‬‭ rush‬‭ to‬‭ ATMs,‬‭ desperate‬‭ to‬‭ withdraw‬‭ cash,” Dyma‬‭ Budorin,‬‭ CEO‬‭ &amp;‬‭ co-founder‬‭ at‬‭ Hacken‬, a cybersecurity company&nbsp;with Ukrainian roots, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Obligated by <a href="https://beincrypto.com/russia-uses-crypto-to-trade-with-china/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dire circumstances and the need to adapt</a>, Ukrainians sought other alternatives to maintain some degree of financial autonomy. Many of them found the answer in cryptocurrency.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Digital‬‭ assets‬‭ like‬‭ liquidity‬‭ pools‬‭ for‬‭ communities‬‭ and‬‭ on-chain‬‭ mutual‬‭ aid‬‭ networks‬‭ allow‬‭ for‬‭ trustless‬‭ peer-to-peer‬‭ transactions‬‭ in‬‭ war-torn‬‭ countries‬‭ where‬‭ traditional‬‭ institutions‬‭ might‬‭ no‬‭ longer‬‭ be‬‭ accessible‬‭ or‬‭ even‬‭ operating.‬‭ They’re‬‭ also‬‭ a‬‭ great‬‭ alternative‬‭ to‬‭ fiat‬‭ since‬‭ the‬‭ local‬‭ currency‬‭ of‬‭ countries‬‭ in‬‭ conflict‬‭ often‬‭ experience‬‭ hyperinflation,‬‭ and‬‭ aid‬‭ or‬‭ remittance‬‭ payments‬‭ rely‬‭ on‬‭ centralized‬‭ institutions‬‭ which‬‭ may‬‭ be‬‭ unstable‬‭ or‬‭ politically‬‭ controlled,” said Will‬‭ Ruddick‬‭, founder of Grassroots Economics Foundation.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Although Ukraine was a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ukraine-crypto-regulation-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leader in digital asset adoption</a> before the war, its usage has proliferated since 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-crypto-s-role-in-funding-ukrainian-aid-efforts">Crypto&#8217;s Role in Funding Ukrainian Aid Efforts</h2>



<p>Since the start of the war, pro-Ukrainian causes <a href="https://beincrypto.com/?post_type%5B%5D=post&amp;post_type%5B%5D=glossary&amp;post_type%5B%5D=toppicks&amp;bic-search-post-type-829b6c9346708920e5db0701bee5de4b=&amp;s=ukraine#:~:text=Ukraine%20Bank%20Mulls%20Blockchain%20Implementation%20After%20Stellar%20Pilot%20Run" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">have leveraged blockchain technology</a> as a fundraising method for donations. According to an Elliptic <a href="https://www.elliptic.co/blog/analysis/crypto-donations-to-ukraine-and-russia-breaking-down-the-numbers#:~:text=Receiving%20over%20%24212%20million%20in,a%20key%20ally%20of%20Russia." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a>, they have since raised over $212.1 million in cryptoassets, predominantly donations to official Ukrainian government wallets. By the fourth day of the war, around $30 million was already raised.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ crypto‬‭ industry‬‭ rallied‬‭ around‬‭ Ukraine,‬‭ offering‬‭ new‬‭ ways‬‭ to‬‭ directly‬‭ contribute‬‭ to‬‭ relief‬‭ efforts‬‭ and‬‭ support‬‭ the‬‭ government.‬‭ From‬‭ medical‬‭ aid‬‭ and‬‭ civilian‬‭ relief‬‭ to‬‭ defense‬‭ equipment,‬‭ these‬‭ funds‬‭ have‬‭ been‬‭ hugely‬‭ supportive‬‭ in‬‭ Ukraine’s‬‭ time‬‭ of‬‭ crisis,”‭ Ruddick said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top-defi-protocols/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Decentralized Finance (DeFi)</a>, Non-Fungible Tokens (<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/nft-advertising/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">NFTs</a>), and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/dao-governance-challenges-long-term-viability/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAOs)</a> have emerged as significant tools in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ukraine-crypto-donations-approaching-70-million-chainalysis/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">facilitating cryptocurrency fundraising efforts for Ukraine</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to Elliptic, these novel technologies have collectively raised over $78 million in donations to support the country. NFT campaigns have played a substantial role in this broader effort, accounting for approximately 10% of the funds raised.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‭Blockchain‬‭ infrastructure‬‭ provides‬‭ the‬‭ most‬‭ powerful‬‭ channel‬‭ for‬‭ high-value‬‭ single‬‭ donations.‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/vitalik-buterin-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Vitalik‬‭ Buterin</a>‬‭ contributed‬‭ at‬‭ least‬‭ $5‬‭ million,‬‭ Gavin‬‭ Wood‬‭ donated‬‭ $5.8‬‭ million.‬‭ Moreover, UkraineDAO&#8217;s NFT sale of the national flag raised $6.75 million,” Budorin added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, cryptoassets have also provided displaced Ukrainians with significant financial flexibility.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-financial-hurdles-do-displaced-ukrainians-face">What Financial Hurdles Do Displaced Ukrainians Face?</h2>



<p>According to data from the UN Refugee Agency (UNHCR), nearly 7 million refugees have fled Ukraine since the start of the war. Meanwhile, around 3.7 million Ukrainians have been internally displaced.</p>



<p>Sergii Malomuzh, founder of Rewump, explained that displaced individuals face multiple obstacles in accessing traditional financial services. These include the loss of crucial identification, the inability to conduct transactions abroad due to a lack of local banking, high international <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-exchange-fees/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">transfer fees</a>, and the instability of their national currencies.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Digital‬‭ assets‬‭ can‬‭ help‬‭ address‬‭ these‬‭ challenges‬‭ by‬‭ providing‬‭ access‬‭ to‬‭ financial‬‭ services‬‭ without‬‭ needing‬‭ physical‬‭ documents,‬‭ being‬‭ unaffected‬‭ by‬‭ geographical‬‭ restrictions,‬‭ offering‬‭ lower‬‭ costs‬‭ for‬‭ international‬‭ transfers,‬‭ and‬‭ enabling‬‭ operations‬‭ without‬‭ depending‬‭ on‬‭ banks.‬‭ They‬‭ also‬‭ act‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ way‬‭ to‬‭ preserve‬‭ value‬‭ through‬‭ stablecoins,” Malomuzh told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While cash is another option, carrying one&#8217;s life savings in physical form makes refugees vulnerable targets.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-digital-vs-physical-cash">Digital vs. Physical Cash</h2>



<p>Beyond the impracticality of refugees carrying large sums of cash, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top-blockchain-security-protocols/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">security offered by digital assets</a> has quickly become a vital advantage for those forced to flee their homes.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭For‬‭ refugees,‬‭ carrying‬‭ cash‬‭ across‬‭ borders‬‭ was‬‭ not‬‭ only‬‭ impractical‬‭ but‬‭ also‬‭ dangerous,‬‭ as‬‭ they‬‭ were‬‭ already‬‭ a‬‭ vulnerable‬‭ population‬‭ at‬‭ risk‬‭ of‬‭ theft,‬‭ loss,‬‭ or‬‭ exploitation.‬‭ Having‬‭ their‬‭ savings‬‭ in‬‭ digital‬‭ form‬‭ provided‬‭ a‬‭ safer‬‭ alternative,‬‭ allowing‬‭ them‬‭ to‬‭ securely‬‭ access‬‭ and‬‭ transport‬‭ funds‬‭ without‬‭ the‬‭ risks‬‭ associated‬‭ with‬‭ physical‬‭ cash,” Budorin said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The ability of digital assets to bypass traditional banking hurdles directly translates into the speed and efficiency required in the often fast-moving circumstances of displacement.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Additionally,‬‭ digital‬‭ assets‬‭ allow‬‭ financial‬‭ transactions‬‭ to‬‭ happen‬‭ without‬‭ relying‬‭ on‬‭ banks,‬‭ which‬‭ is‬‭ crucial‬‭ in‬‭ these‬‭ situations.‬‭ Their‬‭ low‬‭ transaction‬‭ fees‬‭ and‬‭ high‬‭ liquidity‬‭ also‬‭ make‬‭ them‬‭ user-friendly.‬‭ The‬‭ decentralized‬‭ nature‬‭ of‬‭ cryptocurrencies‬‭ means‬‭ that‬‭ funds‬‭ can‬‭ be‬‭ sent‬‭ rapidly‬‭ to‬‭ areas‬‭ affected‬‭ by‬‭ conflict‬‭ or‬‭ disaster,‬‭ bypassing‬‭ the‬‭ slowdowns‬‭ common‬‭ in‬‭ traditional‬‭ financial‬‭ systems.‬‭ This‬‭ empowers‬‭ people‬‭ to‬‭ maintain‬‭ control‬‭ over‬‭ their‬‭ finances,‬‭ even‬‭ in‬‭ situations where banks may fail,” ‭Malomuzh added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, even with the numerous advantages of crypto in war-torn conditions, significant risks and challenges warrant consideration.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-are-the-privacy-risks">What Are the Privacy Risks?</h2>



<p>Adrian‬‭ Brink‬‭,‬‭ co-founder‬‭ of‬‭ Namada &amp; Anoma‬, highlighted the distinct difference between anonymous and pseudonymous privacy features. While the former refers to a real-world identity that is completely unknown, the latter alludes to an identity that is not directly revealed.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“A‬‭ big‬‭ risk‬‭ is‬‭ that‬‭ people‬‭ adopt‬‭ cryptocurrencies‬‭ without‬‭ understanding‬‭ the‬‭ tradeoffs,‬‭ privacy‬‭ being‬‭ a‬‭ huge‬‭ one,‬‭ where‬‭ people‬‭ think‬‭ that‬‭ these‬‭ systems‬‭ are‬‭ anonymous‬‭ when‬‭ they’re‬‭ really‬‭ not.‬‭ Especially‬‭ in‬‭ places‬‭ where‬‭ you‬‭ can’t‬‭ trust‬‭ the‬‭ ruling‬‭ state‬‭ or‬‭ when‬‭ adversaries‬‭ are‬‭ monitoring‬‭ networks‬‭ to‬‭ target‬‭ the‬‭ opposition,” Brink‬‭ told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Most popular cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin and Ethereum, are pseudonymous. All transactions associated with a user’s wallet address are permanently recorded on the blockchain. While the user’s name isn’t directly apparent, various methods can eventually link activity back to their real identity.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ lack‬‭ of‬‭ privacy‬‭ with‬‭ public‬‭ blockchains‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ significant‬‭ issue.‬‭ The‬‭ ability‬‭ to‬‭ connect‬‭ people’s‬‭ identity‬‭ to‬‭ crypto‬‭ donations‬‭ opens‬‭ them‬‭ up‬‭ to‬‭ surveillance‬‭ and‬‭ can‬‭ actually‬‭ put‬‭ people’s‬‭ lives‬‭ in‬‭ danger.‬‭ We‬‭ urgently‬‭ need‬‭ the‬‭ ability‬‭ to protect people’s sensitive data when using blockchains,” Brink‬‭ added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>These risks are amplified when entire populations are under siege, potentially leading to repercussions against political opponents or specific targets.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“People’s‬‭ lives‬‭ can‬‭ be‬‭ at‬‭ risk‬‭ when‬‭ their‬‭ identities‬‭ can‬‭ be‬‭ linked‬‭ with‬‭ their‬‭ on-chain‬‭ activity,‬‭ so‬‭ we‬‭ really‬‭ need‬‭ to‬‭ see adoption and awareness of privacy-preserving systems. Education will be key here,” Brink concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Ultimately, a focused global effort to understand, address, and effectively mitigate the inherent <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/web3-privacy-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">privacy risks within blockchain networks</a> will unlock the future potential of digital assets to deliver even greater financial resilience for conflict-affected populations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Overcoming these privacy concerns will make digital assets an even more powerful tool in contexts of war and human displacement.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-lifeline-ukraine-navigate-finance-war/">Crypto as a Lifeline: How Digital Assets Help Ukrainians Navigate Financial Chaos Amid War</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_Altcoin_coin_5-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_Altcoin_coin_5-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ripple,‬‭ Coinbase,‬‭ Kraken‬‭ —‬‭ Is‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ War‬‭ on‬‭ Crypto‬‭ Ending‬‭ as‬‭ Lawsuits‬‭ Fall?‬</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/ripple-coinbase-kraken-sec-crypto-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p> The SEC’s change in stance toward crypto companies marks a win for the industry, but the lack of regulations leaves room for scams, raising long-term concerns.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-coinbase-kraken-sec-crypto-war/">Ripple,‬‭ Coinbase,‬‭ Kraken‬‭ —‬‭ Is‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ War‬‭ on‬‭ Crypto‬‭ Ending‬‭ as‬‭ Lawsuits‬‭ Fall?‬</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Since US President Donald Trump assumed office, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has dropped, settled, or paused lawsuits against prominent crypto entities left and right. In stark contrast to the previous administration’s leadership under Chair Gary Gensler, the SEC seems to be parting from its previous crackdown on digital assets.</strong></p>



<p>In an interview with BeInCrypto, Nick Puckrin, Founder of The Coin Bureau, and Hank Huang, Chief Executive Officer at Kronos Research, highlighted the substantial election influence the crypto industry had over Trump’s candidacy as a contributing factor to the SEC’s looser stance on crypto.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-sec-s-approach-under-trump">The SEC&#8217;s Approach Under Trump</h2>



<p>The SEC has experienced a clear shift in its approach to crypto lawsuits under Trump’s presidency. Its move away from the aggressive enforcement tactics of its previous leadership has largely characterized this shift.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“When President Donald Trump won the US election, the crypto industry rejoiced. Finally, the‬ ‘regulation by enforcement’ era, which the SEC under‬‭ the leadership of Gary Gensler was so famous for, was about to come to an end. And the new‬‭ administration didn’t disappoint. Within just a couple of weeks of Trump’s inauguration, the‬‭ revamped SEC started dropping lawsuits against crypto firms‬‭ left, right and center‬‭,” Puckrin said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Two weeks ago, the SEC officially <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sec-drops-xrp-lawsuit-against-ripple/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dropped its appeal and XRP lawsuit against Ripple Labs</a>, ending a five-year legal battle. The Commission had originally accused Ripple of conducting an unregistered securities offering worth $1.3 billion through XRP sales.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“After more‬‭ than four years in limbo, the SEC has officially decided that XRP is not a security (though what it‬‭ is instead remains to be seen). This case has been weighing heavily on XRP – the fourth largest‬‭ cryptocurrency with a‬‭ market cap of roughly $130 billion‬‭– so its resolution is a major win,” Puckrin added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The wider crypto community celebrated the outcome, with many arguing that it will set a precedent for how digital assets are classified in the US. This prediction is warranted, given that the SEC has been on a lawsuit-dropping spree.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ripple-and-coinbase-cases-mark-significant-wins">Ripple and Coinbase Cases Mark Significant Wins</h2>



<p>Shortly before ending the Ripple lawsuit, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sec-to-drop-coinbase-lawsuit-xrp/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the SEC dropped its legal battle against Coinbase</a>. The case also centered on whether Coinbase should be classified as a security.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The‬‭ SEC‬‭ is‬‭ clearly‬‭ retreating‬‭ from‬‭ its‬‭ once-aggressive‬‭ stance‬‭ on‬‭ crypto,‬‭ as‬‭ seen‬‭ in‬‭ its‬‭ 2025‬‭ dismissal‬‭ of‬‭ lawsuits‬‭ against‬‭ Ripple,‬‭ Coinbase,‬‭ and‬‭ others.‬‭ This‬‭ shift,‬‭ driven‬‭ by‬‭ the‬‭ crypto-friendly‬‭ and‬‭ pro-business‬‭ Trump‬‭ administration,‬‭ signals‬‭ a‬‭ future‬‭ of‬‭ more‬‭ streamlined‬‭ and‬‭ transparent‬‭ US‬‭ crypto‬‭ regulation,” Huang told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The SEC has also dropped several ongoing investigations against OpenSea, Robinhood, Uniswap Labs, Kraken, and Gemini. It has also asked a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-sec-pause-legal-battle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">federal court to issue a 60-day pause</a> over its litigation against Binance. Meanwhile, the Commission settled its investigation into ConsenSys over its Ethereum software products.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These lawsuits surfaced in parallel to a series of crypto-friendly measures meant to foster greater innovation and curb potential regulatory suffocation that had existed during the Biden era.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-will-new-leadership-define-clear-crypto-regulations">Will New Leadership Define Clear Crypto Regulations?</h2>



<p>A day after Trump assumed office, SEC Acting Chairman Mark Uyeda announced the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sec-crypto-task-force-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">creation of a dedicated crypto task force</a> led by Commissioner Hester Peirce. The task force was reportedly designed to resolve long-standing ambiguities in the regulatory treatment of digital assets.</p>



<p>In all SEC crypto lawsuits, Commissioner Uyeda has implemented a strategy prioritizing industry engagement to develop regulatory frameworks that balance innovation and investor protection.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Trump strategically nominated <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/who-is-paul-atkins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Paul Atkins, a crypto-curious, regulation-light candidate</a>, to replace Gensler as head of the SEC. Just this week, the Senate Banking Committee voted to advance Atkins’ nomination to the full Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Driven‬‭ by‬‭ Republican‬‭ principles,‬‭ the‬‭ SEC‬‭ under‬‭ Trump‬‭ could‬‭ implement‬‭ clearer‬‭ crypto‬‭ guidelines‬‭ by‬‭ 2025,‬‭ reduce‬‭ regulatory‬‭ burdens,‬‭ and‬‭ roll‬‭ back‬‭ Biden-era‬‭ policies‬‭ that‬‭ have‬‭ stifled‬‭ innovation‬‭ by‬‭ 2027.‬‭ This‬‭ could‬‭ mark‬‭ the‬‭ beginning‬‭ of‬‭ treating‬‭ most‬‭ digital‬‭ assets‬‭ as‬‭ commodities,” Huang said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Now, only a stone’s throw away from becoming SEC Chair, Atkins is expected to loosen regulatory oversight on crypto.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“With‬‭ the‬‭ establishment‬‭ of‬‭ a‬‭ new‬‭ Task‬‭ Force‬‭ and‬‭ key‬‭ appointees‬‭ like‬‭ Paul‬‭ Atkins‬‭ fostering‬‭ innovation,‬‭ Trump&#8217;s‬‭ strategic‬‭ move‬‭ to‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/strategic-bitcoin-reserve-usa-executive-order/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">create‬‭ a‬‭ Bitcoin‬‭ reserve</a> within the government further underscores his commitment to supporting the industry.‬‭ The‬‭ future‬‭ of‬‭ crypto‬‭ regulations‬‭ will‬‭ be‬‭ focused‬‭ on‬‭ less‬‭ oversight‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ beginning‬‭ of‬‭ a‬‭ delicate‬‭ but promising thaw in the regulatory landscape,” Huang added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Though some say Trump’s handling of crypto affairs has resulted in a never-before-seen triumph, others are weary that his increasing involvement in the industry has turned out to be a recipe for disaster.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-impact-of-crypto-donations-on-regulations">The Impact of Crypto Donations on Regulations</h2>



<p>Several industry leaders went to great lengths to ensure that Trump became America’s 47th president. Millions of dollars in donations from crypto firms throughout Trump&#8217;s campaign illustrated these efforts.</p>



<p>According to a Public Citizen <a href="https://www.citizen.org/article/big-crypto-big-spending-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a>, over $119 million from crypto corporations <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-involvement-in-us-elections/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">went into influencing the 2024 federal elections</a>, largely through Fairshake, a non-partisan super PAC backing pro-crypto candidates and opposing skeptics.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1638" height="1198" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM.png" alt="Crypto corporations donated over $119 million to the 2024 federal elections." class="wp-image-683590" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM.png 1638w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM-360x263.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM-850x622.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM-768x562.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM-1536x1123.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-04-at-4.55.25 PM-150x110.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1638px) 100vw, 1638px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Crypto corporations donated over $119 million to the 2024 federal elections. Source: <a href="https://www.citizen.org/article/big-crypto-big-spending-2024/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Public Citizen</a></figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-donations-xrp-ripple-trump-fund/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coinbase and Ripple</a>, among others who stand to profit, directly provided over half of Fairshake&#8217;s funding. The remaining funds mostly came from billionaire crypto executives and venture capitalists. Notable contributions included $44 million from the founders of Andreessen Horowitz, $5 million from the Winklevoss twins, and $1 million from Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.</p>



<p>So far, big crypto&#8217;s spending strategy is paying off with a more favorable environment.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Political‬‭ donations‬‭ from‬‭ the‬‭ crypto‬‭ industry‬‭ during‬‭ the‬‭ 2024‬‭ election,‬‭ particularly‬‭ to‬‭ pro-crypto‬‭ candidates‬‭ like‬‭ Trump,‬‭ played‬‭ a‬‭ significant‬‭ role‬‭ in‬‭ shaping‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ 2025‬‭ decision‬‭ to‬‭ drop‬‭ lawsuits‬‭ against‬‭ crypto‬‭ firms.‬‭ These‬‭ contributions‬‭ helped‬‭ align‬‭ the‬‭ administration‬‭ with‬‭ the‬‭ industry&#8217;s‬‭ interests‬‭ and‬‭ influenced‬‭ Congress,‬‭ driving‬‭ about‬‭ 50-60%‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ shift,” Huang told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Without a clear framework to guide the crypto industry following these dropped lawsuits, this lax approach risks being short-lived. Ultimately, this could tarnish long-term crypto adoption.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-meme-coin-scams-highlight-deregulation-dangers">Meme Coin Scams Highlight Deregulation Dangers</h2>



<p>According to Puckrin, the success of the dropped lawsuits was obscured by the lack of regulations that have led to the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-spot-meme-coin-scams/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">proliferation of high-profile meme coin scams</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Somehow, all these victories feel somewhat hollow after the reputation of the crypto industry‬‭ has been tarnished by the‬‭ billions of dollars‬‭ in combined‬‭ losses from‬‭ meme coin scams‬‭.‬‭ Meanwhile, Hayden Davis, the mastermind behind LIBRA,‬‭ continues to launch fraudulent meme‬‭ tokens‬‭, despite being on the Interpol wanted list,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A 2024 report by Web3 intelligence platform Merkle Science revealed that meme coin rug pulls cost investors over $500 million. The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/argentina-investigate-milei-assets-libra-scandal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">February LIBRA incident</a> showed how this trend was carried over to 2025. Nansen data revealed that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/libra-investors-losses-nansen/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">86% of investors lost $251 million</a>, while insiders pocketed $180 million in profits.</p>



<p>Though crypto scammers may be charged with related crimes like wire fraud or money laundering, rug pulling is legal. Better said, it&#8217;s unaccounted for. No regulation holds crypto insiders responsible for meme coin scams.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“As crypto becomes an ever more mainstream asset class, consumers need to be protected‬‭ against those who choose to use it for nefarious purposes. One way to do this is through‬‭ education, and that’s our job as an industry. But deterring scams and extractive behavior is the‬‭ job of the regulators. And it’s time they stepped up to the task,” Puckrin told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If the SEC doesn’t take advantage of this opportunity to curb the consequences that meme coin scams can produce, it will result in an enormous setback for the industry.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-comprehensive-regulation-beyond-dropped-lawsuits">Comprehensive Regulation Beyond Dropped Lawsuits</h2>



<p>‭Puckrin illustrated the need for heightened regulatory clarity in crypto by drawing attention to the way the SEC penalizes insider trading in the context of traditional investing.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In traditional investing, insider trading is a serious crime. In the US, it’s‬‭ punishable by‬‭ fines of up‬‭ to $5 million for individuals and prison sentences up to 20 years. Similarly, federal penalties for‬‭ engaging with illegal gambling activities include‬‭ up to five years in prison‬‭. Perpetrators of‬‭ memecoin scams must be punished with the same level of severity, because the result is the‬‭ same: manipulating markets and cheating unsuspecting investors out of their savings,” he said. ‭</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Puckrin clarified, however, that the issue isn&#8217;t solely about penalizing fraudsters. Just as the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coinbase-sues-sec-crypto-crackdown/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SEC&#8217;s past overregulation hindered the industry</a>, the current lack of meme coin rules creates an environment where new scams and exploitative schemes can easily flourish.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Yes, the removal of lawsuits is‬‭ great news for blockchain innovation, but something needs to replace it. Indeed, serious‬‭ cryptocurrency firms have never advocated for an unregulated Wild West.‬‭ What they want is clarity and rules that are fit for the nascent blockchain industry – not just a‬‭ copy-and-paste of existing financial regulations that simply don’t work for crypto,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Although the Trump administration has only been in place for four months, the clock is ticking, and meaningful change takes time.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-unanswered-questions-loom">Unanswered Questions Loom</h2>



<p>Puckrin expressed concern over the current administration’s prioritization of lawsuit dismissals instead of working faster to implement transcendental crypto regulation.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My concern is that‬‭ regulators will keep kicking the can down the road with crypto regulation, having gained the‬‭ approval of the industry for dropping the many lawsuits that were stifling its growth. And this is‬‭ incredibly dangerous,” he told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, critical questions that only the SEC can define remain unanswered.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“What are memecoins and who will ensure another LIBRA fiasco‬‭ doesn’t happen? Are utility altcoins now commodities and if so, will the Commodities Futures‬‭ Trading Commission (CFTC) regulate them? And, importantly, what do we do about‬‭ compensating investors who have lost‬‭ billions to crypto‬‭ fraud‬‭?” Puckrin concluded.‭</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The SEC&#8217;s current direction promises a regulated renaissance or a breeding ground for future crises.</p>



<p>With billions lost and critical questions unanswered, the future of crypto hinges on whether the regulatory body will translate its recent shift into a lasting framework that fosters innovation without sacrificing investor protection.</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-coinbase-kraken-sec-crypto-war/">Ripple,‬‭ Coinbase,‬‭ Kraken‬‭ —‬‭ Is‬‭ the‬‭ SEC’s‬‭ War‬‭ on‬‭ Crypto‬‭ Ending‬‭ as‬‭ Lawsuits‬‭ Fall?‬</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/bic_Regulations_1-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/03/bic_Regulations_1-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Crypto Mining in Crisis? How Trump’s Liberation Day Tariffs Could Shake the Industry</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/us-crypto-mining-trump-liberation-day-tariffs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulation News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=682195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trump's Liberation Day tariffs threaten to significantly disrupt the US crypto mining industry by raising costs and disrupting supply chains.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-crypto-mining-trump-liberation-day-tariffs/">US Crypto Mining in Crisis? How Trump’s Liberation Day Tariffs Could Shake the Industry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Later today, US President Trump will celebrate what he refers to as Liberation Day by continuing with a tariff policy to reduce American reliance on foreign products. Depending on the severity of the tariffs, the domestic crypto-mining industry will suffer considerable losses.</strong></p>



<p>In an interview with BeInCrypto, Matt Pearl, director of the Strategic Technologies Program at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS), and Pat Zhang, head of research at crypto exchange WOO X, explained that levies on China will inherently disrupt supply chain dynamics and increase operational costs for the US mining industry.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-will-liberation-day-tariffs-impact-mining-costs">How Will Liberation Day Tariffs Impact Mining Costs?</h2>



<p>Later today, Trump is expected to unveil <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sweeping tariffs on US imports</a> as part of an economic agenda he denominated as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-liberation-day-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Liberation Day</a>. However, details on how aggressive they will be or which countries will be most targeted have been lackluster.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-trumps-liberation-day-tariff-impact-crypto-market/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">absence of information</a> surrounding the event has left the greater public in the dark, guessing what will happen next. In the case of the US mining industry, participants will watch Trump’s announcements regarding China.</p>



<p>A little over a month ago, the Trump administration <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-tariffs-impact-crypto-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">slapped a new 10% tariff on goods from China</a> on top of the existing 10% tariff it had enacted only weeks before. During his campaign trail, Trump even proposed up to 60% border taxes on Chinese goods.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If Trump applies further levies on China in light of Liberation Day, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-mining-faces-tariff-challenges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">American Bitcoin miners will have to make many decisions</a> regarding the nature and scale of their future operations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-asic-hardware-the-crucial-import">ASIC Hardware: The Crucial Import</h2>



<p>Crypto mining heavily relies on Application-Specific Integrated Circuit (ASIC) equipment. These computer chips are built to perform the complex mathematical calculations required to validate transactions and mine new coins. They are particularly indispensable in Bitcoin and other proof-of-work cryptocurrencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ASICs have become the dominant hardware in Bitcoin mining due to their superior performance over other types of hardware, such as CPUs or GPUs. They offer a much higher hash rate per unit of energy consumed and are designed for specific mining algorithms.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It’s an incredibly R&amp;D-intensive process to create an ASIC that is energy efficient and does everything you need in the context of Bitcoin mining,” Pearl explained.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The United States heavily relies on imports of ASIC mining hardware, with a substantial portion coming from China. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-crypto-trade-war-us-china/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">China, the US’s longtime trade rival</a>, has well-established manufacturing capabilities for producing advanced semiconductor chips.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-american-reliance-on-chinese-hardware-equipment">American Reliance on Chinese Hardware Equipment</h2>



<p>According to the data from the Observatory of Economic Complexity (OEC), in 2023, the United States became the world&#8217;s largest importer of electrical machinery and electronics. That year, it imported $455 billion worth of hardware, such as integrated circuits (ASICs), semiconductor devices, and electrical transformers.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1088" height="1038" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM.png" alt="The United States imports the largest amount of electrical machinery from China." class="wp-image-682199" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM.png 1088w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM-360x343.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM-850x811.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM-768x733.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-01-at-6.47.10 PM-150x143.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1088px) 100vw, 1088px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The United States imports the largest amount of electrical machinery from China. Source: <a href="https://oec.world/en/profile/bilateral-product/electrical-machinery-and-electronics/reporter/usa" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">OEC</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Electrical machinery and electronics were recorded as the second-largest import category, with China supplying $119 billion of that total, comfortably consolidating its position as the US’s top vendor.</p>



<p>In January 2025 alone, the United States&#8217; Electrical machinery and electronics exports accounted for up to $19 billion, and imports amounted to $41.3 billion, with most imports coming from China.</p>



<p>Given that the US heavily depends on China for this specialized hardware, any tariffs imposed on electronic imports from China would directly affect the cost of ASIC mining hardware in the US.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The US mining industry is heavily dependent on Chinese manufacturers, which control 70% to 80% of the global ASIC market. A 25% tariff would immediately raise hardware costs, adding $1,250 per unit for a miner like the Antminer S19, eroding margins, especially for large-scale operations. If restrictions escalate to outright bans or export controls, miners could face supply shortages, slowing industry growth,” Zhang explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Though less severe, Trump&#8217;s tariff policies during his first term in office offer a glimpse into their potential impact on cryptocurrency miners.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-lessons-from-trump-s-first-term">Lessons from Trump’s First Term</h2>



<p>In June 2018, the United States Trade Representative under Trump reclassified Bitmain, a Chinese Bitcoin mining hardware maker, from a “data processing machine” to an “electrical machinery apparatus.” Bitmain, specifically its “Antminer” series, is a leading manufacturer of ASIC mining hardware.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By reclassifying the hardware, a 2.6% tariff was added to the existing 25% tariff on Chinese goods. This effectively raised the total tariff on US shipments for Chinese crypto mining equipment to 27.6%.</p>



<p>Mining hardware costs are one of the largest input costs <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-states-push-crypto-bills-in-march/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">operators in the American mining business</a> face. Following the tariff hike, crypto miners inevitably saw their production costs increase significantly.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Hardware costs typically make up 30% to 40% of mining expenses,” Zhang explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The current cumulative 20% tariffs on Chinese goods and the potential for further increases after Trump&#8217;s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-btc-liberation-day-indicators-collide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Liberation Day announcements suggest a similar or more severe impact</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In the short to medium term, [the US mining industry] is extremely vulnerable, particularly because most of the Bitcoin mining equipment is coming from China. ASICs are not easy to produce, and so it&#8217;s going to raise the price of Bitcoin mining equipment in the US. It did in 2018 when Trump imposed tariffs in his first term, and it’ll be even more significant this time,” Pearl told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The impact will be most severe for smaller mining firms, potentially jeopardizing their entire operations.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Smaller miners are highly exposed. A 25% tariff could cut profit margins from 37% to 25%, reducing expansion potential but keeping operations viable. A 60% tariff, however, would push margins into single digits, near breakeven. Any drop in Bitcoin’s price or increase in mining difficulty could turn these operations unprofitable, forcing closures,” Zhang told BeInCrypto, adding that, “larger firms have more flexibility, but persistent high costs would slow expansion, allowing global competitors to gain market share.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Aside from increased costs, tariffs will also cause a disruption in supply chain dynamics for mining hardware.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-supply-chain-disruptions-a-looming-threat">Supply Chain Disruptions: A Looming Threat</h2>



<p>According to Pearl, US crypto miners can expect delays and shortages in mining hardware if Trump applies further tariffs on China. His judgment is mainly based on the fact that this is already occurring.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We&#8217;re already seeing delays. We&#8217;ve already seen Customs and Border Patrol taking longer to examine the equipment and clear it through customs, and then you also had the US Postal Service that had very temporarily halted package shipments from China,” Pearl explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Two months ago, the US Postal Service (USPS) announced that it had temporarily suspended package deliveries from China shortly after Trump imposed 10% tariffs on Chinese imports. USPS clarified that the suspension stemmed from removing an exemption allowing duty-free, inspection-free shipments under $800.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The USPS and Customs and Border Protection are working closely together to implement an efficient collection mechanism for the new China tariffs to ensure the least disruption to package delivery,” the Postal Service said in a statement.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The suspension, however, was reversed less than 24 hours later. Yet, with new tariffs on the horizon, a similar situation can play out, threatening to backlog mining plans for American Bitcoin miners.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Once [Trump] imposes the tariffs it&#8217;ll be even more significant in terms of, it&#8217;ll raise costs, it&#8217;ll depress the amount that&#8217;s sent, and then it&#8217;ll raise uncertainty about whether the Customs and Border Patrol or others will slow things down when they do get to the US. It&#8217;s harder for companies to have assurance about when they&#8217;ll be able to actually begin mining,” Pearl added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Zhang added that miners should be especially concerned about tariffs exceeding 25%. They could also lead to a reduction in hashrate, affecting the security of the Bitcoin network.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If tariffs exceed 25% and are combined with export restrictions, supply chain disruptions could last over six months, pushing the US hashrate below 30% of the global total and shifting mining dominance elsewhere,” Zhang told BeinCrypto, adding that, “Bitcoin’s network is resilient, but such a decline could make attacks or regulatory influence more feasible.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If tariffs persist, US crypto mining companies will require considerable long-term restructuring.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-will-us-miners-relocate-due-to-tariffs">Will US Miners Relocate Due to Tariffs?</h2>



<p>Though there’s no evidence that American crypto mining companies relocated due to Trump’s tariff policy during his first presidency, this option is a plausible outcome this second time around.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think the difference this time is that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/experts-warn-volatility-liberation-day-trump/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">there&#8217;s a lot more uncertainty</a>. The President seems to be much more focused on tariffs and so far, it seems that there&#8217;s a lack of permanence to the administration’s decisions. There&#8217;s an imposition of tariffs, but then they&#8217;ll adjust them or increase them, so I think that there&#8217;s just a lot more uncertainty than there was in the first administration. That&#8217;s what would make it different, in terms of seeing more relocation of the mining industry elsewhere, outside of the US,” Pearl told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Clara Chappaz, France&#8217;s Digital Minister, suggested monetizing EDF&#8217;s surplus energy through Bitcoin mining this week. EDF is the country’s largest state-owned energy company. According to Chappaz, this approach could help reduce the company’s debt. Many in the broader crypto community celebrated the idea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If Europe surrenders itself to these strategies, might American companies feel more inclined to move their operations abroad? Pearl says yes, but Europe is not the region of preference.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think the countervailing thing is that labor costs are more expensive in Europe. There can be a lot more red tape in permitting and actually building the infrastructure. I wonder if there are other regulatory and labor barriers that will make a shift to Europe less likely than a shift to other parts of Asia,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Regardless of where miners choose to operate, the critical dependence on a stable ASIC supply chain remains a significant hurdle.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-an-unlikely-outcome">An Unlikely Outcome</h2>



<p>Zhang suggested that miners would require substantial tariff pressure to justify relocation.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Relocation would depend on the severity of tariffs. At 10%-15%, only a small fraction of miners—1%-5% of the US hashrate, would move. At 25%-30%, this could rise to 7%-17%, primarily among mid-sized players. If tariffs reach 50% or more, we could see a mass exodus of 20%-45% of the hash rate, significantly shifting global mining power away from the US,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, simple relocation won’t eliminate the need for access to a consistent ASIC supply.</p>



<p>So far, no country has been able to produce ASICs to the scale and speed that China has. It might also be in China’s best interest to relocate its operations to the United States.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It&#8217;s possible that some of the Chinese companies that produce this equipment will actually locate manufacturing capacity in the US so that they aren’t subject to the tariffs. But that involves relocating facilities and getting permits. It’s something that takes time, and it’s not going to happen tomorrow,” Pearl said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Given the hostility between the two countries, this seems unlikely. </p>



<p>Ultimately, domestic production offers the best path to US self-sufficiency. However, it will be a complex –and lengthy– process.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bringing-operations-onshore">Bringing Operations Onshore</h2>



<p>Under Biden, Congress approved the CHIPS and Science Act in July 2022. This legislation was designed to boost domestic semiconductor manufacturing in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though it doesn’t explicitly single out ASIC equipment, its provisions strongly encourage and incentivize the relocation and establishment of all types of semiconductor production within US borders, including those related to ASICs.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If the [Trump] administration doesn&#8217;t try to undo some of what was done under the CHIPS Act in terms of moving manufacturing capacity to the US, it&#8217;s possible that over the course of the next several years, US companies will develop ASICs that are competitive. But that&#8217;s a long-term project– it&#8217;s not an easy thing to develop those chips,” Pearl told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Two days ago, Hut 8, a major North American Bitcoin mining company, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hut-8-eric-trump-american-bitcoin-corp/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">partnered with Eric Trump to launch American Bitcoin</a>, aiming to turn it into the world&#8217;s largest pure-play miner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While this initiative aligns with President Trump&#8217;s goal of bringing production back to the US, Hut 8, like other American miners, relies on ASIC hardware. This creates a potential conflict with his tariff policies.</p>



<p>In the interim, US miners will have to grapple with the existing reliance on Chinese ASICs.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-us-miners-in-the-crosshairs">US Miners in the Crosshairs</h2>



<p>American companies will continue to bear the impact of Trump&#8217;s tariffs on crucial Chinese crypto mining hardware. This will last until the US can efficiently onshore broader manufacturing and production.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In the long run, we’ll see industry consolidation, a declining US share of global hashrate, and possibly domestic ASIC manufacturing efforts to reduce reliance on China. High tariffs will push miners toward used equipment, renewable energy, and hosting models. Without policy adjustments, the US could lose its competitive edge in Bitcoin mining,” Zhang concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If Trump’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-watch-trumps-liberation-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Liberation Day announcements</a> involve further tariffs on China, domestic mining companies, large or small, will see production costs rise significantly. Disturbances in tightly interrelated supply chain dynamics will also disrupt their operations. How they respond has yet to be determined.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-crypto-mining-trump-liberation-day-tariffs/">US Crypto Mining in Crisis? How Trump’s Liberation Day Tariffs Could Shake the Industry</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BIC_bitcoin_btc_mining_02.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/BIC_bitcoin_btc_mining_02.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>After the Meme Coin Fiasco, Can Donald Trump&#8217;s USD1 Stablecoin Restore Trust? </title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-usd1-stablecoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=681734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Following Trump's meme coin losses, experts believe USD1's success depends on transparency and utility to restore investor confidence.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-usd1-stablecoin/">After the Meme Coin Fiasco, Can Donald Trump&#8217;s USD1 Stablecoin Restore Trust? </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Trump made headlines again last week after World Liberty Financial announced the launch of USD1, its very own stablecoin. However, much anticipation surrounds just how successful the project will be. The launch of Trump’s meme coin at the beginning of the year resulted in billions of dollars in losses. Retail investors, in particular, have learned to be more cautious with Trump-backed endeavors.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>BeInCrypto spoke with nine industry experts to learn more about USD1 and what it needs to restore public confidence in investors disappointed by Trump’s previous crypto ventures. These representatives unanimously agreed that USD1&#8217;s success hinges on transparency, proper utility, and a distinct advantage over well-established competitors.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-usd1-s-promise-and-trump-s-crypto-history">USD1&#8217;s Promise and Trump&#8217;s Crypto History</h2>



<p>Last week, World Liberty Financial (WLF), a token project heavily affiliated with the Trump family, officially acknowledged that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/world-liberty-financial-launches-usd1-stablecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it had launched USD1, its very own stablecoin</a>. To a certain degree, the announcement was unsurprising.</p>



<p>During the Digital Assets Summit the White House held at the beginning of March, Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent said that the Trump administration would <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-speech-digital-asset-summit-stablecoins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">use stablecoins to preserve the US dollar’s role</a> as the world’s strongest reserve currency.</p>



<p>USD1 aims to do exactly this. The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/best-stablecoins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stablecoin</a> will be pegged to the US dollar and supported by a reserve comprised of short-term US Treasury securities, dollar deposits, and other highly liquid assets.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Trump is not simply issuing his stablecoin. He is legitimizing stablecoins in general to support the US dollar. If you go through his stablecoin legislation, it is essentially about increasing the dollarization by making the US dollar easier and safer to use and selling more dollars in the process. Every USD stablecoin in circulation means USD-denominated asset in a bank somewhere. Not in CNY or any other currency,” Tae Oh, Founder of Creditcoin, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>But Trump’s track record in crypto has been polluted by heavy losses for retail investors and reiterated <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">accusations of conflicts of interest</a>. While some welcome the idea of a sitting president backing the launch of a new stablecoin, others say that it sparks further cause for trouble.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-can-usd1-redeem-trump-s-crypto-reputation">Can USD1 Redeem Trump&#8217;s Crypto Reputation?</h2>



<p>The crypto market went berzerk when Trump launched his meme coin two days before assuming office. Within a day of trading, the token reached a market capitalization of over $14.5 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, since that moment, the meme coin has been in freefall, tainted by constant volatility and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/libra-meme-coin-linked-to-melania/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">evidence of insider trading</a>. According to Chainalysis, while early buyers were able to cash out $6.6 billion in profits, smaller traders have experienced collective losses of over $2 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1644" height="1200" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1.png" alt="TRUMP meme coin market capitalization since January launch." class="wp-image-681735" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1.png 1644w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1-360x263.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1-850x620.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1-768x561.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1-1536x1121.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/chart-2-1-150x109.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1644px) 100vw, 1644px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">TRUMP meme coin market capitalization since January launch. Source: <a href="https://www.coingecko.com/en/coins/official-trump" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CoinGecko</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Meanwhile, the Trump family has made nearly $100 million from trading fees alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>WLF, the President’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/decentralized-finance-and-use-cases/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decentralized finance (DeFi)</a> experiment, largely failed to restore confidence in Trump-backed crypto projects. Reports quickly unveiled that the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-binance-stake-crypto-decentralized-ethos/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump family holds a 75% stake in the platform’s net revenue</a> and a 60% stake in the holding company.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Applying these percentages to WLF’s most recent token sale, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-wlfi-revenue-75-corruption-possibility/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump would have earned $400 million in revenue</a>.</p>



<p>Now, WLF has launched USD1. Unlike meme coins, stablecoins offer investors a much higher degree of stability. Some industry leaders believe this could be Trump’s opportunity to redeem himself, while others remain doubtful. S, the pseudonymous community lead behind NEIRO, summarized it cleanly:</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If USD1 is structured well and managed transparently, it could help regain confidence, especially among newer users. But it won’t erase the impact of previous rug pulls and hype-driven projects. That healing process takes time and accountability,” he said, adding that “Authentic community engagement is now essential—it’s not enough to slap a famous name on a token.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>At the same time, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/elizabeth-warren-scrutiny-trump-meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the meme coin&#8217;s turbulent journey</a> revealed Trump&#8217;s capacity to introduce newcomers to crypto, a lesson potentially applicable to USD1&#8217;s launch</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trump-s-meme-coin-impact-on-new-investors">Trump&#8217;s Meme Coin Impact on New Investors</h2>



<p>TRUMP’s initial $14.5 billion market capitalization set the highest benchmark achieved by a meme coin backed by a public figure. Aside from that, according to a survey by NFTvening, 42% of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-trump-coin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">TRUMP meme coin</a> buyers were first-time crypto investors.</p>



<p>In other words, Trump’s meme coin project did wonders in exposing outsider investors to the cryptocurrency market. According to Oh, the same can be done with USD1– at least initially.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The association with Trump is the strongest branding you can get in the current market. However, at the end of Trump’s term, the project needs to become disassociated from the President and more politically neutral,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Oh also added that Trump’s frequent project launches have demonstrated similarities. Though they haven’t necessarily filled a gap in the market, they have managed to onboard new users.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think Trump is showing us a pattern. He is legitimizing various types of cryptocurrency by issuing them himself or through his affiliate organizations. He started with memecoin and now on fiat-backed stablecoin. Is adoption the main objective of the projects? We shall see,” Oh said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>For Anthony Anzalone, CEO of XION, a Trump-backed stablecoin could create pathways for sustainable adoption compared to any meme coin.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In the specific context of a stablecoin, Trump&#8217;s association likely provides advantages rather than disadvantages. Unlike speculative tokens, where celebrity involvement often signals short-term marketing over substance, stablecoins derive their value from stability, regulatory compliance, and institutional adoption &#8211; areas where political connections potentially confer meaningful benefits. The technical requirements and operational challenges of stablecoins are significantly different from speculative tokens, making this a more suitable venture for political backing,” Anzalone told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, market adoption won’t exclusively hinge on presidential backing.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-will-trump-s-name-help-or-hurt-usd1-adoption">Will Trump&#8217;s Name Help or Hurt USD1 Adoption?</h2>



<p>While a Trump-endorsed stablecoin could greatly increase USD1 adoption, it could also have the opposite effect.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Trump&#8217;s polarizing presence could create skepticism, especially among those wary of political influence in financial products. While his involvement might appeal to his supporters, it risks alienating a broad portion of the market,” said Cathy Yoon, General Counsel at the Wormhole Foundation.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This risk is especially true when applied to users who believe that Trump has entered the crypto space exclusively for profit.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Trump’s main motivation is making money from this venture, so his involvement is certainly more likely to be a downside than an advantage. You know he’ll try everything to suck as much profit out of this venture as possible, and it could be at the expense of the end user,” Jean Rausis, Co-founder of SMARDEX, told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The fact that WLF, a Trump-backed project associated with several conflicts of interest, launched USD1 does little to assuage skeptics about future risks.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-conflicts-of-interest-and-usd1-transparency">Conflicts of Interest and USD1 Transparency</h2>



<p>Trump failed to prevent similar accusations of conflicts of interest by directly associating himself with the USD1 launch through WLF.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“A conflict of interest arises when the current US President is also a key figure in World Liberty Financial. He will be <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-involvement-usd1-stablecoin-draws-scrutiny/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">closely monitored and face regulatory hurdles</a> to ensure there is no manipulation of the financial system, but this alone could deter investors when there are highly competitive and much more mature products in that market,” Vivien Lin, Chief Product Officer at BingX, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Suppose Trump wants to distance himself from the criticism his previous projects received. In that case, he will have to ensure that USD1 adheres to transparency mechanisms and regular audits—not only for public trust but also to ensure that the sitting President doesn’t break the law.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Transparency should be at the forefront of all communications, especially with Trump&#8217;s involvement as the US President and stakeholder in World Liberty Financial. This situation could violate the Constitution&#8217;s emoluments clause, which broadly refers to any advantage, profit, or gain received due to holding office. If violated, this could significantly hurt the public&#8217;s trust. Another aspect that should be considered is establishing safeguards against potential market manipulation, especially given WLFI&#8217;s history of large crypto purchases before important events to prevent market manipulation,” Lin added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>USD1’s success will also largely depend on its execution.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-usd1-s-path-in-a-competitive-market">USD1&#8217;s Path in a Competitive Market</h2>



<p>Stablecoins have existed since 2014 and are finding a permanent home in the broader market. According to the World Economic Forum, the current supply of stablecoins in circulation exceeds $208 billion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1210" height="1074" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM.png" alt="Average supply of stablecoins in circulation." class="wp-image-681736" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM.png 1210w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM-360x320.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM-850x754.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM-768x682.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-31-at-5.12.37 PM-150x133.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1210px) 100vw, 1210px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Average supply of stablecoins in circulation. Source: <a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2025/03/stablecoins-cryptocurrency-on-rise-financial-systems/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">World Economic Forum</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>With a market capitalization approaching $144 billion, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/how-to-buy-and-store-the-different-types-of-tether/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tether (USDT)</a> is today&#8217;s most dominant stablecoin. In second place comes Circle’s USDC, with a market capitalization of over $60 billion. Driven by their dollar peg and perceived inflation hedge, stablecoins have become highly popular, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fidelity-plans-to-launch-a-stablecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">prompting increased stablecoin launches</a> from banks and tech firms.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The more we see responsible innovation that includes utility use cases– such as prudentially regulated stablecoins for global payment processing &#8211; the more crypto’s reputation will solidify and credibility will grow. I don’t think we need to rely or wait for one product such as USD1. The momentum has been building and will continue,” Beth Haddock, Global Policy Lead at Stablecoin Standard, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>USD1 must set itself apart to succeed in an already cutthroat market.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If USD1 lacks interoperability, has limited on/off-ramps, or fails to differentiate from incumbents like USDC or USDT, it risks being relegated to a niche use case. Ultimately, mainstream success will come down to execution, partnerships, and solving real user pain points—especially in markets where traditional financial access is limited or inefficient,” said Mouloukou Sanoh, CEO of MANSA.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>According to Martins Benkitis, CEO of Gravity Team, catering to niche markets isn’t a bad idea. But in an already competitive field, it might not be enough.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If it becomes a gateway for on-chain political donations or movement-aligned payments, it’s filling a niche. The question is whether that niche is big enough to sustain a stablecoin. Jury’s still out, but it’s an angle,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Inevitably, providing some utility that is not currently available will factor into USD1’s eventual success.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-utility-will-usd1-offer">What Utility Will USD1 Offer?</h2>



<p>What USD1 can offer the market boils down to what Trump has in store. Several details regarding its launch have yet to be released.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nonetheless, if executed properly, the stablecoin has the potential to offer a degree of stability and predictability that TRUMP’s meme coin was unable to deliver. It could also give the President the golden opportunity to restore the trust that he lost from his previous crypto ventures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If this is among Trump’s matters of concern for USD1, he will have to prioritize factors like transparency, security, and clear utility. These will be the aspects the public will be looking out for.</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-usd1-stablecoin/">After the Meme Coin Fiasco, Can Donald Trump&#8217;s USD1 Stablecoin Restore Trust? </a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/bic_US_Presidential_Candidates_Trump-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/bic_US_Presidential_Candidates_Trump-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trump and Binance: A Deal That Could Undermine Crypto’s Decentralized Ethos?</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/trump-binance-stake-crypto-decentralized-ethos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=680538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Recent Trump ventures, including a potential Binance stake and the USD1 stablecoin launch, have sparked industry debate over centralization.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-binance-stake-crypto-decentralized-ethos/">Trump and Binance: A Deal That Could Undermine Crypto’s Decentralized Ethos?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The Trump family has made headlines lately over potential ventures with Binance and the BNB Chain. Rumors started circulating that the Trump Organization is considering buying a stake in Binance’s US arm, while Trump recently launched his USD1 stablecoin on BNB Chain. This nature of the President’s involvement has raised concerns over decentralization.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>BeInCrypto spoke with representatives from Galxe, Komodo Platform, Kronos Research, Yellow Network, and Solv Protocol to gather further insights on what Trump’s involvement could mean for the centralized exchange and the decentralized blockchain.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-initial-reactions-to-trump-s-binance-ventures">Initial Reactions to Trump&#8217;s Binance Ventures</h2>



<p>A series of events in the last month seem to have brought US President Donald Trump and Binance founder <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/changpeng-zhao-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Changpeng “CZ” Zhao</a> closer together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just two weeks ago, reports circulated that the Trump family may be negotiating <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-family-to-invest-in-binance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to acquire a stake in the US arm</a> of the world’s largest crypto exchange. Then, on Tuesday, World Liberty Financial officially <a href="https://beincrypto.com/world-liberty-financial-launches-usd1-stablecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">launched its very own stablecoin, known as USD1</a>.</p>



<p>Though Binance’s actual involvement in the launch remains unclear, USD1 is native to the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-smart-chain-bsc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BNB Chain</a>. Though BNB is decentralized, community members raised concerns that a stake in Binance could indirectly influence the blockchain’s greater ecosystem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result, a vital question has erupted: Are these latest ventures good for market adoption and crypto’s reputation, or do they go against crypto’s decentralized and community-driven ethos?</p>



<p>Industry experts proved to be divided in their responses.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-does-trump-involvement-signal-market-growth">Does Trump Involvement Signal Market Growth?</h2>



<p>Trump has completely changed the political landscape in the United States, creating a more favorable environment for cryptocurrency adoption. Given his endeavors in the industry, Trump’s approach has been particularly novel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Announcements like the creation of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sui-partners-with-world-liberty-financial/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">World Liberty Financial</a> and the launch of his meme coin were initially celebrated by the community for the increased visibility they gave to the crypto industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, with rumors of a potential stake acquisition in Binance and the launch of USD1 on the BNB Chain, some expect similar results. They argue that The Trump family&#8217;s involvement could bring significant traffic to Binance and, consequently, to the BNB Chain.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;A Trump stake in Binance could actually be bullish for BNB Chain, as it may drive‬‭ greater attention, adoption, or even institutional involvement. There have been multiple moves related to Trump and the crypto space. Personally, I see them‬‭ all as contributing to the industry&#8217;s development—at least for now. Whether driven by political motives or‬ not, these moves are undeniably giving crypto more visibility and mainstream recognition,‬&#8221; said Ryan Chow, CEO and Co-founder of Solv Protocol.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Alexis Sirkia, Chairman of Yellow Network, delivered a similar verdict.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭A‬‭ Trump‬‭ stake‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ bullish,‬‭ not‬‭ bearish.‬‭ It‬‭ would‬‭ draw‬‭ attention,‬‭ capital,‬‭ and‬‭ momentum. The community would more strongly rally behind it than back away,” Sirkia told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, others received the news with much more skepticism.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-concerns-over-centralized-power">Concerns Over Centralized Power</h2>



<p>When rumors surfaced that the Trump family had held talks to buy a stake in Binance, some criticized the move <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">over potential conflicts of interest</a>. Reports also suggested that these negotiations resembled a plot by CZ to get Trump to pardon him following his guilty plea for money laundering charges in 2023.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also cautioned that a stake could give Trump centralized power to a broader industry working to build a decentralized financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭Blockchain‬‭ was‬‭ created‬‭ as‬‭ an‬‭ answer‬‭ to‬‭ the‬‭ shortcomings‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ traditional‬‭ financial‬‭ system,‬ ‭with‬‭ the‬‭ idea‬‭ that‬‭ no‬‭ one‬‭ entity‬‭ should‬‭ have‬‭ full‬‭ control‬‭ over‬‭ it,‬‭ let‬‭ alone‬‭ an‬‭ individual.‬‭ The‬  idea‬‭ of‬‭ an‬‭ influential‬‭ political‬‭ figure‬‭ like‬‭ Trump‬‭ having‬‭ an‬‭ influence‬‭ over‬‭ one‬‭ of‬‭ crypto’s‬ ‭stalwarts challenges the whole ethos of Web3,” Charles‬‭ Wayn, Co-founder of Galxe, told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>A move like this, Wayn added, could have significant long-term implications on Binance and BNB Chain.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If‬‭ Trump‬‭ does‬‭ take‬‭ a‬‭ stake‬‭ in‬‭ Binance.US,‬‭ this‬‭ would‬‭ certainly‬‭ polarize‬‭ the‬‭ community‬‭ and‬‭ lead‬‭ to‬‭ the‬‭ erosion‬‭ of‬‭ trust,‬‭ especially‬‭ from‬‭ the‬‭ more‬‭ ideological‬‭ users.‬‭ They‬‭ would‬‭ likely‬‭ start‬‭ questioning‬‭ the‬‭ integrity‬‭ of‬‭ Binance‬‭ and‬‭ how‬‭ aligned‬‭ –or‬‭ not‬–‬‭ it‬‭ is‬‭ with‬‭ web3‬‭ values.‬‭ This‬‭ will‬‭ inevitably‬‭ have‬‭ an‬‭ impact‬‭ on‬‭ their‬‭ perception‬‭ of‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain‬‭ and‬‭ could‬‭ potentially‬‭ push developers and users to explore alternatives,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, the way in which Trump could potentially exert power over these entities looks different in each case.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-vs-bnb-chain-what-s-the-difference">Binance vs BNB Chain: What&#8217;s The Difference?</h2>



<p>While Binance is a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/irs-to-track-crypto-transactions-on-cexs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">centralized exchange</a>, BNB Chain is a decentralized blockchain ecosystem. Though Binance initially played a central role in creating the BNB Chain, the ecosystem rebranded itself in 2022, evolving toward a more decentralized and community-driven effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Considering their separate natures, Trump&#8217;s potential position holds different meanings for Binance and BNB Chain.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It’s important to recognize that Binance is, by nature, a centralized entity. If Trump were to acquire a‬‭ stake in Binance, the key difference, in my view, would be that Binance could shift from being purely‬‭ profit-driven to being influenced -at least in part- by political factors,” Chow explained.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, BNB is a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/blockchain-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blockchain</a>. Manipulating the technology itself is practically impossible.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“BNB Chain’s decentralization is determined by its validators, not endorsements or political affiliations. A Trump stake wouldn’t inherently compromise its structure,” explained Kronos Research analyst Dominick John.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Instead, the BNB Chain could be influenced by other factors, like governance decisions.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-impact-of-politics-on-governance">The Impact of Politics on Governance</h2>



<p>Despite the technical distinction between Binance and BNB Chain, the potential for political influence raises questions about the platform&#8217;s independence.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‭Governance decisions might be seen as influenced by political interests, eroding confidence in the platform’s neutrality. Additionally, increased regulatory scrutiny could lead to compliance measures that restrict certain activities, weakening the chain’s appeal to privacy-conscious users. With a majority power potentially coming from the political realm, the true decentralization of BNB Chain would be questioned, as the community might fear that decisions are driven by centralized, external forces rather than the collective will of the network,” John added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>At this point, the lines between Binance and BNB Chain become blurred. Despite their technically separate entities, BNB is, after all, a product born out of Binance.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬The‬‭ question‬‭ is‬‭ more,‬‭ how‬‭ decentralized‬‭ is‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain‬‭ right‬‭ now?‬‭ Binance‬‭ has‬‭ been‬‭ criticized‬‭ for‬‭ having‬‭ a‬‭ great‬‭ deal‬‭ of‬‭ influence‬‭ over‬‭ the‬‭ choice‬‭ of‬‭ validators‬‭ on‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain,‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ blockchain’s‬‭ decentralization‬‭ is‬‭ often‬‭ brought‬‭ into‬‭ question‬‭,” Wayn said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Though direct control of the decentralized BNB Chain is unlikely, a stake in Binance could indirectly influence the BNB Chain ecosystem.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-high-are-the-stakes">How High Are the Stakes?</h2>



<p>The existence and size of a potential Trump family Binance stake remains uncertain. From what Sirkia has heard, Trump is looking at a 5% stake or lower.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If that turns out to be true, Sirkia doesn&#8217;t think Trump’s participation is something to worry about so long as the President prioritizes transparency.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬We‬‭ are‬‭ talking‬‭ about‬‭ a‬‭ minority‬‭ stake‬‭ in‬‭ Binance‬‭ US.‬‭ It‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ small‬‭,‬‭ distinct‬‭ offshoot‬‭ of‬‭ Binance‬‭ that‬‭ has‬‭ no‬‭ vote‬‭ on‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain.‬‭ Everybody‬‭ should‬‭ be‬‭ allowed‬‭ to‬‭ invest.‬‭ But‬‭ if‬‭ you&#8217;re‬‭ a‬‭ politico‬‭,‬‭ then‬‭ a‬‭ Blind‬‭ Trust‬‭ or‬‭ public‬‭ disclosure‬‭ is‬‭ the‬‭ answer‬‭.‬‭ Transparency‬‭ is‬‭ key‬‭,” Sirkia told BeInCrypto. </p>
</blockquote>



<p>Chow agreed.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬I see this similarly to a political figure holding stakes in any enterprise. This is not uncommon, and with‬‭ proper disclosure –especially given the level of scrutiny surrounding Trump– I personally don’t find it‬‭ inherently problematic. In an extreme scenario where a blockchain is explicitly branded as a ‘Trump‬‭ Chain’ or an ‘American Chain,’ does it really matter? I don’t think so. The market will decide its‬‭ relevance,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Wayn, on the other hand, argues that the size of the stake is irrelevant.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬Even‬‭ if‬‭ this‬‭ stake‬‭ is‬‭ small,‬‭ politicians‬‭ have‬‭ the‬‭ ability‬‭ to‬‭ wield‬‭ outsized‬‭ control,‬‭ and‬‭ this‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ unlikely‬‭ to‬‭ go‬‭ down‬‭ well‬‭ with‬‭ the‬‭ BNB‬‭ community.‬‭ Even‬‭ though‬‭ Binance‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ centralized‬‭ crypto‬‭ entity,‬‭ outright‬‭ political‬‭ involvement‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ a‬‭ step‬‭ too‬‭ far‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ community‬‭ would‬‭ almost certainly push back,” Wayn said, adding that “while‬‭ Trump’s‬‭ influence‬‭ may‬‭ not‬‭ make‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain‬‭ more‬‭ centralized,‬‭ he‬‭ could‬‭ certainly‬‭ wield‬‭ control‬‭ over‬‭ key‬‭ decisions.‬‭ More‬‭ importantly,‬‭ the‬‭ perception‬‭ will‬‭ be‬‭ that‬‭ BNB‬‭ is‬‭ falling‬‭ under‬‭ the‬‭ US‬‭ government’s influence, and perceptions are often what drives user behavior.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, other considerations also arise.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-regulatory-scrutiny-likely-to-increase">Regulatory Scrutiny Likely To Increase</h2>



<p>When <a href="https://beincrypto.com/will-trump-meme-coin-rally-on-liberation-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump launched his meme coin</a>, the move drew significant scrutiny from regulators, especially as speculation over insider trading started to surface. The same happened when the Trump Organization <a href="https://beincrypto.com/democrats-ethics-probe-trump-crypto/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">disclosed that it had a 75% stake</a> in World Liberty Financial’s net revenue.</p>



<p>Trump’s stablecoin announcement and potential Binance stake acquisition will likely have the same effect.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The involvement of a sitting US president within a crypto exchange could attract heightened regulatory scrutiny, as concerns over political influence may affect market dynamics. This could lead to regulations that stifle innovation, create barriers for smaller players, and ultimately harm the growth and inclusivity of the crypto industry,” John said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, John added that he considered this result unlikely. Sirkia agreed, arguing that Trump’s participation would boost regulatory clarity.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭If‬‭ true,‬‭ this‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ a‬‭ huge‬‭ plus.‬‭ It‬‭ would‬‭ send‬‭ a‬‭ message‬‭ that‬‭ crypto‬‭ is‬‭ not‬‭ on‬‭ the‬‭ fringes‬‭ but‬‭ part‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ future‬‭ financial‬‭ landscape‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ US‬‭ Regulatory‬‭ clarity‬‭ could‬‭ actually speed up under a pro-crypto approach,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, the news has already polarized the broader political arena. The Senate Banking, Housing, &amp; Urban Affairs Committee Minority under Senator Elizabeth Warren has already <a href="https://x.com/SenateBanking/status/1900220011697856777" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">spoken</a> against Trump’s ties with Binance.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Bloomberg just broke news that the Trump family’s crypto company has been in discussions with Binance on doing business, including possibly creating a new stablecoin.<br><br>We have a chance to fix this stablecoin bill to prevent this kind of naked corruption. <a href="https://t.co/NdQH4RHnl3">pic.twitter.com/NdQH4RHnl3</a></p>&mdash; Senate Banking and Housing Democrats (@SenateBanking) <a href="https://twitter.com/SenateBanking/status/1900220011697856777?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Similarly, users who strongly adhere to blockchain’s core principles of decentralization and privacy may feel more inclined to migrate elsewhere.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-potential-for-user-migration-toward-dexs">Potential for User Migration Toward DEXs</h2>



<p>Wayn believes a Trump stake in Binance could urge users to transition from centralized exchanges to decentralized alternatives.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‭There‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ real‬‭ possibility‬‭ that‬‭ users‬‭ and‬‭ developers‬‭ might‬‭ flee‬‭ for‬‭ decentralized‬‭ alternatives‬‭ if‬‭ they‬‭ perceive‬‭ BNB‬‭ Chain‬‭ to‬‭ be‬‭ falling‬‭ under‬‭ political‬‭ influence.‬‭ But‬‭ that’s‬‭ not‬‭ necessarily‬‭ bad‬‭ news‬‭ for‬‭ the‬‭ industry‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ whole‬‭– ‬‭ it‬‭ could‬‭ push‬‭ users‬‭ to‬‭ explore‬‭ alternative‬‭ blockchains‬‭ and‬‭ decentralized‬‭ exchanges.‬‭ It‬‭ would‬‭ also‬‭ be‬‭ an‬‭ opportunity‬‭ to‬‭ highlight‬‭ the‬‭ advantages‬‭ of‬‭ decentralized‬‭ technologies‬‭ more‬‭ broadly,‬‭ which‬‭ are,‬‭ by‬‭ default,‬‭ unbiased‬‭ as‬‭ they‬‭ operate‬‭ off‬‭ of code and not beliefs,” he said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Kadan Stadelmann, Chief Technology Officer at Komodo Platform, doesn’t necessarily think a mass migration will occur. He does think, however, that these announcements will further reinforce crypto aficionados’ beliefs on privacy.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Those‬‭ who‬‭ use‬‭ crypto‬‭ for‬‭ its‬‭ privacy‬‭ potential‬‭ have‬‭ long‬‭ been‬‭ suspicious‬‭ of‬‭ centralization‬‭ in‬‭ any‬‭ chain,‬‭ and‬‭ gravitate‬‭ towards‬‭ those‬‭ projects‬‭ which‬‭ offer‬‭ privacy.‬‭ Trump’ s‬‭ stake‬‭ in‬‭ Binance‬‭ won’t‬‭ surprise‬‭ them,‬‭ though‬‭ it‬‭ might‬‭ make‬‭ them‬‭ more‬‭ hardcore‬‭ in‬‭ their‬‭ preferences‬‭ for‬‭ truly‬‭ decentralized systems,” Stadelmann told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, those in crypto exclusively for profit reasons will remain indifferent to any potential Trump-related conflicts of interest.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-financial-gains-over-decentralized-ideals">Financial Gains Over Decentralized Ideals</h2>



<p>For crypto users primarily motivated by profit, the nuances of data control and decentralization are often secondary concerns.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Much‬‭ of‬‭ the‬‭ public‬‭ globally‬‭ is‬‭ in‬‭ the‬‭ dark‬‭ about‬‭ what‬‭ companies‬‭ do‬‭ with‬‭ their‬‭ data‬‭ and‬‭ they‬‭ don’t‬‭ feel‬‭ as‬‭ though‬‭ they‬‭ have‬‭ any‬‭ say‬‭ in‬‭ how‬‭ the‬‭ companies‬‭ handle‬‭ their‬‭ data.‬‭ The‬‭ resignation‬‭ suggests‬‭ crypto‬‭ users‬‭ interested‬‭ in‬‭ the‬‭ technology‬‭ for‬‭ its‬‭ money-making‬‭ potential‬‭ won’t‬‭ protest‬‭ Trump’s‬‭ stake‬‭ in‬‭ Binance,‬‭ and‬‭ the‬‭ platform‬‭ will‬‭ continue‬‭ to‬‭ grow—especially‬‭ with‬‭ financial‬‭ backing from the monied-classes of which Trump is a part,” Stadelmann concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Regardless of the outcome, the ongoing debate surrounding Trump&#8217;s potential influence illustrates the inherent tension between pursuing mainstream adoption and preserving crypto&#8217;s decentralized ethos.</p>



<p>This tension will likely drive the industry&#8217;s evolution. The side that pulls the hardest will shape the final result.</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-binance-stake-crypto-decentralized-ethos/">Trump and Binance: A Deal That Could Undermine Crypto’s Decentralized Ethos?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_4.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_4.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why GameStop’s Bitcoin Announcement Left BTC Unmoved? Experts Discuss</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/why-gamestop-bitcoin-announcement-left-btc-unmoved/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=680009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>GameStop’s Bitcoin treasury news boosted its stock, but BTC's overall price stayed unchanged due to GameStop’s lack of scale.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/why-gamestop-bitcoin-announcement-left-btc-unmoved/">Why GameStop’s Bitcoin Announcement Left BTC Unmoved? Experts Discuss</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>GameStop’s announcement that it would invest in Bitcoin drove excitement across the crypto community. Within hours, the video game and electronics retailer experienced a significant hike in stock prices. However, Bitcoin’s price remained the same. </strong></p>



<p>In a conversation with BeInCrypto, representatives from Quantum Economics and CryptoQuant explained that Bitcoin’s price was bound to be indifferent to this type of announcement. GameStop lacks the size and scale to meaningfully impact the asset’s trading value, while overall hawkish market sentiment limited significant price movements. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-understanding-gamestop-s-bitcoin-move"><strong>Understanding GameStop&#8217;s Bitcoin Move</strong></h2>



<p>On March 26, GameStop announced an update to its investment policy, revealing that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-to-buy-bitcoin-after-earnings-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it had added Bitcoin as a Treasury Reserve Asset</a>. Mirroring MicroStrategy’s Bitcoin plan, GameStop gambled on crypto exposure to strengthen its financial position in 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“GameStop adding Bitcoin to their balance sheet is a huge win for corporate adoption of the world’s leading cryptocurrency,” Mati Greenspan, Founder and CEO of Quantum Economics, told BeInCrypto in response.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The company’s <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-bitcoin-purchase-stock-surges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stock prices jumped as high as 12%</a> in a matter of hours before seeing corrections. Community members reacted favorably, including high-profile figures like Scottie Pippen, six-time NBA champion.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">U.S. Reserve. BlackRock ETFs. GameStop Treasury. Strategy’s Billions. Fidelity Inflows. Presidential Push. 16 Years Unstoppable.<br><br>BITCOIN. That&#39;s it. That&#39;s the tweet.</p>&mdash; Scottie Pippen (@ScottiePippen) <a href="https://twitter.com/ScottiePippen/status/1904882597101969525?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 26, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>As Pippen’s tweet suggests, GameStop’s announcement parallels recent efforts by different institutional players to acquire Bitcoin holdings. However, unlike previous cases, the company’s initiative did not impact Bitcoin’s price performance.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-market-indifference-explained"><strong>Market Indifference Explained</strong></h2>



<p>A day before GameStop’s announcement, the price of Bitcoin peaked at $88,474. Yesterday, it fell to a high of $88,199. At the time of press, Bitcoin’s price rests at $86,691. In other words, Bitcoin’s trading value has remained unphased by GameStop’s acquisition.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2208" height="852" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM.png" alt="Bitcoin's price performance over the past week." class="wp-image-680011" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM.png 2208w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-360x139.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-850x328.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-768x296.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-1536x593.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-2048x790.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-26-at-6.57.09 PM-150x58.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2208px) 100vw, 2208px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin&#8217;s price performance over the past week. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/">BeInCrypto</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>On previous occasions, these announcements have pushed BTC’s price by significant percentage points, unleashing a wave of bullish sentiment in trading activity. </p>



<p>When Tesla, for example, announced in February 2021 that<a href="https://beincrypto.com/tesla-holds-over-1-billion-in-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> it had bought $1.5 billion worth of Bitcoin</a>, the move briefly pushed up the cryptocurrency&#8217;s price by as much as 20%.</p>



<p>Other <a href="https://beincrypto.com/saylor-microstrategy-one-billion-bitcoin-purchase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">major players like Strategy</a> (formerly MicroStrategy) and BlackRock and nation-states like El Salvador and Bhutan have also acquired massive amounts of Bitcoin. But in yesterday’s announcement, GameStop failed to mention how much BTC it was eyeing.</p>



<p>The firm did mention that it would be issuing $1.3 billion in 0% convertible senior notes to finance this acquisition. Yet, compared to the broader trend of publicly listed firms buying Bitcoin, this figure is rather underwhelming. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The announcement lacked key details —most importantly, how much Bitcoin they’re actually buying. While they’re sitting on about $4.8 billion in cash, we’ve seen no indication of what portion, if any, will be allocated to BTC,” Greenspan told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>As a result, the market was left guessing. Without a clear figure, investors had no reason to react strongly. Instead, the statement served as a message of intent rather than a concrete market-moving event.</p>



<p>But even if GameStop had clarified just how much Bitcoin it was willing to buy, it still wouldn’t have made much of a difference in Bitcoin’s price. This is because of the underlying macroeconomic factors that have kept BTC below $90,000 for nearly a month now.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-why-didn-t-gamestop-s-announcement-move-bitcoin-s-price"><strong>Why Didn’t GameStop&#8217;s Announcement Move Bitcoin&#8217;s Price?</strong></h2>



<p>According to its most recent quarterly report, GameStop has a nearly $4.8 billion cash balance. Per yesterday’s announcement, the company plans to raise $1.3 billion through a private offering of convertible senior notes.</p>



<p>It clarified, however, that the net proceeds from this offering will be used for &#8220;general corporate purposes,&#8221; which may include the acquisition of Bitcoin. </p>



<p>However, this remains to be seen. This vagueness creates a situation with much speculation but no concrete information.</p>



<p>For Greenspan, even if GameStop used its entire cash balance to purchase Bitcoin, BTC’s overall price would remain unchanged.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“To put things in perspective, Bitcoin’s on-chain volume alone averages around $14 billion per day — and that’s not even counting exchanges or ETFs. So even if GameStop went all-in, it still wouldn’t make a dent,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, the announcement must also be considered in light of the larger sentiment surrounding the crypto market at the moment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-bearish-moment-for-bitcoin"><strong>A Bearish Moment for Bitcoin</strong></h2>



<p>Market sentiment has been particularly cautious lately. Between Trump’s tariff announcements and rumors about a possible recession, Bitcoin’s price has remained stagnant.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Overall market sentiment remains the least bullish since January 2023 as measured by CryptoQuant’s Bitcoin Bull Score Index. The index goes from 0 (least bullish) to 100 (most bullish), and it has been at 20 since late February,” Julio Moreno, Head of Research at CryptoQuant, told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1322" height="732" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM.png" alt="Bitcoin Bull Score Index." class="wp-image-680477" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM.png 1322w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM-360x199.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM-850x471.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM-768x425.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.05.55 PM-150x83.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1322px) 100vw, 1322px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin Bull Score Index: Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CryptoQuant</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>While major event announcements have driven Bitcoin prices up in the past, the wider market has been focused on other factors affecting trading behaviors.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Bitcoin spot demand growth remains in contraction territory, declining by 297K Bitcoin in the last 30 days, the largest contraction for such a period since December 2023. The market is more focused on the macro developments, given expectations of a slowing down economy and the uncertainty regarding Trump’s Administration tariffs and trade policy,” Moreno added.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1280" height="766" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM.png" alt="Bitcoin spot demand growth." class="wp-image-680479" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM.png 1280w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM-360x215.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM-850x509.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM-768x460.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-27-at-3.06.04 PM-150x90.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1280px) 100vw, 1280px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin spot demand growth. Source: <a href="https://cryptoquant.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">CryptoQuant</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Given the greater pessimism dampening overall market sentiment, announcements of corporate purchases are unable to garner enough force to impact Bitcoin prices positively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, given how far institutional adoption of crypto has come, corporate announcements don’t have the same impact as they used to.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-has-corporate-adoption-become-old-news"><strong>Has Corporate Adoption Become Old News?</strong></h2>



<p>There’s a case to be made that the general public has become desensitized to corporate Bitcoin treasury announcements. According to<a href="https://treasuries.bitbo.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> data</a> from Bitcoin Treasuries, private companies worldwide hold 381,560 BTC worth over $33.2 billion, twice as large as public companies.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“More pertinently, institutional adoption is so last cycle,” Greenspan said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Many more recent announcements that extend beyond the scope of BTC holdings in private companies have rocked the market, causing prices to surge.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The market went berserk when spot <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-bitcoin-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin ETFs</a> began trading in January last year. For the first time, Bitcoin became available to a much wider pool of institutional investors who were previously hesitant to invest directly in the cryptocurrency. </p>



<p>This event led to a significant influx of capital into the Bitcoin market, driving up demand and prices.</p>



<p>Almost a year later, when Trump, a presidential candidate who <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-pro-crypto-election-victory/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">promised to make the United States a cryptocurrency pioneer</a>, won the elections, Bitcoin prices reached new highs. </p>



<p>Other, more recent events, like Trump’s announcement of a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-strategic-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">national strategic crypto reserve</a>, had similar impacts on the market. </p>



<p>According to Greenspan, events like this last one will create future spikes in BTC’s price. For him, the new adoption cycle will focus on Bitcoin acquisition by entire nations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-national-btc-reserves-set-to-be-newest-market-driver"><strong>National BTC Reserves Set to be Newest Market Driver</strong></h2>



<p>While countries like the United States, China, and Ukraine currently hold stockpiles of Bitcoin mainly seized from law enforcement activities, more countries are deliberately purchasing additional Bitcoin for strategic purposes.</p>



<p>El Salvador, for example, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/el-salvador-imf-criticism-bitcoin-purchase/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has gradually increased purchases of Bitcoin</a>. Today, it holds a little over 6,000 in holdings. Meanwhile, Bhutan’s Bitcoin stockpile <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bhutan-bitcoin-reserves-1-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has already surpassed the $1 billion mark</a>.</p>



<p>Other jurisdictions, such as Brazil, Poland, Hong Kong, and Japan, have also <a href="https://beincrypto.com/japan-to-follow-us-lead-on-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">had lawmakers consider adding Bitcoin</a> to their fiscal reserves.</p>



<p>For Greenspan, these announcements will generate real change in BTC’s future trading activity.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“This bull run is mainly about nation-state adoption. Let’s face it: as fun and nostalgic as GameStop is, it simply can’t compete with the scale and significance of entire countries stepping into the Bitcoin arena,” he said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the grand scheme of Bitcoin&#8217;s market, GameStop&#8217;s announcement, though notable, pales in comparison to the potential impact of large-scale events such as national policy changes or major economic shifts.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/why-gamestop-bitcoin-announcement-left-btc-unmoved/">Why GameStop’s Bitcoin Announcement Left BTC Unmoved? Experts Discuss</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_Bitcoin_BEP2_BTCB_1-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/11/bic_Bitcoin_BEP2_BTCB_1-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ex-CFTC Chair Warns of Corruption Risks in Trump-Linked Crypto Projects</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=678926</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In an exclusive interview with BeInCrypto, former US CFTC Commissioner Timothy Massad explains how President Trump&#8217;s crypto ventures and political power have significantly overlapped in his first two months at the White House. Shortly before assuming office for the second time, US President Donald Trump dove head-first into a flurry of crypto experiments. From endorsing &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/">Ex-CFTC Chair Warns of Corruption Risks in Trump-Linked Crypto Projects</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In an exclusive interview with BeInCrypto, former US CFTC Commissioner Timothy Massad explains how President Trump&#8217;s crypto ventures and political power have significantly overlapped in his first two months at the White House. </strong></p>



<p>Shortly before assuming office for the second time, US President Donald Trump dove head-first into a flurry of crypto experiments. From endorsing World Liberty Financial (WLFI) to launching his meme coin, Trump is raising serious concerns over conflicts of interest. Tim Massad, the 12th CFTC Chairman, who served under Barack Obama, shares his thoughts.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-historic-president-for-many-reasons"><strong>A Historic President For Many Reasons</strong></h2>



<p>Before assuming his first term in office in 2016, President Trump broke with modern precedent by departing from established conflict-of-interest norms. A real estate mogul with a trademark for a last name, Trump would be entering the Oval Office as the leader of a multi-billion dollar empire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While former presidents like Jimmy Carter and George W. Bush took measures to separate themselves from their businesses by placing their assets in a blind trust, the sitting President took a different approach. </p>



<p>Instead, Trump handed day-to-day management decisions over to his sons but did not divest in his ownership stake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Though he received much backlash during his first term over conflict of interest concerns, Trump refused to relinquish ownership of the Trump Organization before assuming office for the second time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the &#8216;conflict of interest&#8217; has reached a new level this time, compared to 2016. Today, his ventures extend far beyond real estate. Trump has now <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-assassination-attempt-defi-launch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">secured a significant footing in the crypto industry</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given Trump’s favorable stance toward digital asset policy development, players inside and outside the industry have begun to wonder whether his decisions are based on the sector’s best interests or are designed to benefit his own ventures.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-deep-is-trump-s-involvement-in-world-liberty-financial"><strong>How Deep is Trump&#8217;s Involvement in World Liberty Financial?</strong></h2>



<p>Though Trump does not have a direct role in WLFI, he appears on the whitepaper’s list of supporting teams as “Chief Crypto Advocate.” His three sons, Eric, Donald Jr., and Barron, are also on the list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Reports further unveiled that the Trump family holds a 75% stake in the platform’s net revenue and a 60% stake in the holding company. At the same time, Trump and his associates own 22.5 billion of the company&#8217;s tokens.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For former CFTC Commissioner Tim Massad, despite Trump’s informal role in WLF’s governance, his stake in the platform’s performance raises serious conflicts of interest.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think it&#8217;s unprecedented and plainly wrong for a President of the United States to engage in commercial ventures or have his family and associates engage in commercial ventures that can be directly influenced by the policies he adopts as President or the statements he makes about those policies,” Massad told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, the tokens themselves are non-transferrable, limiting financial flexibility. Though the project aims to provide token holders access to a range of DeFi-related products and services, it has yet to launch them. In the meantime, token holders will have to wait until the time comes to use their tokens.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I have yet to see any real business case or utility that&#8217;s of value to people who invest. So I think it all just has a character of taking advantage of people,” Massad added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The industry has also grown weary over how WLF and other Trump-endorsed projects could be used to gain the President&#8217;s favor.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-industry-leaders-voice-concerns-over-world-liberty-financial-s-legitimacy"><strong>Industry Leaders Voice Concerns Over World Liberty Financial&#8217;s Legitimacy</strong></h2>



<p>Shortly before Trump launched World Liberty Financial, many prominent figures in the crypto sector warned that the project could cause Trump further legal troubles. </p>



<p>Meanwhile, Alex Miller, CEO of Web3 platform Hiro, described the project as an “obvious pump scheme.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Just fucking shoot me<br><br>Anyone who thinks this is good for crypto, that it doesn’t make us look like clowns, that it doesn’t set us back YEARS in credibility….<br><br>This is such an obvious pump scheme. Maybe he won’t literally rug but he’s just grifting and it’s pathetic <a href="https://t.co/8bTGmUfLvG">pic.twitter.com/8bTGmUfLvG</a></p>&mdash; Alex Miller (@alexlmiller) <a href="https://twitter.com/alexlmiller/status/1845187172678430946?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 12, 2024</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Other industry leaders, such as Mark Cuban, Max Keiser, and Anthony Scaramucci, also criticized Trump’s decision to proceed with WLF’s token sales. Trump’s involvement in the project heightened fears that crypto’s fragile public image and controversial reputation would be smeared further.</p>



<p>Massad agreed with this last point, adding that crypto policy development is alive and well today more than ever. The ongoing development of stablecoin regulations, open talks of a national crypto strategic reserve, and a Senate-driven digital asset working group are only some of the current institutional initiatives.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“He, the Trump Organization and his family members should not be engaging in commercial ventures that pose such blatant conflicts of interest, given the fact that crypto regulation and things like a potential Bitcoin reserve are important policy issues today. A US president shouldn&#8217;t be engaging in these things at all, in my view,” Massad said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Since the project’s launch six months ago, several examples validating these concerns have emerged. The most notable one has focused on Tron founder Justin Sun.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-justin-sun-s-controversial-investment-in-wlf-i"><strong>Justin Sun&#8217;s Controversial Investment in WLF</strong>I</h2>



<p>TRON founder Justin Sun became World Liberty Financial’s largest investor in November <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-invests-30-million-trump-world-liberty-financial/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">after buying $30 million worth of WLF tokens</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The move was highly controversial. Despite Trump&#8217;s endorsement, WLFI struggled to meet its $30 million fundraising target during its first public sale. The token&#8217;s availability was restricted, excluding general trading and limiting purchases to non-US and accredited US investors.</p>



<p>Sun’s investment turned WLFI’s luck around. Soon after that, he also became one of the project’s advisors. Then, on the day of Trump’s inauguration, Sun invested an additional $45 million in the project, bringing the total sum to $75 million.</p>



<p>This investment brought varying degrees of scrutiny. While some questioned his quick transition from investor to advisor, others pointed to Sun’s past as a potential motive for his contributions.</p>



<p>In March 2023, the SEC <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sec-justin-sun-settlement-civil-fraud-case/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">filed fraud charges and other securities law violations</a> against Sun and his companies. This regulatory baggage has led some industry leaders to question the wisdom of his association with World Liberty Financial.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Tron&#8217;s price soared following Sun’s latest WLF investment. Tron, which had been experiencing lagging prices up until that point, was able to jumpstart its trading activities.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2466" height="1245" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236.png" alt="TRON price chart after Sun's world liberty financial investment" class="wp-image-679470" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236.png 2466w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-360x182.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-850x429.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-768x388.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-1536x775.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-2048x1034.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-236-150x76.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2466px) 100vw, 2466px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">TRON Price Surge Following Sun&#8217;s $45 Million Investment in World Liberty Financial. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/fFGOoxEA/?symbol=BINANCE%3ATRXUSDT" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>However, these conflicts of interest are not just limited to Sun&#8217;s investment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-potential-binance-stake-and-further-conflicts"><strong>Potential Binance Stake and Further Conflicts</strong></h2>



<p>Less than two weeks ago, reports surfaced that the Trump family had held talks <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-family-to-invest-in-binance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">to acquire a financial stake</a> in Binance’s US division. Though Binance’s founder, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-binance-cz-wlfi-allegations/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Changpeng Zhao, discredited these reports,</a> flirting with the theory comes easily.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">4. Sorry to disappoint. The WSJ article got the facts wrong.<br><br>More than 20 people have told me they were asked by the WSJ (and another media), &quot;Can you confirm that CZ made some deal for a pardon?&quot;<br><br>They probably asked hundreds of people to have 20 people reach out to me. In… <a href="https://t.co/ELyDPmKD3G">https://t.co/ELyDPmKD3G</a></p>&mdash; CZ <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f536.png" alt="🔶" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> BNB (@cz_binance) <a href="https://twitter.com/cz_binance/status/1900194883891322948?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 13, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Zhao could also benefit from an agreement. In 2023, he pleaded guilty to federal charges for failing to implement adequate anti-money-laundering measures at Binance. </p>



<p>Following his plea, Zhao resigned as Binance’s CEO. Motive-driven speculations point toward the possibility of a potential presidential pardon.</p>



<p>For Massad, maneuvers like these are natural when a president directly involves himself in crypto ventures.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think there is a huge risk of conflicts of interest and corruption by virtue of the President and people associated with him selling crypto assets—whether that&#8217;s through World Liberty Financial or the meme coins. It creates the potential for ongoing conflicts, because people who might want to curry favor with the administration could buy the coins,” Massad told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>All the while, Trump benefits his crypto ventures every time he makes a pro-crypto announcement.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-is-trump-manipulating-the-crypto-market"><strong>Is Trump Manipulating the Crypto Market?</strong></h2>



<p>A week into March, Trump signed an executive order to establish a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-strategic-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Crypto Strategic Reserve</a> and a US Digital Asset Stockpile. In his original announcement, Trump said the reserve would include Bitcoin, Ethereum, and altcoins like XRP, ADA, and SOL. </p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-us-crypto-reserve-debate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto market responded immediately</a>, with all five cryptocurrencies posting strong gains.&nbsp;Yet, Trump’s announcement quickly raised concerns over potential market manipulation.</p>



<p>With Bitcoin, Ethereum, and XRP in its treasury, WLF&#8217;s holdings grew in value as those assets appreciated. This growth could have boosted investor confidence, leading to higher demand for WLF tokens. </p>



<p>The crypto market&#8217;s overall surge and attention to Trump-related projects also generated greater investor interest in WLF, contributing to its price appreciation.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, Trump’s meme coin surged following the President’s reserve announcement. While TRUMP’s price stood at $13.55, with a trading volume of almost $1.2 billion on March 2, those numbers surged to $17.46 and $3.6 billion, respectively, following the news a day later.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2447" height="1222" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237.png" alt="trump meme coin price chart" class="wp-image-679471" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237.png 2447w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-360x180.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-850x424.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-768x384.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-1536x767.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-2048x1023.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-237-150x75.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2447px) 100vw, 2447px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">TRUMP Meme Coin Briefly Surges After Crypto Reserve Announcement. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/chart/eeOqiVxv/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>On March 4, TRUMP’s price and trading volume plummeted below the numbers they registered only two days earlier.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I think the meme coins have looked like a classic pump-and-dump scheme or money grab. I don&#8217;t think the issue should be, <em>why not let people invest in these things if they want to?</em> Of course they should have the right to invest in whatever they want. The issue is the propriety of the President of the United States selling things that capitalize on his being the President,” said Massad.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Even <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/vitalik-buterin-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum Co-Founder Vitalik Buterin</a> touched on the damaging effects of political meme coins in a social media post published five days after TRUMP’s launch.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Now is the time to talk about the fact that large-scale political coins cross a further line: they are not just sources of fun, whose harm is at most contained to mistakes made by voluntary participants, they are vehicles for unlimited political bribery, including from foreign nation states,” Buterin said.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">There is perhaps an analogy with weed here.<br><br>Ten years ago, to many weed represented freedom, and rebellion against sclerotic old order that denied self-sovereignty over our bodies. Then, weed became legalized, and &quot;official&quot;.<br><br>On that day, I remember my personal interest in weed…</p>&mdash; vitalik.eth (@VitalikButerin) <a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1882459101390602338?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 23, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Given Trump’s active participation in the crypto industry over the past several months, a vital question remains: Why hasn’t Trump been held accountable over these apparent conflicts of interest?</p>



<p>The answer remains short and bitter: He can’t be.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-can-trump-be-held-accountable"><strong>Can Trump Be Held Accountable?</strong></h2>



<p>The potential conflicts of interest arising from Donald Trump&#8217;s involvement in the cryptocurrency industry have drawn the attention of various political figures, particularly those focused on government ethics and oversight. </p>



<p>US Senator Elizabeth Warren has been the most vocal opponent of Trump’s dealings in the crypto industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A day before the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trumps-white-house-crypto-summit-market-impact/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">White House Digital Assets Summit</a>, Warren sent an extensive letter to Trump&#8217;s crypto czar, David Sacks.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I write today to request information about how you, as President Trump’s ‘Crypto Czar,’ have addressed your conflicts of interest, and how you will prevent the President and other private individuals from directly profiting off of the Trump Administration’s efforts to selectively pump the value of certain crypto assets, drop crypto asset-related enforcement actions, and deregulate the crypto asset industry. These actions have the potential to benefit billionaire investors, Trump Administration insiders, and speculators at the expense of middle-class families,” Elizabeth Warren wrote.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, not much else can be done beyond letters that demand responses and clarifications from the Trump administration.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-legal-loophole-nbsp"><strong>The Legal Loophole&nbsp;</strong></h2>



<p>US Presidents are largely exempted from conflict of interest provisions. This exemption has been based on legal interpretations that argue these laws could impede the President&#8217;s ability to fulfill their constitutional duties.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The problem is, the POTUS is not subject to the conflict-of-interest laws that apply to most other executive branch officeholders. There is the Foreign Emoluments Clause in the Constitution, which prohibits accepting gifts from foreign countries. There&#8217;s also a domestic clause that prohibits accepting gifts from the government. But beyond that, he&#8217;s not subject to the usual conflict-of-interest standards. So, it&#8217;s unfortunate that we don&#8217;t have those standards applicable to a president. I think, had any other president done these things, there would be far more outrage,” Massad told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Given the legal circumstances, public scrutiny and political pressure are the best ways to hold a president accountable for potential conflicts of interest. </p>



<p>Yet, despite the legal exemptions for sitting presidents, the ethical implications of Trump&#8217;s crypto dealings remain undeniable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the lines between political power and personal profit continue to blur, the necessity for clear ethical standards, even without legal mandates, becomes increasingly urgent. </p>



<p>Failing to do so might erode public trust in the crypto industry, generating potentially irreversible consequences.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ex-cftc-chair-trump-crypto-warning/">Ex-CFTC Chair Warns of Corruption Risks in Trump-Linked Crypto Projects</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_1.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_1.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>SheVerified: Maggie Wu, CEO of TruBit, on Global Growth, Bear Market Resilience, and Inclusion in Web3</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/sheverified-maggie-wu-trubit-ceo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn Wang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 06:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=679027</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trubit's Maggie Wu reflects on navigating cultural, regulatory, and gender challenges while scaling Web3 across emerging markets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sheverified-maggie-wu-trubit-ceo/">SheVerified: Maggie Wu, CEO of TruBit, on Global Growth, Bear Market Resilience, and Inclusion in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Maggie Wu is an early crypto evangelist and a seasoned entrepreneur. As the CEO and co-founder of Krypital Group and Galactic Holdings—the parent company behind TruBit—Wu has helped shape the growth of digital financial inclusion across Latin America and beyond. Her track record includes incubating Web3 unicorns, securing millions in venture funding, and building cross-border crypto infrastructure in some of the world&#8217;s most underserved markets.</p>



<p>In this SheVerified interview, Wu offers rare insight into what it takes to scale in emerging markets, raise capital in a bear cycle, and stay resilient as a woman driving impact in a male-dominated industry.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-you-had-a-strong-cross-industry-background-before-launching-krypital-and-galactic-holdings-what-made-you-transition-into-web3">You had a strong cross-industry background before launching Krypital and Galactic Holdings. What made you transition into Web3?</h4>



<p>Throughout my entrepreneurial journey, I have always been passionate about how technology can reshape the world. In 2017, I delved into blockchain and quickly recognized its potential to transform the global financial system. Though it was still a niche market at the time, I was convinced it would become the foundation of future <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ethena-securitize-launch-converge-blockchain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">financial infrastructure</a>.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-your-vision-for-crypto-s-role-in-financial-inclusion-and-how-can-we-ensure-it-doesn-t-just-replicate-the-inequalities-of-traditional-finance">What is your vision for crypto&#8217;s role in financial inclusion, and how can we ensure it doesn’t just replicate the inequalities of traditional finance?</h4>



<p>While traditional banking is essential, challenges like high costs, slow transactions, and limited access persist, especially in cross-border payments. Crypto enables faster, more accessible, and cost-effective financial services, especially for the unbanked.</p>



<p>To ensure true <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-backed-credit-decentralized-lending/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">financial inclusion</a>, we focus on lowering barriers, improving financial education, and prioritizing long-term value over speculation. At TruBit, we aim to build an open, efficient, and user-friendly financial system that empowers individuals.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-your-company-is-also-an-investor-and-incubator-of-high-growth-web3-projects-what-qualities-do-you-look-for-in-founders-when-selecting-which-teams-to-back">Your company is also an investor and incubator of high-growth Web3 projects. What qualities do you look for in founders when selecting which teams to back?</h4>



<p>When selecting investment projects, I look for several key qualities in founders. First is <strong>industry understanding and vision</strong>—a deep understanding of market trends paired with a clear long-term outlook.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then comes <strong>experience and execution ability</strong>, meaning the founder has relevant background and expertise, and can efficiently turn ideas into reality. I also value <strong>adaptability and learning agility</strong>, the ability to quickly adjust strategies and continuously optimize both products and business models.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another essential trait is <strong>resilience and market endurance</strong>, or the determination to persist through market cycles and navigate challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lastly, I consider the <strong>potential for global expansion</strong>—whether the team can scale across different markets and establish a strong competitive advantage.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-speaking-of-global-expansion-you-have-successfully-led-trubit-s-expansion-across-latam-and-asia-what-were-the-biggest-challenges-you-faced-during-this-time">Speaking of global expansion, you have successfully led TruBit’s expansion across LATAM and Asia. What were the biggest challenges you faced during this time?</h4>



<p>In Latin America, governments have been <a href="https://beincrypto.com/latam-crypto-news-october-12/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">introducing regulatory frameworks</a> in recent years, creating a relatively open environment for crypto. Regulators are generally willing to collaborate with companies to explore compliance pathways, but this requires time and continuous dialogue. </p>



<p>The positive side is that users in Latin America are highly receptive to new fintech solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Culturally, our team is primarily composed of local talent, starting in Mexico and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/latam-crypto-news-august-31/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">expanding into Argentina, Brazil</a>, and other markets, allowing us to integrate deeply into the local ecosystem. However, finding the right talent remains a challenge—it takes time to refine and optimize a strong team.</p>



<p>In Asia, particularly Hong Kong and Singapore, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-staking-facility-ethereum-etf/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto regulations</a> are ahead of the curve compared to other parts of the region, but still evolving relative to the US and Europe. As newcomers to the Asian market, we are still in the exploration phase. </p>



<p>However, strong partnerships and my own background in Asia have provided advantages in both networking and cultural adaptability.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-despite-the-challenges-you-ve-continued-to-lead-with-impact-one-standout-achievement-is-raising-capital-in-a-bear-market-what-lessons-can-founders-especially-women-learn-from-your-experiences">Despite the challenges, you&#8217;ve continued to lead with impact. One standout achievement is raising capital in a bear market. What lessons can founders, especially women, learn from your experiences?</h4>



<p>Fundraising in a bear market is not just a challenge—it’s a true test of resilience and long-term value.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For entrepreneurs, especially women, my advice is to <strong>lead with confidence and conviction</strong>—investors need to believe in you before they believe in your company. Resilience is equally important, particularly when navigating the volatility of this market and staying focused on your long-term vision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also essential to <strong>leverage your network</strong> by actively building relationships and seizing every opportunity that comes your way.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-challenges-have-you-faced-as-a-woman-from-your-early-days-in-the-industry-and-what-barriers-do-women-continue-to-face-in-crypto-leadership-today">What challenges have you faced as a woman from your early days in the industry? And what barriers do women continue to face in crypto leadership today?</h4>



<p>As a woman entering this industry, I inevitably encountered stereotypes and even unwarranted doubts based on gender or appearance. In a male-dominated space, women often have to work even harder to prove their expertise and earn trust. But for me, these challenges have been a source of motivation. I firmly believe that true value creation transcends gender—what truly matters is deep expertise, continuous growth, and a relentless drive for innovation and change.</p>



<p>In the fields of entrepreneurship, investment, and technology development, women are still very much in the minority. One of the biggest challenges we face is <strong>fundraising</strong>—there’s a clear disparity, with female founders consistently receiving far less venture capital than their male counterparts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There’s also <strong>the technical entry barrier</strong>. This industry started with a strong developer-driven culture, and for a long time, there just weren’t many women in technical roles, which made it even harder to break in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then there’s <strong>the lack of support systems</strong>. Many women struggle to find mentors or access the kind of professional networks and resources that can help them grow.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-are-the-first-three-steps-you-d-recommend-to-women-looking-to-build-a-strong-foundation-in-this-industry">What are the first three steps you’d recommend to women looking to build a strong foundation in this industry?</h4>



<p>For women looking to enter the Web3 industry, I recommend focusing on three key areas. First, <strong>learn the fundamentals</strong>—start by understanding blockchain, cryptocurrencies, smart contracts, and DeFi. You can quickly get up to speed through online search, industry media, online courses, industry reports, and community learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, <strong>gain hands-on experience</strong>. Whether by joining a Web3 company, investing, or starting your own project, practical involvement is more important than just theory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, <strong>build a strong network</strong>. Join industry communities, find like-minded peers and mentors, and integrate into the Web3 ecosystem as early as possible.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-in-your-view-how-can-the-industry-actively-support-more-women-in-founding-investing-and-scaling-web3-companies">In your view, how can the industry actively support more women in founding, investing, and scaling Web3 companies?</h4>



<p>Establishing dedicated funds and incubators to support female entrepreneurs, building strong women-led communities for mentorship and networking, and encouraging more women to enter technical roles are all critical steps toward lasting change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A more inclusive Web3 ecosystem will not only create opportunities for women but also lead to greater innovation and diversity in the space.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sheverified-maggie-wu-trubit-ceo/">SheVerified: Maggie Wu, CEO of TruBit, on Global Growth, Bear Market Resilience, and Inclusion in Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-27_22-19-30.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-27_22-19-30.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Experts Discuss Why Trump Might Be Tanking the Market on Purpose</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/experts-discuss-trump-tanking-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Camila Grigera Naón]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=677693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trump may be using tariffs to trigger a market downturn, forcing interest rates to come down. Experts warn of risks.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/experts-discuss-trump-tanking-market/">Experts Discuss Why Trump Might Be Tanking the Market on Purpose</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>‬Trump‬‭’s economic policies‬‭ have‬‭ created‬‭ much‬‭ uncertainty in the past few months,‬‭ stunting stock markets and rocking investor confidence. However, as the United States faces a significant debt maturity of $7 trillion and high yields, theorists wonder whether Trump’s tariffs can get the Federal Reserve to bring interest rates down.</strong></p>



<p>BeInCrypto spoke with Erwin Voloder, Head of Policy of the European Blockchain Association, and Vincent Liu, Chief Investment Officer at Kronos Research, to understand why Trump might be using tariff threats to boost American consumers&#8217; purchasing power. They warn, however, that the risks far outweigh the benefits.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-us-debt-dilemma">The US Debt Dilemma</h2>



<p>The United States currently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/senator-lummis-bitcoin-reserve-us-debt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has a national debt of $36.2 trillion</a>, the highest of any country in the world. This figure reflects the total sum of funds the federal government has acquired through borrowing to finance past expenditures.</p>



<p>In other words, the US owes foreign and domestic investors a lot of money. It will also have to repay certain loans in the next few months.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1264" height="693" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt.png" alt="The public sector finances nearly 80% of the federal government's gross debt." class="wp-image-677694" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt.png 1264w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt-360x197.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt-850x466.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt-768x421.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/debt-held-by-the-public-makes-up-nearly-80-of-gross-debt-150x82.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1264px) 100vw, 1264px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The public sector finances nearly 80% of the federal government&#8217;s gross debt. Source: <a href="https://www.pgpf.org/article/the-federal-government-has-borrowed-trillions-but-who-owns-all-that-debt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Peter G. Peterson Foundation</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>When the government borrows money, it issues debt securities, like Treasury bills, notes, and bonds. These securities have a specific maturity date. Before this deadline, the government must pay back the original amount borrowed. In the next six months, the United States will have to pay back around $7 trillion in debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The government has two options: It can either use available funds to repay the maturity debt or refinance it. If the federal government opts for the latter, it must take out further loans to repay the current debt, increasing the already ballooning national debt.</p>



<p>Since the US has a history of opting for the refinancing option, direct repayment seems unlikely. However, steep interest rates currently complicate refinancing.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-high-interest-rates-an-obstacle-to-debt-refinancing">High Interest Rates: An Obstacle to Debt Refinancing</h2>



<p>Refinancing allows the government to roll over the debt, meaning it doesn&#8217;t need to find the money from available funds to pay off the old debt immediately. Instead, it can issue new debt to cover the old one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the Federal Reserve&#8217;s interest rate decisions significantly impact the federal government&#8217;s ability to refinance its debt.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, the Federal Reserve announced that it will <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fomc-no-interest-rate-cuts-crypto-priced-in/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">keep interest rates between 4.25% and 4.50%</a>. The Reserve has steadily increased percentages past the 4% benchmark since 2022 to control inflation.</p>



<p>While this is good news for investors who expect higher yield returns on their bonds, it’s a bad outlook for the federal government. If it issues new debt to cover the old one, it would have to pay more in interest, which will strain the federal budget.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“In‬‭ practical‬‭ terms,‬‭ even‬‭ a‬‭ 1%‬‭ higher‬‭ interest‬‭ rate‬‭ on‬‭ $7‬‭ trillion equates to‬‭ $70 billion more in interest expense‬‭ per‬‭ year.‬‭ A‬‭ 2%‬‭ difference‬‭ would be $140‬‭ billion‬‭ extra‬‭ annually‬‭–‬‭ real‬‭ money that‬‭ could‬‭ otherwise‬‭ fund‬‭ programs‬‭ or‬‭ reduce‬‭ deficits,” Voloder told BeInCrypto, adding that “the‬‭ US‬‭ already‬‭ has‬‭ a‬‭ national‬‭ debt‬‭ exceeding‬‭ $36‬‭ trillion.‬‭ Higher‬‭ refinancing‬‭ rates‬‭ compound‬‭ the‬‭ debt‬‭ problem,‬‭ as‬‭ more‬‭ tax‬‭ revenue‬‭ must‬‭ go‬‭ just‬‭ to‬‭ pay‬‭ interest,‬‭ creating‬‭ a‬‭ vicious‬‭ cycle‬‭ of‬‭ larger‬‭ deficits‬‭ and‬‭ debt.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This scenario indicates that the United States needs to proceed cautiously with its monetary policies. With looming debt repayment deadlines and concerns over inflation, the government should embrace stability over uncertainty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, the Trump administration seems to be doing the opposite by threatening its neighbors with steep tariffs. The main question is: Why?&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trump-s-tariff-policies-a-strategy-or-a-gamble">Trump&#8217;s Tariff Policies: A Strategy or a Gamble?</h2>



<p>During Trump’s first and second terms in office, he has continuously toyed with a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tariff policy</a> targeting his <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-crypto-trade-war-us-china/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">neighbors Canada and Mexico and his longtime rival China</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In his most recent inaugural address, Trump reaffirmed his commitment to this trade policy, claiming it would bring money back into the United States.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I will immediately begin the overhaul of our trade system to protect American workers and families. Instead of taxing our citizens to enrich other countries, we will tariff and tax foreign countries to enrich our citizens. For this purpose, we are establishing the External Revenue Service to collect all tariffs, duties, and revenues. It will be massive amounts of money pouring into our Treasury, coming from foreign sources,” Trump said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, the ensuing uncertainty about trade relationships and consequent retaliatory actions from affected countries have inevitably created instability, causing investors to react sharply to the news.</p>



<p>Earlier this month, markets experienced a widespread selloff, driven by anxieties surrounding Trump&#8217;s tariff policies. These resulted in a sharp decline in US stocks, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/why-is-bitcoin-going-down/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">a drop in Bitcoin&#8217;s value</a>, and a surge in Wall Street&#8217;s fear index to its highest point of the year.</p>



<p>A similar scenario also played out during Trump’s first presidency.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Intentionally rising economic uncertainty via tariffs carries steep risks: markets could overreact, plunging and increasing percentages for a possible recession, as seen in 2018&#8217;s trade war drop,” Liu said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2164" height="822" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM.png" alt="Bitcoin's One-Month Price Chart." class="wp-image-677696" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM.png 2164w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-360x137.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-850x323.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-768x292.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-1536x583.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-2048x778.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-20-at-8.09.33 PM-150x57.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2164px) 100vw, 2164px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin&#8217;s One-Month Price Chart. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Whenever traditional financial markets are affected, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-markets-impact-inflation-trumps-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto also suffers by association</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;In the immediate term, Trump&#8217;s production-first, America-First economics means digital asset markets‬‭ must‬‭ grapple‬‭ with‬‭ higher‬‭ volatility‬‭ and‬‭ less‬‭ predictable‬‭ policy‬‭ inputs.‬‭ Crypto‬‭ is‬‭ not‬‭ isolated‬‭ from‬‭ macro‬‭ trends‬‭ and‬‭ is‬‭ trading‬‭ increasingly‬‭ in‬‭ tandem‬‭ with‬‭ tech‬‭ stocks‬‭ and‬‭ risk‬‭ conditions,” Voloder said.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>While some view Trump’s measures as careless and erratic, others see them as calculated. Some analysts have viewed these policies as a means to get the Federal Reserve to lower interest rates.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-is-trump-using-tariffs-to-influence-the-federal-reserve">Is Trump Using Tariffs to Influence the Federal Reserve?</h2>



<p>In a recent video, Anthony‬ Pompliano, CEO of Professional‬ Capital‬ Management‬‭, argued that Trump was trying to lower Treasury yields by intentionally creating economic uncertainty.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The President and his team are intentionally crashing the market.<br><br>Is this a master plan or are we watching uncontrolled destruction?! <a href="https://t.co/Tbc0M9Rjxu">pic.twitter.com/Tbc0M9Rjxu</a></p>&mdash; Anthony Pompliano <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f32a.png" alt="🌪" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@APompliano) <a href="https://twitter.com/APompliano/status/1899154245783359849?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 10, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Tariffs can disrupt trade relationships by acting as taxes on imported goods, consequently increasing the cost of goods for consumers and businesses. Given that these policies are often a great source of economic uncertainty, they can create a sense of instability in the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As evidenced by the market’s strong reaction to Trump’s tariff announcements, investors were spooked out of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/made-in-usa-coins-fall-trump-recession/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">fear of an economic slowdown or looming recession</a>. Consequently, businesses might reduce risky investments while consumers limit spending to prepare for price spikes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investor habits may also change. With less confidence in a volatile stock market, investors may <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-stocks-continue-to-drop-amid-market-chaos/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">shift from stocks to bonds</a> to seek safe-haven assets. US Treasury bonds are considered one of the safest investments in the world. In turn, this flight to safety increases their demand.</p>



<p>When demand for bonds increases, bond prices go up. This series of events indicates that investors are bracing themselves for prolonged economic uncertainty. In response, the Federal Reserve may be more inclined to lower interest rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Trump achieved this during his first presidency.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The theory that tariffs could lift bond demand hinges on fear sparking market shifts. Tariff‬ uncertainty might trigger equity sell-offs, boosting Treasuries and lowering yields to ease $7 trillion in US debt refinancing evidenced by 2018, when trade shocks cut yields from 3.2% to‬ 2.7%. Yet, with inflation at 3-4% and yields at 4.8%, success is not guaranteed. This will require tariffs to be credible enough to adjust markets without stoking inflation,” Liu told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If the Reserve lowers interest rates, Trump can acquire new debt at a lower price to pay off the impending debt maturity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plan may also benefit the average American consumer– to an extent.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-potential-benefits">Potential Benefits</h2>



<p>Treasury yields are a benchmark for many other interest rates in the economy. Therefore, if Trump’s trade policies get Treasury yields to fall, this could have a trickle effect. The Federal Reserve could lower interest rates on other loans, such as mortgages, car loans, and student loans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In turn, borrowing rates would drop, and disposable income would increase. Thus, the average American citizen can contribute to overall economic growth with greater purchasing power.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“For‬‭ an‬‭ American‬‭ family,‬‭ a‬‭ drop‬‭ in‬‭ mortgage‬‭ rates‬‭ can‬‭ mean‬‭ substantial‬‭ savings‬‭ on‬‭ monthly‬‭ payments‬‭ for‬‭ a‬‭ new‬‭ home‬‭ or‬‭ refinance.‬‭ Businesses‬‭ might‬‭ find‬‭ it‬‭ easier‬‭ to‬‭ finance‬‭ expansions‬‭ or‬‭ hire‬‭ new‬‭ workers‬‭ if‬‭ they‬‭ can‬‭ borrow‬‭ at‬‭ 3%‬‭ instead‬‭ of‬‭ 6%.‬‭ In‬‭ theory,‬‭ greater‬‭ access‬‭ to‬‭ low-interest‬‭ loans‬‭ could‬‭ stimulate‬‭ economic‬‭ activity‬‭ on‬‭ Main‬‭ Street,‬‭ aligning‬‭ with‬‭ Trump’s‬‭ goal‬‭ of‬‭ revving‬‭ growth,” Voloder explained.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, the theory relies on investors reacting very specifically, which is not guaranteed.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“It’s a high-stakes bet with a narrow margin for error for success depending on many different economic‬ factors,” Liu said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the end, the risks heavily outweigh the potential benefits. In fact, consequences can be grave.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-inflation-and-market-instability">Inflation and Market Instability</h2>



<p>The theory of deliberately causing market uncertainty hinges on the fact that the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/fed-bessent-lower-interest-rates-amid-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Federal Reserve would bring down interest rates</a>. However, the Reserve is intentionally keeping interest rates high to contain inflation. A tariff war threatens to spur inflation.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Yields‬‭ could‬‭ hit‬‭ 5%‬‭ if‬‭ inflation spikes, not drop, and [Jerome] Powell’s‬‭ high‬‭ odds‬‭ of‬‭ holding‬‭ rates‬‭ steadily‬‭ undermine‬‭ the‬‭ plan,” Liu said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>To that point, Voloder added:</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If‬‭ the‬‭ plan‬‭ backfires‬‭ and‬‭ yields‬‭ don’t‬‭ fall‬‭ enough,‬‭ the‬‭ US might‬‭ end‬‭ up‬ ‭refinancing‬‭ at‬‭ high‬‭ rates‬‭ anyway‬‭ and‬‭ with‬‭ a‬‭ weaker‬‭ economy,‬‭ which‬‭ would‬‭ be‬‭ the‬‭ worst‬‭ outcome.”</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, since tariffs directly increase the cost of imported goods, this cost is often passed on to consumers. This scenario creates higher prices for a wide range of products and causes inflationary pressures, eroding purchasing power and destabilizing the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Inflation‬‭ stemming‬‭ from‬‭ tariffs‬‭ means‬‭ each‬‭ dollar‬‭ earned‬‭ buys‬‭ less.‬‭ This‬‭ stealth‬‭ tax‬‭ hurts‬‭ lower-income‬‭ families‬‭ the‬‭ most,‬‭ as‬‭ they‬‭ spend‬‭ a‬‭ higher‬‭ fraction‬‭ of‬‭ their‬‭ income‬‭ on‬‭ affected essentials,” Voloder said.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In this context, the Reserve would likely hike Treasury yields. The scenario could also gravely affect the health of the United States’ job market economy.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-impact-on-jobs-and-consumer-confidence">Impact on Jobs and Consumer Confidence</h2>



<p>The economic uncertainty of tariffs can deter businesses from continuing to invest in the United States. In this context, companies may delay or cancel expansion plans, reduce hiring, and cut back on research and development projects.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“‬‭The‬‭ impact‬‭ on‬‭ jobs‬‭ is‬‭ a‬‭ major‬‭ concern.‬‭ Intentionally‬‭ cooling‬‭ the‬‭ economy‬‭ to‬‭ force‬‭ rate‬‭ cuts‬‭ is‬ ‭ essentially‬‭ flirting‬‭ with‬‭ higher‬‭ unemployment.‬‭ If‬‭ markets‬‭ drop‬‭ and‬‭ business‬‭ confidence‬‭ wanes,‬ ‭ companies‬‭ often‬‭ respond‬‭ by‬‭ cutting‬‭ back‬‭ on‬‭ hiring‬‭ or‬‭ even‬‭ laying‬‭ off‬‭ workers,” Voloder said.‭</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Rising prices and market volatility could also damage consumer confidence. This dynamic would reduce consumer spending, which is a major driver of overall economic growth.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Americans‬‭ face‬‭ higher‬‭ prices‬‭ and‬‭ eroded‬‭ purchasing‬‭ power‬‭ as‬‭ a‬‭ direct‬‭ result‬‭ of‬‭ tariffs‬‭ and‬‭ uncertainty.‬‭ Tariffs‬‭ on‬‭ everyday‬‭ goods‬‭ –‬‭from‬‭ groceries‬‭ to‬‭ electronics‬‭–‬‭ act‬‭ like‬‭ a‬‭ sales‬‭ tax‬‭ that‬‭ consumers‬‭ ultimately‬‭ pay.‬‭ These‬‭ costs‬‭ hit‬‭ consumers‬‭ at‬‭ a‬ ‭ time‬‭ when‬‭ wage‬‭ growth‬‭ may‬‭ stall‬‭ if‬‭ the‬‭ economy‬‭ slows.‬‭ So,‬‭ any‬‭ extra‬‭ cash‬‭ saved‬‭ from‬‭ lower‬ ‭interest‬‭ payments‬‭ could‬‭ be‬‭ offset‬‭ by‬‭ rising‬‭ prices‬‭ for‬‭ consumer‬‭ goods‬‭ and‬ ‭ possibly‬‭ higher‬‭ taxes‬‭ down‬‭ the‬‭ road‬‭,” Voloder told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The consequences are not just limited to the United States, however. As with any trade dispute, countries will feel inclined to respond– and recent weeks have proven that they already have.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trade-wars-and-diplomatic-tensions">Trade Wars and Diplomatic Tensions</h2>



<p>Both countries responded sharply when Trump imposed 25% tariffs on products entering the US from Canada and Mexico.</p>



<p>Canadian Prime Minister Justin Trudeau <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-canada-tariff-crypto-bear-market-fears/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">called the trade policy a “very dumb thing to do.”</a> He then announced retaliatory tariffs on American exports and gave notice that a trade war would have consequences for both countries. Mexico’s President Claudia Sheinbaum did the same.</p>



<p>In response to Trump&#8217;s 20% tariff on Chinese imports, Beijing imposed retaliatory tariffs of up to 15% on various significant US agricultural products, including beef, chicken, pork, and soybeans.</p>



<p>Additionally, ten American companies now face restrictions in China after being placed on the country&#8217;s &#8216;reliable entity list.’ This list prevents them from engaging in import/export trade with China and limits their ability to make new investments there.</p>



<p>The Chinese Embassy in the United States also said that it wasn&#8217;t scared by intimidation.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The fentanyl issue is a flimsy excuse to raise U.S. tariffs on Chinese imports. Our countermeasures to defend our rights and interests are fully legitimate and necessary.<br><br>The U.S., not anyone else, is responsible for the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/FentanylCrisis?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#FentanylCrisis</a> inside the U.S. In the spirit of humanity… <a href="https://t.co/OjvSEcZS6o">pic.twitter.com/OjvSEcZS6o</a></p>&mdash; Spokesperson发言人办公室 (@MFA_China) <a href="https://twitter.com/MFA_China/status/1896904623589621816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">March 4, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Tariffs will also have consequences beyond harming international relations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-global-supply-chain-disruptions">Global Supply Chain Disruptions</h2>



<p>International trade wars could disrupt global supply chains and harm export-oriented businesses.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“From‬‭ a‬‭ macro‬‭ perspective‬‭ there‬‭ is‬‭ also‬‭ the‬‭ fear‬‭ of‬‭ trade‬‭ war‬‭ escalation‬‭ globally‬‭ which‬‭ could‬‭ have‬‭ the‬‭ boomerang‬‭ effect‬‭ of‬‭ denting‬‭ US‬‭ exports‬‭ and‬‭ manufacturing,‬‭ meaning‬‭ US‬‭ farmers‬‭ losing‬‭ export‬‭ markets‬‭ or‬‭ factories‬‭ facing‬‭ costlier‬‭ inputs.‬‭ This‬‭ global‬‭ tit-for-tat‬‭ could‬‭ amplify‬‭ the‬‭ downturn‬‭ and‬‭ also‬‭ strain‬‭ diplomatic‬‭ relations.‬‭ Additionally,‬‭ if‬‭ international‬‭ investors‬‭ see‬‭ US‬‭ policy‬‭ as‬‭ chaotic,‬‭ they‬‭ might‬‭ reduce‬‭ investment‬‭ in‬‭ the‬‭ US over‬‭ the‬‭ longer‬‭ term,” Voloder told BeinCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Inflationary pressures and economic downturns could also <a href="https://beincrypto.com/stablecoins-reshaping-finance-circle-executive/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">push individuals to embrace digital assets</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Additionally,‬‭ if‬‭ the‬‭ US pursues‬‭ mercantilist‬‭ policies‬‭ that‬‭ alienate‬‭ foreign‬‭ creditors‬‭ or‬‭ weaken‬‭ confidence‬‭ in‬‭ the‬‭ dollar’s‬‭ stability,‬‭ some‬‭ investors‬‭ might‬‭ increase‬‭ allocations‬‭ to‬‭ alternative‬‭ stores‬‭ of‬‭ value‬‭ like‬‭ gold‬‭ or‬‭ <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/bitcoin-halving-history/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin‬‭</a> as‬‭ a‬‭ hedge‬‭ against‬‭ currency‬‭ or‬‭ debt‬‭ crises,” Voloder explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Consumers might experience shortages of essential goods, while businesses would see increased production costs. Those that rely on imported materials and components would be particularly affected.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-high-risk-strategy-is-it-worth-it">A High-Risk Strategy: Is it Worth it?</h2>



<p>The theory that tariffs could lower yields by creating uncertainty is a highly risky and potentially damaging strategy. The negative effects of tariffs, such as inflation, trade wars, and economic uncertainty, far outweigh potential short-term benefits.</p>



<p>As products become more expensive and businesses reduce their workforce to equilibrate their balance sheets, the average American consumer will experience the brunt of the consequences.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/experts-discuss-trump-tanking-market/">Experts Discuss Why Trump Might Be Tanking the Market on Purpose</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_3.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/bic_Donald_Trump_USA_neutral_3.png"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
