<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Businesses - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/business/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/business/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 09:42:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Businesses - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/business/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Web3 Gaming: Balancing Fun and Profit in the Next Evolution of Digital Play</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/web3-gaming-fun-profit-balance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The future of Web3 gaming lies in striking a delicate balance between entertainment and profit, according to industry leaders and experts at the 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong. Recent data shows 60% of Web3 gamers stop playing within the first month, highlighting the sector&#8217;s key challenge: creating games that are genuinely fun while offering investment &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/web3-gaming-fun-profit-balance/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/web3-gaming-fun-profit-balance/">Web3 Gaming: Balancing Fun and Profit in the Next Evolution of Digital Play</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The future of Web3 gaming lies in striking a delicate balance between entertainment and profit, according to industry leaders and experts at the 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong.</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.binance.com/en/square/post/12-27-2024-challenges-and-innovations-in-blockchain-gaming-by-2025-18098491992585" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Recent data</a> shows 60% of Web3 gamers stop playing within the first month, highlighting the sector&#8217;s key challenge: creating games that are genuinely fun while offering investment potential.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-fun-first-profit-second">Fun First, Profit Second</h2>



<p>&#8220;Games should be fun first,&#8221; said Quinn, Director of Strategy at Delabs Games. &#8220;The monetization layer is kind of an add-on. Many Web3 games that have failed so far couldn&#8217;t get the retention loops good enough.&#8221;</p>



<p>This sentiment was echoed throughout multiple sessions at the Web3 Festival, with speakers consistently emphasizing that enjoyable gameplay must precede tokenomics.</p>



<p>&#8220;For sustainability, we need to find external sources of revenue that supplement the token economy,&#8221; said Chris, CSO at Tabi. &#8220;This creates a base layer of yield that sustains the game when token prices fluctuate.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-messenger-platforms-drive-adoption">Messenger Platforms Drive Adoption</h2>



<p>Messaging apps are becoming key gateways for Web3 gaming, providing ready access to millions of users. For Layer 1 blockchains seeking mass adoption, games integrated into these platforms emerge as the critical first use case.</p>



<p>Kaia DLT Foundation, which launched on LINE messenger in January, has already deployed  more than 60 applications, with games comprising roughly 80% of its offerings. The project combines blockchain initiatives from South Korea&#8217;s Naver (LINE) and Kakao through their merged blockchain projects Finschia and Klaytn.</p>



<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re targeting users who consume short-form content,&#8221; explained Sam Seo, Chairman of Kaia DLT Foundation, in an exclusive interview with BeInCrypto. &#8220;Our strategy draws from Kakao&#8217;s earlier experiences, where gaming drove initial Web2 messenger growth. We believe Web3 will follow a similar path.&#8221;</p>



<p>Their most successful game has already attracted 5.5 million users, demonstrating the potential of lightweight, casual games in the Web3 space.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="850" height="567" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-850x567.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-685054" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-850x567.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-360x240.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-768x512.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GameFi_session_8-150x100.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong.</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-technical-innovations-expand-gaming-possibilities">Technical Innovations Expand Gaming Possibilities</h2>



<p>New blockchain architectures are unlocking previously impossible gaming experiences. Howard Wu, Co-founder of Aleo, explained how their zk-technology enables more sophisticated gameplay mechanics.</p>



<p>&#8220;When you look at Ethereum or Solana, these fully public Layer 1s can support games like chess but cannot support games like Battleship where you have hidden game states,&#8221; Wu explained in a separate interview. &#8220;With private smart contracts on Aleo, you can have information asymmetry, supporting quests with hidden features and loot boxes.&#8221;</p>



<p>Sarah Song, Head of Business Development at BNB Chain, addressed scaling challenges: &#8220;High-frequency GameFi applications often require Layer 2 solutions due to their large transaction volumes. You can deploy on Layer 2 protocols first and send final confirmations to the settlement layer.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-future-outlook-mainstream-adoption">Future Outlook: Mainstream Adoption</h2>



<p>The path forward requires making blockchain technology invisible to users. &#8220;Web3 should be in the backend, enhancing the overall gaming experience without emphasizing return on investment,&#8221; said Clement, Head of Partnerships at Spot Zero, during the Web3 Festival&#8217;s GameFi panel discussion.</p>



<p>Quin noted, &#8220;With AI, users, and communities can make user-generated content with our IPs. That&#8217;s going to be powerful for ecosystem growth.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;In our Arena of Faith game, players earn tokens but a portion goes to a staking pool – it&#8217;s playing to stay, not just playing to earn,&#8221; explained Hason, Founder of Arena of Faith.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/web3-gaming-fun-profit-balance/">Web3 Gaming: Balancing Fun and Profit in the Next Evolution of Digital Play</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/gamefi-banner-mobile-360x195-1.png" medium="image" width="360" height="195" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/gamefi-banner-mobile-360x195-1.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet The Crypto Marketing Queen: 15 mins with Amanda Cassatt</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/amanda-cassatt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a swift Hong Kong encounter, we caught up with Amanda Cassatt, the undisputed queen of crypto marketing. From HuffPost editor to ConsenSys CMO to founding Serotonin, she&#8217;s been reshaping how blockchain connects with the world. Fifteen minutes. Rapid fire. Here&#8217;s the buzz. APAC HUB: WHY HONG KONG? Hong Kong has proven itself forward-thinking with &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/amanda-cassatt/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/amanda-cassatt/">Meet The Crypto Marketing Queen: 15 mins with Amanda Cassatt</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>In a swift Hong Kong encounter, we caught up with Amanda Cassatt, the undisputed queen of crypto marketing. From HuffPost editor to ConsenSys CMO to founding Serotonin, she&#8217;s been reshaping how blockchain connects with the world. Fifteen minutes. Rapid fire. Here&#8217;s the buzz.</em></p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-apac-hub-why-hong-kong">APAC HUB: WHY HONG KONG?</h6>



<p>Hong Kong has proven itself forward-thinking with crypto regulation. Great home base to travel easily—Vietnam, Korea, Japan, Singapore, India. We help global projects enter Asia and local projects go global.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-secret-weapon">SECRET WEAPON?</h6>



<p>Taking responsibility for making certain outcomes happen. The world is changing so fast—PR, advertising, social media. We&#8217;ve done the legwork and built relationships so clients can focus on building products.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-gallery has-nested-images columns-default is-cropped wp-block-gallery-1 is-layout-flex wp-block-gallery-is-layout-flex">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="566" height="850" data-id="684806" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02-566x850.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-684806" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02-566x850.jpg 566w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02-240x360.jpg 240w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02-768x1154.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02-150x225.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda02.jpg 852w" sizes="(max-width: 566px) 100vw, 566px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Source: 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong</figcaption></figure>
</figure>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-on-community-marketing">ON COMMUNITY MARKETING:</h6>



<p>We&#8217;re facilitators, blowing oxygen on the sparks of what the community is already doing. Crypto collapses investors, builders, and users into a single category called &#8216;community.&#8217; We set up incentives, solve the cold start problem, and watch what organically emerges.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ai-s-role">AI&#8217;S ROLE:</h6>



<p>No more excuses for typos. If you think AI is a good writer, it just means you&#8217;re a worse writer than AI. Great for research—double-check for hallucinations. Great for copy editing. But no match for the highest quality human.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-industry-focus">INDUSTRY FOCUS:</h6>



<p>This cycle, RWA is really interesting. BlackRock&#8217;s CEO saying everything will be tokenized. Stablecoins are huge—USD already has product-market fit, so tokenizing it automatically gets PMF. Novel DeFi primitives keep evolving.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-your-book-s-message">YOUR BOOK&#8217;S MESSAGE:</h6>



<p><em><a href="https://amandacassatt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web3 Marketing</a></em> just hit shelves in Mandarin. It&#8217;s the story of bringing Ethereum to market, graded with my personal journey. The takeaway? It&#8217;s more efficient to incentivize users to help grow your platform than to market the whole thing yourself. It&#8217;s a template for harnessing community ownership.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ethereum-to-now">ETHEREUM TO NOW:</h6>



<p>We built strategies that became templates for how Web3 projects come to market. Some tactics are enshrined, but we want to conserve what&#8217;s worked while defining the next greatest trend.</p>



<p><em>As our 15 minutes closes, this Columbia graduate and Forbes 30 Under 30 honoree drops one certainty: The thing that doesn&#8217;t change in marketing is the protocol—understanding the </em>audience, understanding the product, and <em>measuring how well it&#8217;s working. Rinse and repeat. From the daughter of a neuroscientist and computer scientist to the architect of Web3&#8217;s marketing playbook, Cassatt continues leading Serotonin&#8217;s global team of 100 from the edge of what&#8217;s next.</em></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/amanda-cassatt/">Meet The Crypto Marketing Queen: 15 mins with Amanda Cassatt</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda-Cassatt.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Amanda-Cassatt.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stablecoins Gain Momentum in Asia as Financial Adoption Grows</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/asia-stablecoin-growth-financial-adoption/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoin News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Stablecoins are gaining significant traction across Asia as regulators and financial institutions embrace these blockchain-based assets, industry leaders said at Hong Kong&#8217;s Web3 Festival this week. While the United States moves toward legislation on stablecoins, Asian markets are developing their own frameworks with Hong Kong at the forefront of regulatory innovation. Market Expansion Beyond USD &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/asia-stablecoin-growth-financial-adoption/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/asia-stablecoin-growth-financial-adoption/">Stablecoins Gain Momentum in Asia as Financial Adoption Grows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Stablecoins are gaining significant traction across Asia as regulators and financial institutions embrace these blockchain-based assets, industry leaders said at Hong Kong&#8217;s Web3 Festival this week.</strong></p>



<p>While the United States moves toward <a href="https://beincrypto.com/stablecoin-transparency-act-regulation-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">legislation on stablecoins</a>, Asian markets are developing their own frameworks with Hong Kong at the forefront of regulatory innovation.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-market-expansion-beyond-usd-dominance">Market Expansion Beyond USD Dominance</h3>



<p>The global stablecoin market has reached $220 billion in value, surpassing pre-Terra collapse levels, JD.com Vice President and Chief Economist Shen Jianguang told attendees. Monthly transactions now exceed 700 billion USD, with volume already surpassing traditional payment networks like Visa and Mastercard.</p>



<p>JD.com, one of China&#8217;s largest e-commerce companies, has been <a href="https://beincrypto.com/chinese-showcase-digital-yuan-2023-beijing-fair/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">at the forefront of stablecoin innovation,</a> having issued a Hong Kong dollar-based stablecoin in July 2024. The company is leveraging its extensive foreign trade corridors for exports and imports, implementing stablecoins in closed-loop systems as initial use cases.</p>



<p>US dollar-backed tokens currently dominate approximately 99% of the market, according to Rita Liu, CEO of RD Technologies, one of the first companies selected for Hong Kong&#8217;s stablecoin issuer regulatory sandbox. Liu noted growing interest in non-USD alternatives across the region.</p>



<p>&#8220;A CNH-backed stablecoin could be very interesting under Hong Kong&#8217;s regulation,&#8221; Liu said, referring to offshore yuan that trades outside mainland China. &#8220;It will become a meaningful tool as China&#8217;s exports to emerging markets are increasingly priced in RMB.&#8221;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-hong-kong-s-regulatory-leadership">Hong Kong&#8217;s Regulatory Leadership</h3>



<p>Hong Kong is positioning itself as a stablecoin hub with its regulatory framework advancing rapidly. Legislative Council Member <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-stablecoin-lawmaker-china-regulator/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Duncan Chiu</a> said the territory&#8217;s stablecoin bill is expected to pass in May, with issuance possible in the second half of this year.</p>



<p>Standard Chartered&#8217;s Head of Digital Asset &amp; FinTech Hong Kong, Dominic James Maffei, believes combining USD stablecoins with high-quality regulated local currency stablecoins will create powerful market dynamics. He pointed to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/usdc-stablecoin-japan-approval/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Japan</a>&#8216;s &#8220;Project Pax,&#8221; where the country&#8217;s three major banks have jointly developed a cross-border payment system using stablecoins, as an example of successful implementation that Hong Kong could emulate and improve upon.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-multi-currency-solutions-gaining-ground">Multi-Currency Solutions Gaining Ground</h3>



<p>Ryan De Souza, Partnerships Lead at Arbitrum, highlighted that his platform is seeing increased adoption of multiple currency stablecoins beyond USD.</p>



<p>&#8220;We&#8217;re not only seeing great dominance in USD stablecoin liquidity, but we&#8217;re also onboarding different currency stablecoins, high-quality regulated stablecoins onto the ecosystem,&#8221; said De Souza. He noted that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ripple-rlusd-launch-xrp-selloffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mexican fintech Bitso</a> launched MXN stablecoin exclusively on Arbitrum, while Singapore-based issuers have introduced Singapore dollar stablecoins on the platform.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="850" height="566" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49-850x566.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-684704" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49-850x566.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49-360x240.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49-768x511.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49-150x100.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-08_21-15-49.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Hashkey Exchange BG Co-CEO Ru Haiyang. Source: Web3 Festival.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Traditional financial institutions are rapidly entering the ecosystem. Ru Haiyang, Co-CEO of Hashkey Exchange BG, pointed to major banks including Bank of America, BNY Mellon, Standard Chartered, Brazil&#8217;s Itaú, and Japan&#8217;s Sumitomo Mitsui Bank exploring stablecoin initiatives. &#8220;Going forward, the swap between stablecoins and fiat currencies will be just as easy as doing foreign exchange,&#8221; predicted Ru, emphasizing that this financial integration will make stablecoins a mainstream tool for international transactions.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-efficiency-driving-mainstream-adoption">Efficiency Driving Mainstream Adoption</h3>



<p>The driving forces behind adoption are efficiency and cost advantages. While traditional remittances require five working days and average 6.3% in fees globally, blockchain stablecoin payments can complete transactions within an hour at significantly lower costs.</p>



<p>Circle&#8217;s Vice President Yam Ki Chan emphasized the technological superiority of stablecoins. &#8220;At a technology level, it&#8217;s a better form of money. There are things you can do with stablecoins with logic and conditionality that you cannot do with the best form of non-blockchain based digital money today.&#8221;</p>



<p>Industry experts anticipate stablecoins will continue expanding beyond crypto trading into mainstream financial applications, with Asia playing a significant role in this evolution as regulatory clarity emerges across the region.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/asia-stablecoin-growth-financial-adoption/">Stablecoins Gain Momentum in Asia as Financial Adoption Grows</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bic_stablecoins_neutral-covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/12/bic_stablecoins_neutral-covers.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solana&#8217;s Vision of Internet Capital Markets: Insights from Lily Liu</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/solanas-vision-of-internet-capital-markets-lily-liu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Lily Liu, President of the Solana Foundation, is looking beyond meme coins to establish Solana as the infrastructure for what she calls &#8220;internet capital markets.&#8221; In an exclusive interview with BeInCrypto and a presentation at the 2025 Web3 Festival in Hong Kong, Liu outlined her vision for blockchain technology&#8217;s role in democratizing financial access. From &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solanas-vision-of-internet-capital-markets-lily-liu/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solanas-vision-of-internet-capital-markets-lily-liu/">Solana&#8217;s Vision of Internet Capital Markets: Insights from Lily Liu</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Lily Liu, President of the Solana Foundation, is looking beyond meme coins to establish Solana as the infrastructure for what she calls &#8220;internet capital markets.&#8221;</strong></p>



<p>In an exclusive interview with BeInCrypto and a presentation at the 2025 Web3 Festival in Hong Kong, Liu outlined her vision for blockchain technology&#8217;s role in democratizing financial access.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-from-meme-coins-to-the-everything-chain">From Meme Coins to the &#8220;Everything Chain&#8221;</h2>



<p>&#8220;Solana has evolved from being the DeFi chain to the NFT chain, the gaming chain, the payment chain, and recently the meme coin chain,&#8221; Liu explained. &#8220;When you sum all that up, Solana is the everything chain.&#8221;</p>



<p>While meme coins drove Solana&#8217;s price to an impressive $290 high in January before falling 60% to around $120 today, Liu views them as just one transient asset class in a much broader ecosystem. &#8220;Meme coins are just one type of asset. There will be something else—there&#8217;s always going to be the tulip market and the beanie baby market. That&#8217;s been going on for a really long time. That&#8217;s just what humans do with or without blockchain,&#8221; Liu noted.</p>



<p>Despite price volatility, Solana&#8217;s Total Value Locked (TVL) reached an all-time high in April 2025, demonstrating continued investor confidence in the ecosystem beyond speculative assets.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-crisis-of-capital-access-for-young-generations">The Crisis of Capital Access for Young Generations</h2>



<p>Liu, who previously co-founded Earn.com (acquired by Coinbase in 2018) and served as CFO of Chinaco Healthcare Corporation, brings significant experience from building businesses in both the US and China to her current role at Solana. Her background in traditional finance gives weight to her critique of current capital markets.</p>



<p>&#8220;Fifty years ago, it took 25 hours of labor to buy one share of the S&amp;P 500. Today, it takes 195 hours,&#8221; Liu noted in her presentation, highlighting how capital gains have become less accessible to average workers while losses are increasingly socialized through national debt.</p>



<p>This inaccessibility to capital markets has created anxiety among young people globally. Liu pointed to challenges in Korea and China, where housing prices have skyrocketed beyond what young professionals can afford without parental support.</p>



<p>&#8220;In Korea and China, the parents&#8217; generation has retained the upside of a major asset class like housing. Young people&#8217;s ability to convert hours of labor into capital and freedom later in life has become extremely limited,&#8221; she observed. &#8220;In China, it creates huge anxiety for families where young men are culturally expected to own an apartment before marriage, yet average professional salaries make this impossible without parental help.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-blockchain-as-global-financial-infrastructure">Blockchain as Global Financial Infrastructure</h2>



<p>Liu sees blockchain&#8217;s core purpose as creating a unified global financial infrastructure, similar to how the internet unified attention. &#8220;What crypto is doing is providing this unified infrastructure to unify the wealth, the transactions, the financial coffers of five and a half billion people,&#8221; she explained.</p>



<p>This infrastructure enables what Liu calls &#8220;internet capital markets,&#8221; making the full range of financial assets available to anyone with an internet connection. She contrasts the simplicity of downloading a crypto wallet against the complex paperwork of traditional banking and investment systems.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="566" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3-850x566.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-684870" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3-850x566.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3-360x240.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3-768x512.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3-150x100.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily_Solana_3.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Lily Liu, President of Solana Foundation. Source: 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong.</figcaption></figure>



<p>For Liu, this infrastructure is particularly valuable in expanding access to equities and other assets that have both fundamental value and price discovery—currently reserved primarily for accredited investors even in developed markets.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-community-based-capitalism-and-the-ownership-economy">Community-Based Capitalism and the Ownership Economy</h2>



<p>Liu argues that blockchain offers an alternative to traditional economic systems. &#8220;In the last 100 years, we&#8217;ve come to accept that the dominant ownership models are either capitalist or communist—corporate ownership or state ownership,&#8221; she explained. &#8220;What Bitcoin proposed is that those aren&#8217;t the only choices.&#8221;</p>



<p>This has evolved into what Liu calls &#8220;community-based capitalism,&#8221; a term she uses to describe economic models where value accrues to network participants rather than just shareholders or the state. &#8220;Instead of universal basic income, which is essentially a welfare economy, crypto proposes universal basic opportunity,&#8221; she said. This model allows early participants in network building to share in the upside.</p>



<p>Liu contrasts this with traditional platforms like Uber, where early drivers who helped bootstrap the network received hourly pay but no equity upside. Her &#8220;ownership economy&#8221; concept refers to this more inclusive approach to capital formation where contribution and ownership are more closely aligned.</p>



<p>Solana&#8217;s governance reflects this philosophy, which was recently demonstrated in a controversial proposal to reduce inflation. Liu actively participated in this discussion, explaining that inflation reduction might seem efficient from a network security perspective but would potentially harm Solana as a yield-generating asset.</p>



<p>&#8220;Dynamic yield on an asset makes it a worse asset,&#8221; Liu emphasized. &#8220;If you have an asset yielding a fixed percentage annually, you price that very differently than an asset yielding at variable rates.&#8221;</p>



<p>Looking five years ahead, Liu envisions Solana enabling an ownership economy where blockchain creates new pathways for individuals to convert labor into capital, bringing &#8220;more inclusivity for five and a half billion people on the internet into capital markets.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;The end state is moving into assets that have value, can also command price, and bring more inclusivity around the world,&#8221; Liu concluded. &#8220;This is where crypto is going.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/solanas-vision-of-internet-capital-markets-lily-liu/">Solana&#8217;s Vision of Internet Capital Markets: Insights from Lily Liu</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily-Liu.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Lily-Liu.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Future of Web3 Venture Capital: What to Expect in 2025</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/future-of-web3-venture-capital-what-to-expect-in-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jakub Dziadkowiec]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News for institutional investors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web3 News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gate.io executive Laura K. Inamedinova discusses the factors that are shaping the future of Web3 venture capital.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/future-of-web3-venture-capital-what-to-expect-in-2025/">Future of Web3 Venture Capital: What to Expect in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>BeInCrypto had the opportunity to sit down with Laura K. Inamedinova, Chief Ecosystem Officer at Gate.io, during the Next Block Expo, The Blockchain Festival of Europe 2025. As one of the leading figures in the Web3 and crypto space, Laura shared her insights on the current state of the venture capital industry, its challenges, and the exciting opportunities emerging in 2025. </strong></p>



<p>In this interview, Laura discusses the factors that are shaping the future of Web3 venture capital, the potential for stablecoins and real-world asset tokenization, and how global regulatory advancements are paving the way for more institutional involvement in the sector. Her expertise offers valuable guidance for anyone looking to understand the next phase of crypto and blockchain development.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-resurgence-of-web3-venture-capital-key-drivers-for-2025">The Resurgence of Web3 Venture Capital: Key Drivers for 2025</h2>



<p><em><strong>BeInCrypto (BIC)</strong>: Given the challenging VC landscape in 2024, what factors do you believe will drive a potential resurgence in Web3 venture capital activity in 2025?</em></p>



<p><strong>Laura K. Inamedinova (LKI)</strong>: After a tough 2024, I think we’re finally seeing the pieces fall into place for a strong Web3 VC comeback in 2025. Regulations are becoming clearer; the US is dropping major <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sec-drops-xrp-lawsuit-against-ripple/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lawsuits like Ripple</a>, and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/american-voters-oppose-trump-bitcoin-reserve/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump announced</a> a $17 billion crypto reserve. </p>



<p>That shift alone has already brought results: we saw $861 million in crypto VC deals just in Q1, which is a clear sign of renewed confidence. What’s also fueling the comeback is global capital.</p>



<p>For example, Gate Ventures launched a $100 million fund with UAE last year, and Abu Dhabi invested $2 billion into Binance, positioning the region as a new hotspot for Web3 investment. Overall, Web3 venture capital activity is shifting back to the early stage. In 2024, 85% of VC deals were seed or Series A, backing infrastructure-first projects like modular chains like Celestia and Move-based networks like Movement Labs.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-institutional-involvement-and-regulatory-advancements-shaping-investment-strategies">Institutional Involvement and Regulatory Advancements Shaping Investment Strategies</h2>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: Last year marked the rise of institutional involvement in Web3 and regulatory advancements for the industry. How do you see these factors influencing your investment strategy in the coming year?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: This has been a cycle of contrasts. Retail chased hype-driven meme coins, while institutions played it safe, focusing on stablecoins and tokenized assets. </p>



<p>Regulatory clarity is now reinforcing that shift: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/mica-eu-unanimous-approval/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MiCA in Europe</a> and new US frameworks under the Trump administration are making yield-bearing stablecoins and risk-adjusted RWAs like tokenized treasuries more attractive. In a high-interest-rate environment, these assets offer stable returns &#8211; a much safer bet for serious investors.</p>



<p>Our investment thesis aligns with this institutional trend, focusing on RWA tokenization platforms and stablecoin ecosystems. By backing the infrastructure that enables compliant, scalable adoption, we position ourselves at the core of crypto’s institutional evolution.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-consumer-oriented-solutions-in-web3">Consumer-Oriented Solutions in Web3</h2>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: Which areas of Web3 (e.g., NFTs, DeFi, DAOs, etc.) do you believe will maintain its momentum into 2025, and why?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: To predict the next big narratives, we need to understand what’s holding the market back today. Most projects have been heavily B2B-focused, catering to existing industry players rather than expanding the ecosystem by attracting a fresh audience from Web2. This inward-facing approach has limited mainstream adoption. It created an echo chamber where innovation circulates among the same user base without reaching new consumers.</p>



<p>Put simply, for one project to win, three others need to die. The true winners of this cycle will be those who shift their focus to consumer-oriented solutions, designing products and experiences that resonate with everyday users. By prioritizing accessibility, usability, and real-world value, these projects will finally break the cycle and catalyze the beginning of the bull market.</p>



<p>Apart from the B2C focused apps, I see strong potential in AI, RWA, and payment solutions. It goes without saying, AI is here to stay. But instead of simple <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-ai-agents-expand-in-number-despite-declining-market-caps/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ChatGPT-wrapped AI agents</a>, we’ll see more advanced, integrated solutions with real-world applications, including robotics. </p>



<p>This will unlock a ton of new use cases in automated security, AI-driven trading, and on-chain decision-making, to name just a few. I see AI transforming from an external tool into a fundamental layer of Web3. RWA tokenization will continue to gain momentum, especially with the integration of AI-powered RWAs.</p>



<p>Major institutions like State Street are already exploring AI-driven tokenized bonds and money market funds. There’s a growing alignment between traditional finance and blockchain. This isn’t a niche development &#8211; it’s an opportunity to unlock liquidity in a $70 trillion+ asset class. With RWA tokenization <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-dominates-rwa-buidl-aum-grows/">projected to surpass $50 billion</a> by the end of 2025, the addition of AI will introduce automation, scalability, and transparency &#8211; critical elements for mass adoption.</p>



<p>Payments will also be a key driver. Stablecoins are seeing increased adoption for cross-border transactions, remittances, and on-chain settlements. Regulatory clarity and improved UX will accelerate this trend, making stablecoins a core component for the future of global finance.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="638" height="850" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO-638x850.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-683823" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO-638x850.jpg 638w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO-270x360.jpg 270w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO-640x853.jpg 640w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO-150x200.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Gate-IO.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 638px) 100vw, 638px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bartek Juraszek of BeInCrypto speaks with Laura K. Inamedinova at Next Block Expo</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-stablecoins-as-core-infrastructure-for-venture-capital">Stablecoins as Core Infrastructure for Venture Capital</h2>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: Stablecoin development attracted significant venture capital in the last quarter of 2024. Do you see this trend continuing, and what specific aspects of stablecoin projects are you prioritizing?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: Stablecoins <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-venture-capital-to-exceed-18-billion/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">were a major VC focus</a> in late 2024, and I see that trend continuing in 2025. Just in Q4, stablecoin projects pulled in $649 million across nine deals; that’s nearly 18% of all crypto VC funding. We’re also seeing strong signals from traditional finance: Fidelity is testing its own stablecoin, and Trump-linked World Liberty Financial launched USD1. </p>



<p>With over $239 billion in stablecoins already in circulation, this space isn’t just growing, it’s becoming core infrastructure for payments, trading, and settlements across both DeFi and TradFi.</p>



<p>What’s getting the most attention now is the rise of gold-backed stablecoins. Tokens like Tether’s XAUT and Paxos’ PAXG now hold a combined market cap of over $1.4 billion, a massive jump from just $12 million in 2020. These asset-backed models bring real-world value on-chain and offer protection against inflation, which is super attractive in today’s macro environment.</p>



<p>Based on this, we&#8217;re prioritizing stablecoin projects that have strong collateral models, clear regulatory paths, and real use cases beyond speculation, especially those bridging into RWAs or global payments.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-innovations-in-defi-and-infrastructure">Innovations in DeFi and Infrastructure</h2>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: DeFi and Infrastructure followed closely behind the top categories. What specific innovations within these sectors are you most excited about for potential funding in 2025?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: I think in DeFi, the real momentum is getting toward projects that merge automation with usability and compliance. One standout is DeFi Agents AI ($DEFAI), which raised $1.2 million in January 2025, backed by GameFi.org and eesee.io. It is building an AI trading assistant layered with restaking mechanics. So, you’re not just trading; you’re staking for revenue share and training custom models.</p>



<p>Add to that tools like Griffain, which reduces impermanent loss by 22%, and VaderAI, running 10,000+ on-chain transactions daily, and you start to see a new class of DeFi products built for scale, efficiency, and real usage. As MiCA 2.0 rolls out in Europe, platforms that offer AI-powered compliance and risk tools will stand out in both funding rounds and user adoption.</p>



<p>From an infrastructure perspective, we’re seeing strong capital flow into AI-ready backend systems that support these DeFi layers. CoreWeave, backed by over $1.1 billion from Nvidia and Microsoft, is scaling AI-optimized data centers that can support up to 5 million DeFi agents per site.</p>



<p>On the enterprise side, Cisco’s acquisition of strong intelligence and deeper insights AI shows how serious legacy tech firms are about owning the infrastructure layer. For investors, this is where the edge is. Make sure to check out projects that are building the high-speed, compliant infrastructure that will quietly power the next wave of DeFi and on-chain automation.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-not-just-meme-coins-and-ai-agents-is-web3-maturing">Not Just Meme Coins and AI Agents: Is Web3 Maturing?</h2>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: The last couple of months suggested a shift away from meme coins and AI agents. What do you attribute this change in investor sentiment to, and what does it suggest about the maturity of the Web3 market?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: The recent shift away from memes and AI agents reflects a growing maturity in the Web3 market. Meme coins, while often <a href="https://beincrypto.com/donald-trump-usd1-stablecoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">popular in speculative cycles</a>, generally lack real utility, making them unsustainable in the long run.</p>



<p>AI agents are still in their infancy &#8211; most projects offer similar functionalities, suffer from technical limitations, and remain too buggy for practical use. As the market matures, investors are becoming more discerning, prioritizing projects with tangible value, strong fundamentals, and real-world applications. </p>



<p>This shift suggests a move toward more sustainable narratives, such as payments, RWA tokenization, and infrastructure, signaling that Web3 is evolving beyond hype-driven trends into a phase of real adoption and long-term growth.</p>



<p><em><strong>BIC</strong>: What types of projects and what qualities of projects are you most looking for in 2025?</em></p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: We have multiple criteria when evaluating projects with the best fit for our venture arm. First, we’re looking for projects that are led by experienced founders with a proven track record in Web3, ideally with a successful exit in the past.</p>



<p>Second, we prioritize businesses with existing investor backing, whether in the current or previous rounds. We evaluate each project on a case-by-case basis, but our investment thesis generally revolves around stablecoins, payments, new technology, infrastructure, and US-based projects.</p>



<p>Third, we take into consideration the project’s valuation, tokenomics, and burn rate.</p>



<p>Last but not least, we assess the company’s ability to drive real-world adoption, offering solutions with a clear path to mainstream success.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion-venture-capital-in-web3">Conclusion: Venture Capital in Web3</h2>



<p><strong>BIC</strong>: How do you balance the pursuit of emerging trends with the need for sustainable, long-term value creation in your Web3 investments?</p>



<p><strong>LKI</strong>: One of the clearest signals this cycle has been the rise of AI agent coins &#8211; they hit a $16.6 billion market cap early in 2025. It shows that when you combine a viral narrative with actual user engagement, there’s staying power. </p>



<p>From there, we saw that the bigger trend wasn’t just AI; it was AI fused with tokenization. Projects like Centrifuge, which tokenizes real-world assets like invoices and real estate to unlock liquidity for businesses, are doing exactly that. They&#8217;re not hype plays; they’re solving real inefficiencies in traditional finance using on-chain rails.</p>



<p>We’re also seeing strong signals from early-stage modular blockchain ecosystems that are building quietly but with clear scalability goals. We lean into trends but only when the tech underneath has the foundation to last.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="565" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1-850x565.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-683822" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1-850x565.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1-360x239.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1-768x511.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1-150x100.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/f2e47453-96e1-4a6e-8237-6705b82a2ab4_1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Laura K. Inamedinova speaks at NBX</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-about-laura-k-inamedinova">About Laura K. Inamedinova</h3>



<p>An award-winning serial entrepreneur, investor, and keynote speaker sharing her insights on Web3 space since 2016. She currently holds a dual role within the Gate ecosystem, managing the global growth of the exchange and attracting new investments to its venture arm &#8211; GVC. </p>



<p>In her position as a CGEO at Gate.io, she builds cross-border partnerships and as a Principal at Gate Ventures, Laura oversees investments, partnerships, and development of the fund.</p>



<p>Before joining Gate.io, she founded a Web3 marketing agency, LKI Consulting, which she grew to 8-figures. This led her to be globally acclaimed as one of the “10 Women Entrepreneurs” by Entrepreneur Magazine and among the “Top 10 Women in International Business” by Silicon Valley Times. She was named one of Forbes&#8217; 30 Under 30 Blockchain Visionaries, recognizing her impact on the global crypto ecosystem.</p>



<p>On a personal level, Laura is a successful angel investor with 40+ projects in her portfolio, an ex-Forbes and Huffington Post columnist, and an internationally renowned speaker with a track record of 156+ conferences in 25+ countries.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-about-gate-io">About Gate.io</h3>



<p>Gate.io is a global cryptocurrency exchange platform that facilitates the buying, selling, and trading of over 3,800 digital assets. It offers a variety of products and services, including spot and futures trading, staking, decentralized finance (DeFi) solutions, Web3 wallets, and educational resources. </p>



<p>Additionally, Gate.io provides a range of tools for managing crypto investments, such as exchange wallets, live market data, and token airdrops. The platform also emphasizes security with robust measures like proof of reserves and offers services like Gate Pay for sending and receiving cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/future-of-web3-venture-capital-what-to-expect-in-2025/">Future of Web3 Venture Capital: What to Expect in 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Laura-K.-Inamedinova.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Laura-K.-Inamedinova.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TON&#8217;s Path to 500M Users and US Expansion Plans &#8211; Interview with Steve Yun</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/steve-yun-reveals-ton-foundation-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Steve Yun, representing TON Foundation as a board member, met with BeInCrypto during the 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong. In this exclusive interview, he discussed TON&#8217;s recent developments and their unique position in the blockchain landscape as a mini-app focused infrastructure built for Telegram&#8217;s ecosystem. The conversation covered TON&#8217;s $400 million secondary market investment, technical &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/steve-yun-reveals-ton-foundation-strategy/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/steve-yun-reveals-ton-foundation-strategy/">TON&#8217;s Path to 500M Users and US Expansion Plans &#8211; Interview with Steve Yun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Steve Yun, representing TON Foundation as a board member, met with BeInCrypto during the 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong. In this exclusive interview, he discussed TON&#8217;s recent developments and their unique position in the blockchain landscape as a mini-app focused infrastructure built for Telegram&#8217;s ecosystem.</strong></p>



<p>The conversation covered TON&#8217;s $400 million secondary market investment, technical upgrades to their asynchronous architecture, and strategic initiatives across DeFi and gaming sectors. Yun also shared his perspectives on expansion into US markets and leveraging the Asia-Pacific region&#8217;s familiarity with super-app ecosystems.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tvl-on-ton-has-dropped-by-72-why-and-what-s-your-response">TVL on TON has dropped by 72%. Why, and what&#8217;s your response?</h6>



<p>The decrease in Total Value Locked primarily stems from our strategic decision to discontinue liquidity pool incentives. Our analysis confirms that incentives are effective—with their impact being significant in bear markets and exponentially greater during bull markets—but the fundamental challenge is ensuring that liquidity remains sustainable after incentives end.</p>



<p>What we discovered is that a comprehensive DeFi ecosystem is essential for sustainable liquidity. Our initial infrastructure consisted primarily of basic Automated Market Makers, which wasn&#8217;t sufficient. Now we&#8217;re building a complete suite of DeFi primitives: lending protocols, derivatives, perpetual futures, concentrated liquidity DEXs with limit orders, stable swap mechanisms like Curve, and dynamic liquidity solutions similar to Maverick.</p>



<p>These capital-efficient tools create an ecosystem where liquidity naturally wants to remain. We&#8217;re busy developing this comprehensive infrastructure, and once it&#8217;s in place, we&#8217;ll consider reintroducing incentives. The key insight was that incentives alone create temporary activity, but a robust ecosystem creates lasting value and sustainable growth.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-will-you-use-the-recent-400m-investment-with-telegram-for-web3-initiatives">How will you use the recent <a href="https://fortune.com/crypto/2025/03/20/telegram-based-blockchain-ton-raises-400-million-from-prominent-crypto-vcs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">$400M investment</a> with Telegram for Web3 initiatives?</h6>



<p>The $400 million investment happened over several years in the secondary market, not directly to the foundation. The foundation does not directly receive these funds—the beneficiaries are Toncoin holders and miners who determine the allocation of these proceeds independently. We operate solely on donations from miners as our reserve. While we hope these funds benefit the ecosystem, it&#8217;s ultimately up to the individual holders. It&#8217;s important to clarify that when we announced this investment, we were consolidating and reporting secondary market sales that we were aware of, not announcing a direct investment into the foundation itself.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="566" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-850x566.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-684392" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-850x566.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-360x240.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-768x511.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-150x100.jpg 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Steve Yun is giving a keynote speech at the Web3 Festival main event. Source:Web3 Festival</figcaption></figure>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-key-features-will-your-2025-layer-2-network-and-accelerator-mainnet-upgrade-deliver">What key features will your 2025 Layer-2 network and <a href="https://docs.ton.org/v3/documentation/infra/nodes/validation/collators" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">&#8220;Accelerator&#8221; mainnet upgrade</a> deliver?</h6>



<p>We&#8217;ve implemented substantial enhancements to TON&#8217;s asynchronous architecture, which is fundamentally different from synchronous blockchains like Ethereum. In TON, transactions don&#8217;t need to wait for previous ones to confirm—they can all be confirmed simultaneously, making it much faster and more scalable. Previously, congestion in one shard could affect the entire network, but our update ensures problems remain isolated to specific shards, greatly improving network robustness.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also developing a new programming language to replace FunC, which presents significant complexity for developers due to its low-level nature. Additionally, we&#8217;re working on workchains—similar to Polkadot&#8217;s parachains but more tightly coupled with the main chain. These specialized chains will enable use cases the current infrastructure can&#8217;t support efficiently, like high-frequency trading that requires hyper-liquid decentralized exchanges. These improvements collectively make TON more developer-friendly and capable of supporting diverse applications.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-how-will-the-ton-btc-bridging-mechanism-impact-your-ecosystem">How will the TON BTC bridging <a href="https://blog.ton.org/unlocking-the-future-of-bitcoin-with-ton-teleport-btc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">mechanism</a> impact your ecosystem?</h6>



<p>tgBTC represents a significant addition to our collateral ecosystem, substantially boosting liquidity in TON&#8217;s DeFi environment. What makes it unique is our implementation approach. Most wrapped Bitcoin solutions on other chains use token standards like ERC-20, which include compliance features allowing the issuer to freeze or confiscate assets. This centralization is problematic for Bitcoin holders who value decentralization.</p>



<p>TON addresses this challenge through our proprietary &#8220;extra currencies&#8221; technology, which functions like Toncoin itself—controlled only by the validator network, not by any single entity. This means tgBTC cannot be frozen or confiscated by the token creator, making it uniquely appealing to Bitcoin holders who want to generate yield through DeFi activities but have been reluctant to use other wrapped solutions due to custody concerns. They can now utilize their Bitcoin in DeFi without compromising on the core value of censorship resistance that attracted them to Bitcoin initially.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-advantages-does-ton-have-in-defi-and-gamefi">What advantages does TON have in DeFi and GameFi?</h6>



<p>Speaking personally, I maintain measured expectations regarding the future trajectory of crypto gaming. When we&#8217;ve seen high-quality games launch on Telegram, users&#8217; primary concern tends to focus on tokenization timelines rather than appreciating gameplay. People want speculation, not games—crypto gaming often served as an alternative vehicle for speculative activity. Even successful examples like Axie Infinity saw price outpace reality, and few still play these games.</p>



<p>The foundation continues supporting gaming initiatives due to Telegram&#8217;s social aspects, but I believe the crypto gaming paradigm as initially conceived may have reached its conclusion. It can exist as one monetization strategy among many, but isn&#8217;t essential.</p>



<p>DeFi, however, cannot exist without crypto. We&#8217;re focused on payments and DeFi solutions, including the tokenization of Telegram bonds, which generate 8-15% annual returns and may offer discount access to potential Telegram IPOs—powerful assets for the ecosystem.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-are-your-us-expansion-plans-under-chairman-manuel-stotz-s-leadership">What are your US expansion plans under chairman <a href="https://blog.ton.org/ton-foundation-new-president" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Manuel Stotz</a>&#8216;s leadership?</h6>



<p>Due to past SEC issues with Gram, we maintained a policy of non-engagement with US entities. When they reached out, we simply declined engagement opportunities. However, the regulatory landscape has evolved, prompting a recalibration of our strategy.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re now actively engaging with US companies and exchanges about listing Toncoin and TON-based assets, including stablecoins. We&#8217;re encouraging stablecoin issuers to natively mint on TON. The community has already begun holding events in the US, and the foundation plans to establish physical representation there.</p>



<p>A significant development is making the non-custodial portion of TON Space wallet available to US persons, which was previously restricted. This strategic shift recognizes the importance of the US market while maintaining compliance with regulatory requirements.</p>



<h6 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-what-s-your-message-at-hong-kong-web3-festival-and-asia-pacific-strategy">What&#8217;s your message at Hong Kong Web3 Festival and Asia-Pacific strategy?</h6>



<p>Our strategic positioning distinguishes us from conventional blockchain projects—we target mini-app developers rather than smart contract developers. While other chains attend Ethereum conferences to compete for smart contract developers, we focus on regions with established super-app ecosystems. The APAC region is particularly important because people here understand and use super-apps like WeChat, Line, and KakaoTalk.</p>



<p>We access this market through Hong Kong, building relationships with key players like Hashkey, who&#8217;ve supported us by providing main stage access for TON Ecosystem Day two years running. This partnership is strategic because APAC users possess sophisticated familiarity with integrated digital ecosystems, making them ideal early adopters for TON&#8217;s mini-app ecosystem within Telegram. The region&#8217;s familiarity with integrated digital experiences makes it fertile ground for our approach to Web3 adoption.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/steve-yun-reveals-ton-foundation-strategy/">TON&#8217;s Path to 500M Users and US Expansion Plans &#8211; Interview with Steve Yun</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-Yun.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Steve-Yun.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>RWA Tokenization Takes Center Stage in Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/rwa-tokenization-takes-center-stage-in-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 23:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>At this week&#8217;s series of Web3 events in Hong Kong, industry leaders are highlighting real world asset (RWA) tokenization as a pivotal evolution in blockchain&#8217;s journey toward mainstream adoption. &#8220;This is the perfect time for our whole industry,&#8221; said Shukyee Ma, Chief Strategy Officer of Plume, during an exclusive interview. &#8220;After last year&#8217;s disappointment with &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/rwa-tokenization-takes-center-stage-in-hong-kong/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/rwa-tokenization-takes-center-stage-in-hong-kong/">RWA Tokenization Takes Center Stage in Hong Kong</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>At this week&#8217;s series of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-financial-innovation-industrial-revolution/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web3 events</a> in Hong Kong, industry leaders are highlighting real world asset (RWA) tokenization as a pivotal evolution in blockchain&#8217;s journey toward mainstream adoption.</strong></p>



<p>&#8220;This is the perfect time for our whole industry,&#8221; said Shukyee Ma, Chief Strategy Officer of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/yzi-labs-invests-in-plume-network/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Plume</a>, during an exclusive interview. &#8220;After last year&#8217;s disappointment with DeFi yields, users are looking for something new, and we have the tokenized assets ready.&#8221;</p>



<p><strong>Read more: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/tokenization-rwas/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Impact of Real World Asset (RWA) Tokenization</a></strong></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-purpose-built-blockchains-leading-the-way">Purpose-Built Blockchains Leading the Way</h2>



<p>A key trend emerging from the discussions is the development of purpose-built blockchains specifically designed for RWAs, rather than using existing general-purpose chains.</p>



<p>&#8220;All those public chains are not built for RWA protocols,&#8221; explained Ma. &#8220;That&#8217;s why we build this RWA chain and put DeFi composability on top of it to make it easier for crypto users to adopt.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Over the next 10 years we&#8217;re going to see a lot of existing fungible assets coming on chain—US treasuries, sovereign bonds, equities,&#8221; predicted Jayant Ramanand, Co-founder of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/mantra-rwa-ecosystem-fund-om-price-steady/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">MANTRA</a>. &#8220;As these assets come on chain, you&#8217;ll have fungible, movable value that can be transferred across the world instantly.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-regulatory-challenges-and-opportunities">Regulatory Challenges and Opportunities</h2>



<p>Industry professionals identified regulatory certainty as vital for widespread adoption.</p>



<p>&#8220;In order to further unlock the potential of this technology and encourage traditional finance to adopt it, we issued circulars to provide guidance,&#8221; said Elizabeth Wong, Director of Fintech at <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-accelerates-crypto-licensing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hong Kong&#8217;s Securities and Futures Commission</a>. &#8220;We maintained it to be agnostic to the technology used, as each blockchain has their benefits and limitations.&#8221;</p>



<p>Vivian Mei, a lawyer specializing in RWA compliance, observed that global regulatory frameworks are becoming increasingly aligned: &#8220;The overall regulatory landscape is moving toward high convergence in terms of virtual asset definitions, KYC requirements, and compliance standards.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="566" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61-850x566.png" alt="" class="wp-image-684379" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61-850x566.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61-360x240.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61-768x512.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61-150x100.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-61.png 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">During the Web3 Festival, the RWA tokenization was discussed in Hong Kong through various events, including the main event discussion. Source: 2025 Web3 Festival Hong Kong</figcaption></figure>



<p>George Chou, Chief Fintech Officer at <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-approves-bitcoin-assets-for-immigration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hong Kong Monetary Authority</a>, highlighted their Project Ensemble initiative: &#8220;We want to explore an innovative market infrastructure with the industry to facilitate settlement using tokenized money, and identify impactful domestic and cross-border use cases with leading experts and industry pioneers.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bridging-traditional-finance-with-crypto">Bridging Traditional Finance with Crypto</h2>



<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not just simply bringing offline assets on-chain. It&#8217;s providing a structural change in how the real world and virtual world connect,&#8221; said JJ from The PAC, whose platform recently tokenized a quantitative fund with approximately $100 million in assets.</p>



<p>While financial assets will lead early adoption, Rachel Keum, CEO of VaultX, offers a different approach with her platform tokenizing art assets using NFC technology: &#8220;Our mission is to revolutionize RWA ownership by empowering digital-illiterate creators and collectors to unlock new value in the digital economy.&#8221; She explained that VaultX had already launched partnerships with galleries across Asia and Europe, creating a decentralized marketplace for artists to receive ongoing royalties from secondary sales.</p>



<p>Consumer-focused applications are also emerging. &#8220;The real distribution is never for institutional investors—it&#8217;s for the people,&#8221; said EudemoniaCC from Morph, whose Black Card quickly gained popularity. &#8220;We&#8217;re trying to put payment and consumption at the center, letting people spend their crypto assets in the real world while bringing new audiences into the ecosystem.&#8221;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/rwa-tokenization-takes-center-stage-in-hong-kong/">RWA Tokenization Takes Center Stage in Hong Kong</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_tokenization_building_4-covers.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_tokenization_building_4-covers.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>AlgosOne X BeInCrypto AMA Session</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/algosone-beincrypto-ama-session/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sofia Pashnina]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>AlgosOne is making a significant impact by simplifying crypto and stock trading for users of all levels. Recently, Alex Andera, Head of Marketing and Public Relations at AlgosOne, joined BeInCrypto for an AMA session to discuss the platform&#8217;s unique features, from automated trading to risk management.  During the session, Alex discussed how AlgosOne&#8217;s AI-powered system &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/algosone-beincrypto-ama-session/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/algosone-beincrypto-ama-session/">AlgosOne X BeInCrypto AMA Session</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><a href="https://algosone.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"><strong>AlgosOne</strong></a><strong> is making a significant impact by simplifying crypto and stock trading for users of all levels. Recently, Alex Andera, Head of Marketing and Public Relations at AlgosOne, joined BeInCrypto for an AMA session to discuss the platform&#8217;s unique features, from automated trading to risk management. </strong></p>



<p>During the session, Alex discussed how AlgosOne&#8217;s AI-powered system streamlines trading, supports multiple assets, and ensures a user-friendly experience, even for beginners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this article, we’ll recap the key insights from the AMA and explore how AlgosOne is shaping the future of AI trading by making trading accessible to everyone.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ama-session-with-algosone">AMA Session With AlgosOne</h2>



<p><strong>BeInCrypto: Today, we have a guest speaker from AlgosOne – Alex Andera, Head of Marketing &amp; Public Relations <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f525.png" alt="🔥" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></strong></p>



<p><strong>Without further ado…</strong></p>



<p><strong>Could you explain how AlgosOne&#8217;s AI trading platform works in simple terms for new users? And what types of assets or markets can be traded on the AlgosOne platform?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex Andera: </strong>Algosone is an AI-powered trading bot that makes crypto trading effortless. No need to understand markets, charts, or coding—just deposit funds, choose your trading mode, and let the AI handle the rest. Go fully automatic or receive trade notifications to approve with a single click.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With a proven track record and a high success rate, Algosone takes the complexity out of trading so you can focus on the results.</p>



<p><strong>What Types of Assets or Markets Can Be Traded on AlgosOne?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Cryptocurrencies: </strong>AlgosOne allows you to trade popular digital assets like Bitcoin, Ethereum, and other altcoins</p>



<p><strong>Stocks: </strong>AlgosOne supports trading in various asset types, including crypto, stock, and commodities.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Can beginners use AlgosOne, or is it only for experienced traders?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex:</strong> AlgosOne is designed to be <strong>user-friendly</strong> and accessible to both <strong>beginners</strong> and <strong>experienced traders</strong>. Here’s how it accommodates users at all skill levels:</p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>No Trading Experience Needed:</strong><strong><br></strong> Beginners don’t need any prior knowledge of trading. The platform uses <strong>AI-powered automation</strong> to make trading decisions for you, so you don’t have to manually place trades or analyze complex data. The AI does all the work while you sit back and monitor performance.<br></li>



<li><strong>Easy Setup and Interface:</strong><strong><br></strong> The <strong>AlgosOne platform</strong> is designed with a simple, <strong>intuitive interface</strong> that’s easy to navigate. New users can quickly create an account, fund it, and start trading with just a few clicks.<br></li>



<li><strong>Educational Resources:</strong><strong><br></strong> AlgosOne provides educational materials, such as <strong>tutorials and guides</strong>, to help beginners understand how the platform works and how they can maximize their trading potential. These resources break down complex trading concepts into easy-to-understand content.<br></li>



<li><strong>Customizable Risk Strategies for Experienced Traders:</strong><strong><br></strong> While beginners can benefit from fully automated trading, more experienced traders have the option to <strong>customize risk strategies</strong> to suit their specific needs. The platform also supports advanced features for those looking for more control over their trades. According to my experience even the advanced traders prefer to us our AI and let it do the work for them, while saving them tons of time and effort. </li>
</ol>



<p>Overall, <strong>AlgosOne</strong> is designed to be accessible for beginners while offering enough features to satisfy experienced traders, making it a versatile platform for users of all levels.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: How does AlgosOne&#8217;s AI trading system work?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne&#8217;s AI trading system continuously analyses a vast amount of trade-related data using machine learning. It makes data-driven trading decisions based on statistical analysis and market trends to generate consistent profits for users.</p>



<p>There is a detailed YouTube video about this subject: </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="How Algosone Technology Works?" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Exr0wAkGsno?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p><strong>BIC: Are there any risks involved with using AlgosOne’s AI-driven trading system?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne provides a secure investing environment. It is licensed in the EU and has partnerships with major custodians and grade-A banks.</p>



<p>As with any AI-driven trading system, there are inherent risks associated with using AlgosOne.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While the platform utilizes advanced algorithms designed to optimize trading strategies, it’s important to note that no trading system is entirely risk-free. Market volatility, unforeseen economic events, and algorithmic limitations can result in losses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AlgosOne aims to mitigate these risks through continuous updates, monitoring, and improvements to its algorithms. However, users should always be aware of the potential for market fluctuations that could impact their investments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At higher trading tiers, AlgosOne offers compensation for failed trades from its <strong>reserve fund</strong>. The compensation amount is a percentage of the sum invested in the trade and is returned to your account balance. The higher your trading tier, the higher the compensation percentage.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: How does AlgosOne ensure the security of user data and funds while using the platform?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex:</strong> AlgosOne prioritizes the security of both user data and funds. The platform employs robust security measures, including encryption protocols and secure access controls, to protect sensitive information. User data is stored in compliance with industry standards and best practices for data protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, AlgosOne works with reputable financial partners and integrates with secure payment and banking systems to safeguard user funds. Regular security audits and updates are conducted to ensure that the platform remains secure in an ever-evolving digital landscape.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Can you elaborate on the AI models used in AlgosOne’s platform, specifically the NLP and deep learning algorithms? What percentage of trade win rate does your AI system ensure?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne&#8217;s platform leverages advanced artificial intelligence technologies, including deep learning and natural language processing (NLP) models, to enhance trading strategies across various financial markets.</p>



<p><strong>AI Models and Technologies:</strong></p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Deep Neural Networks:</strong> AlgosOne employs proprietary deep neural networks trained on extensive and diverse datasets. These networks have adaptive learning capabilities, allowing them to self-adjust and improve performance over time.<br></li>



<li><strong>Natural Language Processing (NLP):</strong> The platform utilizes NLP models akin to GPT-4 and LLaMA, enabling the AI to extract relevant information, interpret data, and identify relationships between data points. This allows the system to analyze a vast array of data sources, including global economic indicators and market sentiment.<br></li>



<li><strong>Continuous Learning Algorithms:</strong> AlgosOne&#8217;s AI integrates continuous learning algorithms that incorporate new data to refine trading strategies without the need for retraining.<br></li>



<li><strong>Real-Time Analytics:</strong> The platform is equipped with real-time analytics tools capable of processing large volumes of streaming global economic data, reflecting price movements, market sentiment, and emerging trends.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Trade Win Rate:</strong></p>



<p>AlgosOne has achieved an average annual trade success rate of 80% for two consecutive years, with some accounts in 2024 reaching up to a 92% success rate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This performance is attributed to the integration of advanced AI technologies and continuous oversight by human risk-management teams.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note that while the AI system has demonstrated high success rates, individual results may vary based on factors such as market conditions and user engagement.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Does AlgosOne offer a trial period?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>The AlgosOne Trial Period is a special offering for new users who fund their accounts for the first time. It provides a 14-day window during which users can withdraw their deposited amount without incurring early termination penalties. This allows new users to explore Algosone&#8217;s services risk-free. We also offer a 30-day trading plan which has no early termination fees.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: How can users increase their chances of purchasing tokens at earlier, lower prices in the presale?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex:</strong> Users can increase their chances of purchasing AiAO tokens at earlier, lower prices in the AlgosOne presale by following these key steps:</p>



<p>1. Upgrade Your Account Tier</p>



<p>Token allocation is based on account tier—higher tiers receive larger allocations and priority access to early-stage pricing. To maximize your allocation:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Engage with the platform to qualify for higher tiers.</li>



<li>Follow AlgosOne’s tier upgrade criteria (such as staking, holding tokens, or platform activity).</li>
</ul>



<p>2. Complete KYC &amp; Register Early</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Ensure your account is verified and KYC-approved before the presale starts.</li>



<li>Users who complete these steps early will be able to participate without delays.</li>
</ul>



<p>3. Stay Updated &amp; Act Fast</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Monitor AlgosOne’s official channels for presale announcements.</li>



<li>Be ready to purchase as soon as the presale opens, as early-stage token prices are lower.</li>
</ul>



<p>4. Use a Fast &amp; Compatible Wallet</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Have a supported wallet funded in advance to avoid transaction delays.</li>
</ul>



<p>By upgrading your account tier and acting quickly, you can maximize your allocation and secure AiAO tokens at the best possible price.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Can you explain Retrodrop and how it rewards AlgosOne users for their community involvement? How can users become eligible for this special offer?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: What is Retrodrop?</strong></p>



<p>Retrodrop is a special reward program designed to thank early AlgosOne users by distributing AiAO tokens to those who actively contributed to the platform before its official launch.</p>



<p><strong>How Does Retrodrop Reward Users?</strong></p>



<p>Retrodrop rewards users based on their engagement, contributions, and commitment to the AlgosOne ecosystem. The more involved you are, the bigger your reward.</p>



<p><strong>Who is Eligible for Retrodrop?</strong></p>



<p>Users who meet one or more of the following criteria will be eligible:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Registered Before Launch – Only users who joined before the official launch qualify.</li>



<li>Active Community Participation – Engaging in community growth through discussions, referrals, and promotional activities.</li>



<li>Completed Tasks &amp; Achievements – Users who complete specific challenges or contribute to ecosystem development.</li>



<li>Deposited Funds &amp; Higher Account Tiers – Users who make deposits and hold higher-tier accounts receive larger rewards.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>How to Maximize Your Retrodrop Reward?</strong></p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Be an early registrant – Sign up before the token sale launch.</li>



<li>Engage with AlgosOne’s community – Participate in activities, discussions, and referrals.</li>



<li>Complete platform tasks &amp; challenges – Check for any special assignments that boost eligibility.</li>



<li>Deposit funds &amp; upgrade your tier – Higher-tier users receive larger allocations.</li>
</ul>



<p><strong>Final Tip:</strong> Stay connected to AlgosOne’s official channels for Retrodrop announcements, including reward distribution details and claiming instructions.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Please tell us more about the AIAO token. How does it offer price appreciation, and what factors drive its value increase? What are its benefits?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex:</strong> The AiAO token offers several unique advantages for holders, including:</p>



<p>Guaranteed Capital Appreciation: Each token sale stage will have a higher minimum price than the previous round.</p>



<p>Dividends: Token holders will receive quarterly or monthly dividends credited directly to their accounts, with amounts increasing as the user base grows.</p>



<p>Governance Rights: Holders can influence the platform’s direction and prioritize new developments through voting.</p>



<p>Additional benefits and utilities will be introduced during the sale stages.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>BIC: How does the AiAO token’s presale structure work, and what are the pricing tiers?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex:</strong> The <strong>AiAO token presale</strong> is structured to provide early adopters with opportunities to acquire tokens at progressively increasing prices across multiple stages. Here&#8217;s an overview of how the presale is organized and the associated pricing tiers:</p>



<p>Presale Structure:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Multiple Stages:</strong> The presale is divided into several stages, each offering a specific percentage of the total token supply.<br></li>



<li><strong>Eligibility:</strong> Only registered AlgosOne users who have completed the necessary verification processes are eligible to participate in the presale.<br></li>



<li><strong>Allocation Limits:</strong> Token purchase limits are determined by the user&#8217;s trading tier and platform activity, with higher-tier users receiving larger allocations.<br></li>



<li><strong>Intervals Between Stages:</strong> There is an interval of up to eight weeks between each presale round.<br></li>



<li><strong>Post-Presale Trading:</strong> After all presale stages are completed, tokens will become tradable on the AlgosOne platform and external exchanges.</li>
</ul>



<p>Pricing Tiers:</p>



<p>Each presale stage has a starting price that is at least 50% higher than the previous stage, incentivizing early participation. Below is a breakdown of the stages, the percentage of tokens available, and the corresponding starting prices:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="428" height="642" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-50.png" alt="" class="wp-image-683851" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-50.png 428w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-50-240x360.png 240w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-50-150x225.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 428px) 100vw, 428px" /></figure>



<p>This structured approach ensures that early participants can acquire AiAO tokens at more favorable prices, with the value appreciating in subsequent stages. For more information, please visit the presale: <a href="https://algosone.ai/aiao-presale/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">https://algosone.ai/aiao-presale/</a></p>



<p><strong>BIC: How can users track the performance of their trades on AlgosOne?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne offers several tools to help users track the performance of their trades effectively:</p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Real-Time Dashboards:</strong><strong><br></strong> Users have access to an intuitive <strong>dashboard</strong> where they can view key metrics, such as <strong>current portfolio balance</strong>, <strong>profit and loss (P&amp;L)</strong>, and <strong>trade history</strong>. The platform updates this information in real-time, allowing users to monitor their trades at any moment.<br></li>



<li><strong>Trade Performance Analytics:</strong><strong><br></strong> The platform provides detailed <strong>performance reports</strong> and analytics that break down each trade’s outcome, including entry and exit points, trade duration, and profit or loss. These reports are designed to help users evaluate the effectiveness of their trading strategies.</li>
</ol>



<p><strong>BIC: How does AlgosOne support users in terms of customer service and troubleshooting?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne offers robust customer support to ensure users have a seamless experience. Here’s how the platform assists users with troubleshooting and addressing any concerns:</p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Customer Support:</strong><strong><br></strong> AlgosOne provides <strong>round-the-clock customer support</strong>, ensuring that users can reach out for help at any time, whether it&#8217;s day or night. Support is available through <strong>live chat</strong> or via <strong>email</strong> for urgent issues.<br></li>



<li><strong>Help Center and Knowledge Base:</strong><strong><br></strong> The platform features an extensive <strong>Help Center</strong> and <strong>knowledge base</strong>, offering answers to common questions and providing <strong>step-by-step guides</strong> on how to use the platform, troubleshoot issues, and optimize trading strategies.</li>



<li><strong>Academy Page in the app:</strong></li>
</ol>



<p>AlgosOne provides an Academy page with tutorials and videos explaining the features of the platform and additional news, new features and updates.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: What role do account tiers play in AlgosOne, and how do they impact user experience?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>Account tiers in AlgosOne play a significant role in customizing the user experience, providing benefits based on the user’s level of involvement and activity. Here’s how account tiers work:</p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Increased Token Allocations:</strong><strong><br></strong> Higher account tiers provide users with <strong>larger allocations</strong> of AiAO tokens during presale events. This rewards active users and incentivizes those who are more engaged with the platform.<br></li>



<li><strong>Priority Support and Guidance:</strong><strong><br></strong> Higher-tier accounts also come with <strong>dedicated account managers</strong> who offer personalized support, making it easier for users to optimize their trading strategies and ensure their needs are met promptly.<br></li>



<li><strong>Exclusive Offers and Rewards:</strong><strong><br></strong> Users in higher tiers may also receive <strong>exclusive offers, bonuses, or rewards</strong> tied to their account activity and tier level, providing additional value as they continue to engage with the platform.<br></li>
</ol>



<p>By creating different account tiers, AlgosOne ensures that users are rewarded for their commitment and experience, giving them access to more advanced features and personalized services as they grow within the platform.</p>



<p><strong>Question: How do the different trading plans offered by AlgosOne compare to each other?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne offers three trading plans: the 1-Month Plan, the Standard Plan, and the High-Yield Plan.</p>



<p>The <strong>1-Month Plan</strong> is for short-term users seeking flexibility with a one-month commitment, offering semi-automated trading and liquid profits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <strong>Standard Plan</strong> provides a balance between flexibility and structure with liquid profits and contract terms for invested funds. It also includes semi-automated trading.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The <strong>High-Yield Plan</strong> is for long-term investors seeking higher returns, offering fully automated trading, compounded profits, and no access to profits until maturity. You can find more information in the guide <a href="https://help.algosone.ai/en/articles/10439157-algosone-trading-plans" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">here</a>. </p>



<p><strong>BIC: Now, questions from the Community <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f5a4.png" alt="🖤" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />@HancerBurakk: </strong><em>How does AlgosOne plan to leverage advancements in generative AI or natural language processing to enhance user interaction and trading insights on the platform?</em></p>



<p><em>With the rise of competing AI-trading platforms, what unique value proposition does AlgosOne offer to ensure it remains the preferred choice for both retail and institutional traders?</em></p>



<p><em>Looking ahead, how does AlgosOne envision the role of AI in shaping the future of decentralized finance, and what steps is the platform taking to lead this transformation?</em></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>AlgosOne is committed to leveraging advancements in generative AI and natural language processing (NLP) to enhance user interaction and provide sophisticated trading insights. By integrating generative AI, AlgosOne enables the platform to deliver personalized, real-time market analysis and trade recommendations that are tailored to individual trader preferences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through NLP, the platform can analyze and process vast amounts of unstructured data, such as news articles, financial reports, and social media sentiment, to uncover actionable insights that would otherwise be challenging for traders to detect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This allows traders to make informed decisions more quickly and with higher confidence, improving both their experience and performance on the platform.</p>



<p>As the competition in the AI trading space intensifies, AlgosOne stands out with its unique value proposition of combining cutting-edge AI capabilities with a user-friendly interface and institutional-grade algorithms. The platform’s hybrid model caters to both retail and institutional traders, allowing users to fine-tune strategies in real-time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AlgosOne also emphasizes security and transparency, ensuring that users can trust the platform for high-performance, risk-managed trading in an environment that supports the latest AI technologies.</p>



<p>Looking to the future, AlgosOne envisions AI playing a central role in the evolution of decentralized finance (DeFi). The platform aims to be a key enabler of AI-powered smart contracts, decentralized autonomous trading strategies, and data-driven decision-making across blockchain ecosystems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By advancing AI integration into DeFi protocols, AlgosOne is positioning itself at the forefront of this transformation. Steps are already underway to incorporate AI-driven risk management tools, optimize liquidity pools, and enhance smart contract security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By aligning with the decentralized ethos of DeFi while offering robust AI-powered features, AlgosOne is ensuring it remains a pioneer in shaping the future of financial markets in a decentralized world.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: @Rebbecacamp1993:</strong> <em>A user reportedly earned $500K with AlgosOne. What were the key factors (e.g., starting capital, trade frequency, asset selection) behind this outlier result? How typical is this for average users?</em></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>The impressive $500K earnings resulted from several key factors working together. Understanding these elements provides insight into how such high returns are possible.</p>



<p>A larger starting capital is a major advantage, as higher-tier users can leverage AlgosOne’s automated trading system and high-yield plans more effectively. The platform’s AI-driven automation ensures that trades are executed optimally, maximizing returns while minimizing risks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Users who opt for fully automated trading allow the system to analyze market trends and execute trades seamlessly, while those who prefer one-click trades can retain some control by approving transactions manually.</p>



<p>The high-yield plan plays a crucial role in accelerating profit growth. Users can double their investment in under a year, especially when profits are compounded efficiently.</p>



<p>While such results are typically seen among higher-tier users with substantial capital, AlgosOne provides a powerful AI-driven system that enables users at all levels to grow their investments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Actual results will depend on factors such as starting capital, chosen plan, and risk strategy, but the platform’s automation and smart trading strategies create a strong foundation for achieving significant financial growth.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: @VenusGiron40: </strong><em>What role does automation play in AlgosOne’s AI trading platform, and how does it help traders mitigate risks and maximize returns in volatile market conditions?</em></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>Automation is the core of AlgosOne’s AI trading system, enabling traders to navigate volatile markets with precision, efficiency, and risk control. The platform’s AI-driven automation ensures that trades are executed optimally, minimizing human error and maximizing returns.</p>



<p>Real-Time Market Analysis – AI continuously scans markets, identifying profitable trades in milliseconds based on price action, sentiment, and historical patterns.</p>



<p>Automated Trade Execution – Depending on the chosen plan, trades are either fully automated (executed instantly) or one-click approved, ensuring traders don’t miss opportunities.</p>



<p>Risk Mitigation – AI applies dynamic stop-loss, portfolio rebalancing, and volatility-based trade adjustments, protecting users from excessive market swings.</p>



<p>Compounded Profits – Automated reinvestment strategies allow users to compound gains efficiently, particularly when using high-yield plans.</p>



<p>Emotional Trading Elimination – By removing human bias, automation ensures traders stick to data-driven strategies, avoiding impulsive decisions in volatile conditions.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: @VictoryBuiTR: </strong><em>The AiAO token is an integral part of the AlgosOne ecosystem. How does it function within the platform, and what are its key utilities, such as staking, governance, or enhancing AI-trading capabilities?</em></p>



<p><strong>Alex: </strong>The AIAO token is set to become the foundation of the AlgosOne ecosystem, providing users with enhanced AI-driven trading capabilities, governance influence, and financial benefits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Once launched, traders will be able to purchase AIAO and take advantage of its potential price appreciation, dividend rewards, and staking opportunities. Additionally, AIAO holders will play a role in shaping the platform’s future through governance, allowing them to vote on AI model enhancements and system upgrades.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond trading, the token serves as an investment opportunity, with early adopters positioned to benefit as demand for AIAO grows. Ultimately, AIAO will drive AlgosOne’s evolution, merging AI automation with decentralized finance to create a smarter, more profitable trading experience.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: @LittleXiaYuann: </strong><em>Security and regulatory compliance are critical in the AI-trading space. AlgosOne is licensed in the EU and partners with top-tier financial institutions. Can you provide details on how this licensing enhances platform security, user trust, and the overall legitimacy of its financial services?</em></p>



<p><strong>Alex</strong>: Security and regulatory compliance are fundamental to AlgosOne’s mission of providing a safe, transparent, and trustworthy AI trading platform. Being licensed in the EU and partnering with top-tier financial institutions ensures that AlgosOne meets the highest regulatory and security standards, giving users confidence in its financial services.</p>



<p>EU licensing means that AlgosOne operates under strict financial regulations, including anti-money laundering (AML), know-your-customer (KYC), and data protection laws. These measures prevent fraudulent activities, safeguard user funds, and ensure that all trading operations are conducted transparently.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, compliance with financial authorities enhances platform legitimacy, attracting both retail and institutional traders who seek a secure and regulated trading environment.</p>



<p>Beyond compliance, AlgosOne’s partnerships with top-tier financial institutions further reinforce security. These partnerships provide custodial protection for user funds, secure payment processing, and liquidity access, ensuring seamless and reliable transactions. Combined with AI-driven risk management, these safeguards protect users from market volatility and potential security threats.</p>



<p>By adhering to global financial regulations, leveraging institutional partnerships, and implementing advanced security measures, AlgosOne establishes itself as a trusted leader in AI-powered trading, offering users both profitability and peace of mind.</p>



<p><strong>BIC: Great! Alex, thank you for being here today!</strong></p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>The AMA session with Alex Andera provided valuable insights into how AlgosOne is changing AI-driven trading. By combining advanced AI algorithms with user-friendly automation, the platform empowers both beginners and experienced traders to optimize their strategies effortlessly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From its support for various assets to the emphasis on security and compliance, AlgosOne positions itself as a reliable choice when it comes to AI crypto trading. As the platform continues to evolve, it aims to integrate even more innovative features, making the tool even more all-round.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Whether you’re new to trading or looking to enhance your portfolio management, AlgosOne’s platform might be worth exploring.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/algosone-beincrypto-ama-session/">AlgosOne X BeInCrypto AMA Session</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AlgosOne.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/AlgosOne.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 07:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Justin Sun once again set the crypto world abuzz. As reported by CoinDesk, Sun stepped in with a critical injection of liquidity to support TrueUSD (TUSD) amid a staggering $456 million reserve gap—averting a potential depegging crisis that could have rocked the stablecoin ecosystem. &#8220;Godzilla was destroying the city. I’m Ultraman—I came in and punched &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Justin Sun once again set the crypto world abuzz. As reported by CoinDesk, Sun stepped in with a critical injection of liquidity to support TrueUSD (TUSD) amid a staggering $456 million reserve gap—averting a potential depegging crisis that could have rocked the stablecoin ecosystem.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Godzilla was destroying the city. I’m Ultraman—I came in and punched Godzilla to save everyone,&#8221; Sun told Hong Kong media outlet Sing Tao Daily, in his trademark flair.</p>



<p>But behind the theatrics lies a much graver mission. Sun is taking on the alleged fraud by First Digital Trust (FDT) and its affiliated partners, urging Hong Kong regulators &amp; and law enforcement agencies to take decisive measures to address these loopholes.&nbsp; &#8220;These assets are essentially public users’ money,&#8221; he said. &#8220;To protect users and uphold Hong Kong’s credibility as a global financial hub, I had to step in. The scale of the fraud shocked me. All fraudsters must be held accountable.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>To accelerate the investigation and bring resolution to the incident, Sun also announced a <a href="https://x.com/justinsuntron/status/1908126661075476688" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$50 million bounty program</a> for anyone who can provide crucial leads. “This isn’t just about money,” he added. “It’s about justice for the Web3 industry.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zh" dir="ltr">(1/3)<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />5000万美元悬赏计划 &#8211; First Digital Trust诈骗案<br><br>本人正式宣布：将设立5000万美元悬赏计划（约相当于本人提供的流动性支持或被盗TUSD储备金的10%），用于追回被First Digital Trust（FDT）等不法分子非法挪用的TUSD储备金。</p>&mdash; H.E. Justin Sun <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f34c.png" alt="🍌" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@justinsuntron) <a href="https://twitter.com/justinsuntron/status/1908136107377594454?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-relentless-defender-of-crypto"><strong>A Relentless Defender of Crypto</strong></h2>



<p>Crypto has always been a volatile adventure. Bull runs feel like reaching for the stars, while crashes leave only wreckage. But in these uncertain times, Justin Sun has made it his role to keep the lights on. He’s not just a survivor—he’s a watchman. Someone who shows up when others hesitate.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-ethereum-showdown-twice-tested-never-broken"><strong>The Ethereum Showdown: Twice Tested, Never Broken</strong></h2>



<p>Sun’s relationship with Ethereum has been nothing short of a saga.</p>



<p>During the infamous May 19, 2021 crash, ETH dipped below $2,000 and Sun was inches away from liquidation. He repaid $300 million just in time to protect his 606,000 ETH position and threw in another $280 million to buy more ETH and BTC at fire-sale prices.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My assets were safe, but it felt like a bullet grazed my scalp. The wick was brutal,” he wrote on Weibo. It wasn’t just a trade. It was a battle of conviction. He shielded his own position while keeping the crypto dream alive.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In 2024, ETH lagged in performance and Sun faced fresh rumors of massive losses and sell-offs. Instead of retreating, he proposed bold plans: Halt ETH Sales, heavily tax Layer 2 solutions, streamline foundation &amp; optimize revenue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wild? Maybe. But Sun has always married ambition with execution.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-reviving-htx-from-burnout-to-breakout"><strong>Reviving HTX: From Burnout to Breakout</strong></h2>



<p>Critics once joked that Sun &#8220;got burned&#8221; buying into HTX (formerly Huobi). When he stepped in as Global Advisor in October 2022, the market was reeling from FTX’s collapse, and centralized exchanges were under siege. HTX had lost ground—and users.</p>



<p>Today, HTX is thriving. Trading volume and user activity are up, euro-stablecoin trading is on top three globally, and its CIS market share is dominant. It even made Forbes’ list of &#8220;<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/javierpaz/2025/01/28/the-worlds-most-trustworthy-crypto-exchanges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Top 25 Most Trustworthy Crypto Exchanges of 2025</a>.&#8221;</p>



<p>The same exchange that once looked like a liability? Now a pillar of Sun’s empire.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ftx-fallout-standing-in-the-storm"><strong>FTX Fallout: Standing in the Storm</strong></h2>



<p>When FTX collapsed in November 2022, chaos swept the markets. Sun publicly pledged to support TRON-related tokens and HT assets with 1:1 redemption. He even told Bloomberg he was prepared to inject &#8220;billions&#8221; to help FTX, subject to due diligence.</p>



<p>FTX ultimately folded, but Sun’s swift move bought time for users and preserved value within the TRON and HTX ecosystems.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-curve-crisis-defi-gets-a-lifeline"><strong>The Curve Crisis: DeFi Gets a Lifeline</strong></h2>



<p>DeFi’s fragility was exposed again in 2023 when Curve Finance was hacked. Founder Michael Egorov faced possible liquidation on $100M in loans. As CRV tanked, Sun and allies stepped in, purchasing 72 million CRV for $28.8 million to shore up the protocol.</p>



<p>He didn’t stop there—Sun launched a stUSDT pool on TRON, giving the ecosystem a boost. Some say it was strategic self-interest. But in a storm, does it matter who holds the umbrella, as long as someone does?</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-controversial-but-unshaken"><strong>Controversial but Unshaken</strong></h2>



<p>Sun’s name always invites debate. Opportunist or idealist? Visionary or self-promoter? The truth probably lies somewhere in between. Yes, he’s bold. Yes, he’s ambitious. But when others flee, he steps forward.</p>



<p>From converting $HT to $HTX, to partnering with WLFI on reserve-backed assets, Sun continues to bet on crypto’s long-term future. “I’m not here to make a quick buck,” he once said. “I want to build something that lasts.&#8221;</p>



<p>Love him or not, in the darkest hours of Web3, Justin Sun has made a habit of showing up with a flashlight.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-04-16.19.23.jpeg" medium="image" width="1280" height="854" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-04-16.19.23.jpeg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CZ Makes Rare Hong Kong Appearance: &#8220;I Don&#8217;t Trade Crypto Much&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/cz-hong-kong-appearance-doesnt-trade-crypto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 16:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao made a rare public appearance in Hong Kong Sunday, revealing he rarely trades cryptocurrency despite founding the world&#8217;s largest exchanges. The appearance was particularly noteworthy as Zhao recently denied reports he would attend another Hong Kong crypto event on April 8. His presence at both the BNB Super Meetup and &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/cz-hong-kong-appearance-doesnt-trade-crypto/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/cz-hong-kong-appearance-doesnt-trade-crypto/">CZ Makes Rare Hong Kong Appearance: &#8220;I Don&#8217;t Trade Crypto Much&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Former Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao made a rare public appearance in Hong Kong Sunday, revealing he rarely trades cryptocurrency despite founding the world&#8217;s largest exchanges.</strong></p>



<p>The appearance was particularly noteworthy as Zhao recently <a href="https://x.com/cz_binance/status/1904802691655884952" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">denied</a> reports he would attend another Hong Kong crypto event on April 8. His presence at both the BNB Super Meetup and the MVB 9th event generated significant attention in the crypto community.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="765" height="498" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-45.png" alt="" class="wp-image-683814" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-45.png 765w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-45-360x234.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-45-150x98.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 765px) 100vw, 765px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">CZ talking with Justin Sun at a BNB event in Hong Kong. Source:X(joezhoublack)</figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-market-concerns-and-investment-advice">Market Concerns and Investment Advice</h2>



<p>&#8220;The industry is not particularly healthy right now,&#8221; Zhao said during the <a href="https://x.com/BNBCHAIN/status/1908824195439743217" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BNB Super Meetup</a>, criticizing excessive focus on meme coins. &#8220;We&#8217;re putting too much attention on quick gains.&#8221;</p>



<p>In a surprising admission, Zhao said, &#8220;I don&#8217;t speculate much. I don&#8217;t trade crypto much. I haven&#8217;t bought any meme coins.&#8221;</p>



<p>Zhao, worth approximately $66.6 billion, suggested several dozen to &#8220;over a hundred&#8221; cryptocurrencies could potentially outperform Bitcoin long-term, while emphasizing Bitcoin remains the most stable investment.</p>



<p>For newcomers, he recommended a disciplined approach &#8220;I strongly recommend young people invest a small amount each month that you can afford to lose,&#8221; he advised, endorsing <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/dollar-cost-averaging/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">dollar-cost averaging</a>. &#8220;There&#8217;s no bad time to enter the market, but how you enter is very important.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-past-mistakes">Past Mistakes</h2>



<p>Zhao acknowledged <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-community-fears-for-binance-bnb-as-ftt-is-declared-security/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">mistakes</a> in Binance&#8217;s approach to DeFi, admitting he failed to give proper attention to the BNB ecosystem while dealing with US legal issues.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;We didn&#8217;t focus enough on the BNB ecosystem. This was a big mistake.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>When asked about BNB&#8217;s future value, Zhao avoided specific predictions but emphasized that expanding use cases would naturally increase its value.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-personal-life">Personal Life</h2>



<p>Zhao revealed numerous countries now seek his blockchain advice, including the UAE, United States, Hong Kong, Thailand, Malaysia, and Japan. &#8220;Now countries need us, and we can support them,&#8221; he said.</p>



<p>In a separate interview with Tron founder Justin Sun, Zhao discussed his digital education project aimed at providing free content to children worldwide. &#8220;With about $300 million, we could digitize 18 years of education across 30 subjects,&#8221; he explained.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Looked who stopped by at <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MVB9?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MVB9</a> <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f440.png" alt="👀" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /><br><br>Great to see <a href="https://twitter.com/cz_binance?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@cz_binance</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">@VitalikButerin</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/InsideMVB?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#InsideMVB</a> and thanks for coming! <a href="https://t.co/gzrWtBIQyb">pic.twitter.com/gzrWtBIQyb</a></p>&mdash; BNB Chain (@BNBCHAIN) <a href="https://twitter.com/BNBCHAIN/status/1908812241538867227?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 6, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>Before the Super Meetup, Zhao appeared alongside Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin at BNB Chain&#8217;s MVB 9th event, where 16 projects were selected for an acceleration program.</p>



<p>When asked about his daily routine, Zhao said he typically works from bed due to back problems and enjoys kitesurfing in his free time. &#8220;Most of my time is spent working from bed because my back isn&#8217;t great,&#8221; he shared.</p>



<p>He <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binances-changpeng-zhao-release-bnb-gains/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">completed</a> a four-month prison sentence in September 2024 after <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-changpeng-zhao-sentenced-to-prison/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">pleading guilty</a> to U.S. federal charges related to money laundering. Binance paid $4.3 billion in fines, while Zhao personally paid $50 million.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/cz-hong-kong-appearance-doesnt-trade-crypto/">CZ Makes Rare Hong Kong Appearance: &#8220;I Don&#8217;t Trade Crypto Much&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/binance-ceo-changpeng-cz-zhao.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/binance-ceo-changpeng-cz-zhao.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain Financial Innovation Critical for Next Industrial Revolution, Says HashKey Chair</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-financial-innovation-industrial-revolution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Oihyun Kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 05:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683716</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>HashKey Group Chairman and CEO Xiao Feng kicked off the 2025 Hong Kong Web3 Festival on Sunday with a keynote address highlighting blockchain technology&#8217;s transformative impact on global financial infrastructure. Speaking to an early morning crowd at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Center, Xiao described blockchain as &#8220;a new generation of financial infrastructure&#8221; that &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-financial-innovation-industrial-revolution/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-financial-innovation-industrial-revolution/">Blockchain Financial Innovation Critical for Next Industrial Revolution, Says HashKey Chair</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong><a href="https://beincrypto.com/hashkey-group-2025-predictions/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">HashKey Group</a> Chairman and CEO Xiao Feng kicked off the 2025 Hong Kong <a href="https://www.web3festival.org/hongkong2025/#/en" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web3 Festival</a> on Sunday with a keynote address highlighting blockchain technology&#8217;s transformative impact on global financial infrastructure.</strong></p>



<p>Speaking to an early morning crowd at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Center, Xiao described blockchain as &#8220;a new generation of financial infrastructure&#8221; that fundamentally changes how financial transactions are recorded, settled and governed.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-industrial-revolution-requires-financial-innovation">Industrial Revolution Requires Financial Innovation</h2>



<p>&#8220;Any industrial revolution must wait for a financial revolution,&#8221; Xiao told attendees at the four-day event hosted by his company.</p>



<p>Xiao emphasized historical parallels between technological and financial evolution: banking credit supported the British Industrial Revolution, stock markets enabled the electrical revolution in America, and venture capital fueled Silicon Valley&#8217;s information revolution.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Cryptocurrency finance will become the core financial innovation supporting the fourth industrial revolution.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The executive highlighted key differences between traditional and blockchain-based finance, including the shift from bank accounts to digital wallets and the move from batch settlement systems to instantaneous transaction completion.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-regulatory-changes-and-market-evolution">Regulatory Changes and Market Evolution</h2>



<p>Xiao noted the significance of the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission&#8217;s recent decision not to classify dollar-backed stablecoins as securities, suggesting this allows more institutions to participate in monetary creation processes.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="567" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-850x567.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-683717" style="width:1025px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-850x567.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-360x240.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-768x512.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/XiaoFeng_Hashkey-150x100.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">HashKey Group Chairman and CEO Xiao Feng at Keynote speech of 2025 Hong Kong Web3 Festival. Courtesy of Web3 Festival</figcaption></figure>



<p>He also pointed to major stock exchanges moving toward 23-hour trading cycles, compared to blockchain markets that operate continuously.</p>



<p>&#8220;Traditional exchanges will eventually need to adapt to compete with cryptocurrency markets that have operated 24/7 since day one,&#8221; Xiao predicted.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-hong-kong-s-strategic-role">Hong Kong&#8217;s Strategic Role</h2>



<p>The event features several high-profile regulators, including Paul Chan Mo-po, Financial Secretary of the Hong Kong Government; Joseph H. L. Chan, Under Secretary for Financial Services and the Treasury; Christina Choi, Executive Director of Investment Products at the Securities and Futures Commission; and George Chou, Chief Fintech Officer of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority.</p>



<p>While mainland China maintains strict prohibitions on cryptocurrencies, analysts view Hong Kong&#8217;s supportive stance as a strategic testing ground for the technology&#8217;s potential. This approach effectively <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hong-kong-accelerates-crypto-licensing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">creates a regulatory breathing space</a> where blockchain innovations can develop under controlled conditions, potentially informing future policies across the broader Chinese economy.</p>



<p>The Web3 Festival continues through Wednesday with industry panels, demonstrations and networking events, bringing together blockchain developers, investors and technology enthusiasts from around the world.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-financial-innovation-industrial-revolution/">Blockchain Financial Innovation Critical for Next Industrial Revolution, Says HashKey Chair</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/BIC_HongKong_negative.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/BIC_HongKong_negative.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Circle Reportedly Delays IPO Amid Market Turmoil Sparked by Trump’s Trade War</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/circle-ipo-delayed-trump-tariffs-market-turmoil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mohammad Shahid]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stablecoin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDC News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683565</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Circle, the issuer of the USDC stablecoin, has reportedly delayed its plans to go public. This is due to the growing financial market instability triggered by Trump’s sweeping import tariffs and China’s earlier retaliation.&#160; Multiple sources have claimed that the company has paused its IPO preparations. However, no official confirmation has been issued by Circle. &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/circle-ipo-delayed-trump-tariffs-market-turmoil/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/circle-ipo-delayed-trump-tariffs-market-turmoil/">Circle Reportedly Delays IPO Amid Market Turmoil Sparked by Trump’s Trade War</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Circle, the issuer of the USDC stablecoin, has reportedly delayed its plans to go public. This is due to the growing financial market instability triggered by Trump’s sweeping import tariffs and China’s earlier retaliation.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Multiple sources have claimed that the company has paused its IPO preparations. However, no official confirmation has been issued by Circle.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-circle-is-not-going-public-yet">Circle is Not Going Public Yet</h2>



<p>The alleged decision places Circle among a growing list of high-profile firms—including Klarna and StubHub—that have <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-04-04/klarna-stubhub-pause-ipo-plans-after-trump-tariffs-roil-markets" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">shelved</a> initial public offering plans today.&nbsp;All three had <a href="https://beincrypto.com/circle-files-for-ipo/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">confidentially filed with the SEC</a> and were preparing to begin investor roadshows this quarter.</p>



<p>The retreat comes as financial markets reel from the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">impact of a blanket 10% tariff on all imports</a>, announced earlier this week. </p>



<p>The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-recession-fears-grow-nasdaq-dow-falls/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq both posted their steepest declines</a> in over a year. Volatility indexes spiked, creating an unfavorable environment for IPO pricing and institutional appetite.</p>



<p>For Circle, the supposed delay carries broader implications. <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-10-year-treasury-yield-bitcoin-appeal/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Unlike Tether</a>, Circle’s strategy <a href="https://beincrypto.com/usdc-stablecoin-japan-approval/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">hinges on securing global regulatory approval</a> and institutional trust. </p>



<p>Its push for transparency, compliance, and public listing was seen as a pathway to cement USDC’s status as a stablecoin preferred by banks, payment processors, and tokenized asset platforms.</p>



<p>However, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-recovery-trump-liberation-day/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">global trade disruptions</a> and the strengthening dollar have introduced new risks. USDC’s dollar peg could become a point of pressure if geopolitical instability continues. </p>



<p>This is especially a concern in jurisdictions with growing <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-future-amid-trump-tariffs/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">skepticism toward US-centric financial infrastructure</a>.</p>



<p>While the company has yet to comment on the IPO status, market observers say the delay reflects a recalibration across the fintech and crypto sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Overall, Circle’s pause mirrors a broader hesitancy. Markets are pricing in policy risk again, and companies with cross-border exposure are reassessing.</p>



<p>Circle’s IPO had been positioned as a bellwether for maturing crypto companies entering the public markets. Its postponement marks another signal that the trade war’s fallout is rippling far beyond traditional equities.</p>



<p>BeInCrypto has contacted Circle to confirm the reports but is yet to receive an official response.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/circle-ipo-delayed-trump-tariffs-market-turmoil/">Circle Reportedly Delays IPO Amid Market Turmoil Sparked by Trump’s Trade War</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bic_Circle_Internet_Financial_3-covers_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/bic_Circle_Internet_Financial_3-covers_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
