<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Sponsored Archives - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/sponsored/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/sponsored/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 07:25:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Sponsored Archives - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/sponsored/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 07:25:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683968</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Justin Sun once again set the crypto world abuzz. As reported by CoinDesk, Sun stepped in with a critical injection of liquidity to support TrueUSD (TUSD) amid a staggering $456 million reserve gap—averting a potential depegging crisis that could have rocked the stablecoin ecosystem. &#8220;Godzilla was destroying the city. I’m Ultraman—I came in and punched &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Justin Sun once again set the crypto world abuzz. As reported by CoinDesk, Sun stepped in with a critical injection of liquidity to support TrueUSD (TUSD) amid a staggering $456 million reserve gap—averting a potential depegging crisis that could have rocked the stablecoin ecosystem.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Godzilla was destroying the city. I’m Ultraman—I came in and punched Godzilla to save everyone,&#8221; Sun told Hong Kong media outlet Sing Tao Daily, in his trademark flair.</p>



<p>But behind the theatrics lies a much graver mission. Sun is taking on the alleged fraud by First Digital Trust (FDT) and its affiliated partners, urging Hong Kong regulators &amp; and law enforcement agencies to take decisive measures to address these loopholes.&nbsp; &#8220;These assets are essentially public users’ money,&#8221; he said. &#8220;To protect users and uphold Hong Kong’s credibility as a global financial hub, I had to step in. The scale of the fraud shocked me. All fraudsters must be held accountable.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>To accelerate the investigation and bring resolution to the incident, Sun also announced a <a href="https://x.com/justinsuntron/status/1908126661075476688" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$50 million bounty program</a> for anyone who can provide crucial leads. “This isn’t just about money,” he added. “It’s about justice for the Web3 industry.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="500" data-dnt="true"><p lang="zh" dir="ltr">(1/3)<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f6a8.png" alt="🚨" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />5000万美元悬赏计划 &#8211; First Digital Trust诈骗案<br><br>本人正式宣布：将设立5000万美元悬赏计划（约相当于本人提供的流动性支持或被盗TUSD储备金的10%），用于追回被First Digital Trust（FDT）等不法分子非法挪用的TUSD储备金。</p>&mdash; H.E. Justin Sun <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/15.0.3/72x72/1f34c.png" alt="🍌" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /> (@justinsuntron) <a href="https://twitter.com/justinsuntron/status/1908136107377594454?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">April 4, 2025</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-relentless-defender-of-crypto"><strong>A Relentless Defender of Crypto</strong></h2>



<p>Crypto has always been a volatile adventure. Bull runs feel like reaching for the stars, while crashes leave only wreckage. But in these uncertain times, Justin Sun has made it his role to keep the lights on. He’s not just a survivor—he’s a watchman. Someone who shows up when others hesitate.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-ethereum-showdown-twice-tested-never-broken"><strong>The Ethereum Showdown: Twice Tested, Never Broken</strong></h2>



<p>Sun’s relationship with Ethereum has been nothing short of a saga.</p>



<p>During the infamous May 19, 2021 crash, ETH dipped below $2,000 and Sun was inches away from liquidation. He repaid $300 million just in time to protect his 606,000 ETH position and threw in another $280 million to buy more ETH and BTC at fire-sale prices.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“My assets were safe, but it felt like a bullet grazed my scalp. The wick was brutal,” he wrote on Weibo. It wasn’t just a trade. It was a battle of conviction. He shielded his own position while keeping the crypto dream alive.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In 2024, ETH lagged in performance and Sun faced fresh rumors of massive losses and sell-offs. Instead of retreating, he proposed bold plans: Halt ETH Sales, heavily tax Layer 2 solutions, streamline foundation &amp; optimize revenue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wild? Maybe. But Sun has always married ambition with execution.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-reviving-htx-from-burnout-to-breakout"><strong>Reviving HTX: From Burnout to Breakout</strong></h2>



<p>Critics once joked that Sun &#8220;got burned&#8221; buying into HTX (formerly Huobi). When he stepped in as Global Advisor in October 2022, the market was reeling from FTX’s collapse, and centralized exchanges were under siege. HTX had lost ground—and users.</p>



<p>Today, HTX is thriving. Trading volume and user activity are up, euro-stablecoin trading is on top three globally, and its CIS market share is dominant. It even made Forbes’ list of &#8220;<a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/javierpaz/2025/01/28/the-worlds-most-trustworthy-crypto-exchanges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Top 25 Most Trustworthy Crypto Exchanges of 2025</a>.&#8221;</p>



<p>The same exchange that once looked like a liability? Now a pillar of Sun’s empire.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-ftx-fallout-standing-in-the-storm"><strong>FTX Fallout: Standing in the Storm</strong></h2>



<p>When FTX collapsed in November 2022, chaos swept the markets. Sun publicly pledged to support TRON-related tokens and HT assets with 1:1 redemption. He even told Bloomberg he was prepared to inject &#8220;billions&#8221; to help FTX, subject to due diligence.</p>



<p>FTX ultimately folded, but Sun’s swift move bought time for users and preserved value within the TRON and HTX ecosystems.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-curve-crisis-defi-gets-a-lifeline"><strong>The Curve Crisis: DeFi Gets a Lifeline</strong></h2>



<p>DeFi’s fragility was exposed again in 2023 when Curve Finance was hacked. Founder Michael Egorov faced possible liquidation on $100M in loans. As CRV tanked, Sun and allies stepped in, purchasing 72 million CRV for $28.8 million to shore up the protocol.</p>



<p>He didn’t stop there—Sun launched a stUSDT pool on TRON, giving the ecosystem a boost. Some say it was strategic self-interest. But in a storm, does it matter who holds the umbrella, as long as someone does?</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-controversial-but-unshaken"><strong>Controversial but Unshaken</strong></h2>



<p>Sun’s name always invites debate. Opportunist or idealist? Visionary or self-promoter? The truth probably lies somewhere in between. Yes, he’s bold. Yes, he’s ambitious. But when others flee, he steps forward.</p>



<p>From converting $HT to $HTX, to partnering with WLFI on reserve-backed assets, Sun continues to bet on crypto’s long-term future. “I’m not here to make a quick buck,” he once said. “I want to build something that lasts.&#8221;</p>



<p>Love him or not, in the darkest hours of Web3, Justin Sun has made a habit of showing up with a flashlight.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/justin-sun-web3-watchman-crypto-ultraman-financial-godzilla/">The Ultraman of Crypto vs. Financial Godzilla: Justin Sun, the Watchman of Web3</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-04-16.19.23.jpeg" medium="image" width="1280" height="854" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/photo_2025-04-04-16.19.23.jpeg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This AI Trading Bot Is Profiting on Bitcoin Records, While It’s Still Available to the Public</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/ai-trading-bot-profiting-bitcoin-records/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 07:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a bold move, the popular AI trading powerhouse, AlgosOne, has rejected a series of  acquisition offers ranging from $250 to $500, from leading global investment firms and tech giants. Instead, the project leadership is doubling down, and betting big on its upcoming AIAO token launch, later this quarter, which promises to give the opportunity &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ai-trading-bot-profiting-bitcoin-records/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ai-trading-bot-profiting-bitcoin-records/">This AI Trading Bot Is Profiting on Bitcoin Records, While It’s Still Available to the Public</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a bold move, the popular AI trading powerhouse, <a href="https://algosone.ai?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a115.040425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AlgosOne</a>, has rejected a series of  acquisition offers ranging from $250 to $500, from leading global investment firms and tech giants. Instead, the project leadership is doubling down, and betting big on its upcoming AIAO token launch, later this quarter, which promises to give the opportunity for lucrative returns for its early investors. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-algosone-turns-down-major-industry-players-nbsp">AlgosOne Turns Down Major Industry Players&nbsp;</h2>



<p>Since the start of 2025 major global hedge funds and AI firms across Japan, China, Russia, and the United States have made buyout bids but the company has stayed steadfast in its refusal to sell.&nbsp;</p>



<p>According to AlgosOne CMO Alex Andera, the company is confident in its ability to independently reach a valuation that exceeds all these offers, particularly in light of the launch of the platform’s native token, AIAO, in a few weeks. Token holders will benefit from&nbsp; governance rights and partial ownership of the AI model, receiving regular dividend payouts on platform revenues and this democratization of the financial AI space is central to AlgosOne’s values.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXc8ius3UaFkyipMFYB8FnUV_htZIv56ogCszahG442xzdpNfJOxpx0shWL0TZxDQ7VuX1xpt91TJBtsXzOr856d3MJwp2THgnkEcL5BmyNwcx5Q6LpgdxnYE1OoYslgNbdx_i1rBE8Q4kmFbaiUtRs?key=k_dHGY-aZedErv15e2gTiRPB" alt=""/></figure>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;<em>Rather than a large conglomerate, we want our token holders to own the project and direct its future,</em>&#8221; states Andera. &#8220;<em>By remaining independent, we&#8217;re reinforcing our dedication to decentralization and user ownership.</em>&#8220;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Even SoftBank, which made a trillion-yen investment in OpenAI earlier this year, couldn&#8217;t tempt the trading platform to sell. This decision speaks volumes about AlgosOne&#8217;s belief in its growth trajectory and the immense potential of its proprietary AI trading technology.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-why-algosone-is-dominating-the-ai-trading-space">Why AlgosOne Is Dominating the AI Trading Space</h2>



<p>Since AlgosOne hit the market in 2022, with its next-generation machine-learning algorithm, it has become the go-to AI for retail traders by delivering consistent profits. In fact, at the end of December, 2024, when the first 24-month contracts matured, every single trading plan met or exceeded profit projections, with some users seeing returns as high as 250%!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXeJ7wcDxDm3hdiymfrQpG44YWEfJdDuDfEiKS0a94go_RKZINTOCUtn_B8XtCrz43L191x4KLXbdHrPqmDPn6EJDR07FLtObWHMrM5DFXVKf_2VKkdR6X2TrZSMEoEOlYQKWAr7ZkIqar7biab7m2g?key=k_dHGY-aZedErv15e2gTiRPB" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Online opinions have been overwhelmingly positive, and it has an excellent <a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/algosone.ai?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a115.040425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 4.7 Trustpilot rating</a>, with thousands of traders posting enthusiastic reviews.</p>



<p>So what exactly sets the platform apart in what is now quite a crowded field?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Proven performance:</strong> The AI has sustained an impressive 80%+ trade win rate for 2 years straight</li>



<li><strong>Real accessibility:</strong>  The minimum deposit is just $300 and no coding or financial experience is needed- you just sign up, deposit and the AI takes over </li>



<li><strong>An attractive fee structure: </strong>There are no spreads, registration, deposit, trading or inactivity fees—just a commission, which is only charged on winning trades</li>



<li><strong>Regulatory compliance</strong>: AlgosOne is a fully licensed platform with a Reserve Fund offering complete client capital coverage<br></li>
</ul>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-aiao-token-sale-what-to-expect">The AIAO Token Sale: What to Expect</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-aiao-token-sale-will-be-structured-as-follows">The AIAO token sale will be structured as follows:</h3>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>The Presale</strong><strong><br></strong>This will include 16 rounds, in which  65% of the 1 billion token supply will be available for purchase &#8211;<strong> </strong><strong><em>exclusively to AlgosOne users</em></strong>. A number of private sales will also be conducted, in advance of select presale rounds.<br></li>



<li><strong>The Public Sale</strong><br>25% of the token supply will be made available, with AlgosOne committing to purchase $100M worth of AIAO, during the public sale stage.<br></li>



<li><strong>Exchange Listing</strong><br>This is the final phase offering  widespread availability, where the token will be tradable on major crypto exchanges </li>
</ol>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-nbsp-nbsp-why-become-an-early-adopter">&nbsp;&nbsp;Why Become an Early Adopter?</h2>



<p><a href="https://algosone.ai/aiao-presale?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a115.040425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The AIAO presale </a>will kick off  in the second half of Q2, 2025, and the token will offer multiple utilities and revenue opportunities for registered AlgosOne users:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-certain-price-appreciation"><strong>Certain Price Appreciation</strong></h3>



<p>With a guaranteed minimum 50% price increase at the start of each of the 16 presale rounds, this works out as a 437X return on investment for those who bought AIAO at the very start.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-steady-dividend-payments"><strong>Steady Dividend Payments</strong></h3>



<p>A major reason to join the token sale is that&nbsp; AIAO holders will get partial ownership of the project, receiving regular dividends based on AlgosOne&#8217;s growing revenues, paid directly into their checking accounts in USD. With a rapidly growing global userbase, tens of thousands of new users are joining the AI trading platform annually, so dividend payouts are projected to see a massive increase over time.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-project-governance-rights"><strong>Project Governance Rights</strong></h3>



<p>Token holders will have voting power, with the right to participate in strategic decisions relating to the platform&#8217;s future direction. More tokens will translate to greater influence.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-trading-points"><strong>Trading Points</strong></h3>



<p>AIAO holders receive trading points that determine their<a href="https://algosone.ai/trading?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a115.040425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> trading tier</a>. Upgrading to a higher tier means more daily trades for bigger sums, higher profit percentages, and lower commission fees on winning trades.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfLcG05e8D9ZPAdkIL_ygIjWQp3f-dyEwmm467jUe-HjD3GvfUTJi8xhPJaOLuk59gVHhqMic2L6-9sC1et-9uEiiGb7GzNaUf9ofwOVmMZ-wx2eTHdIxhGimGNQHVbWj7_w9jHkFDxNvW8ofXxn54?key=k_dHGY-aZedErv15e2gTiRPB" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Many industry players that made buyout bids are now scrambling to acquire large allocations of tokens, which is a testament to the industry consensus on AlgosOne and the AIAO token’s Impressive growth potential. It’s no surprise that AlgosOne has backed itself, since the AIAO token launch is on track to be one of the most promising launches of 2025. Want to get in on the ground floor? Well you’d better move fast. To maximize profits and qualify to participate in the presale, you need to <a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a115.040425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">sign up with AlgosOne</a>, complete KYC verification, and fund your account before the sale begins later this quarter. Also, if you actively engage with the platform, you’ll become eligible to receive free AIAO tokens in the retrodrop.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/ai-trading-bot-profiting-bitcoin-records/">This AI Trading Bot Is Profiting on Bitcoin Records, While It’s Still Available to the Public</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/cover-1-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1400" height="795" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/cover-1-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Making Money When the Market Drops: How Traders Use AI to Predict Crypto Crashes</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/how-traders-use-ai-predict-crypto-crashes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=682522</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>President Trump’s recent declarations on import tariffs has rattled the global economy, spooking investors and dragging the cryptocurrency market down with it. Confidence is shaky, and the vibes? Not great. However, while most people are panicking, some traders found a way to make a ton of money. They are profiting from these storms rather than &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-traders-use-ai-predict-crypto-crashes/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-traders-use-ai-predict-crypto-crashes/">Making Money When the Market Drops: How Traders Use AI to Predict Crypto Crashes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>President Trump’s recent declarations on import tariffs has rattled the global economy, spooking investors and dragging the cryptocurrency market down with it. Confidence is shaky, and the vibes? Not great.</p>



<p>However, while most people are panicking, some traders found a way to make a ton of money. They are profiting from these storms rather than merely surviving them. In what way? By leveraging AI trading platforms like<a href="https://algosone.ai/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AlgosOne</a>.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a step-by-step look at how they are doing this.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-navigating-volatility-with-advanced-ai">Navigating Volatility with Advanced AI</h2>



<p>Crypto’s twitchy nature is no secret—one geopolitical headline, and prices go haywire. Take this tariff news: it didn’t just hit stocks; it sparked a crypto sell-off too. Bitcoin’s drop is proof of how sensitive this market is to the world’s drama. Most investors see a dip and hit the panic button, but AlgosOne users? They’ve got an AI ace up their sleeve.</p>



<p>AlgosOne’s trading AI is like a market whisperer. It’s combing through real-time data—price trends, trading volumes, even the buzz on social media—to spot the signals humans might miss. Is fear driving a sell-off? Is a recovery brewing? The AI figures it out fast, buying up assets when they’re cheap and setting sell orders for when the market perks up. It’s not about guessing—it’s about reacting smarter and faster than the crowd.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-automated-execution-and-custom-strategies">Automated Execution and Custom Strategies</h3>



<p>In a crash, every second counts. Hesitate, and you’re either missing a deal or stuck holding a bag that’s losing value. Watching charts all day? Good luck with that. AlgosOne’s AI takes the wheel instead,<a href="https://algosone.ai/ai-trading?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> automating trades</a> so you don’t have to babysit the market.</p>



<p>It’s not a robot just following orders;<a href="https://algosone.ai/technology?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> it’s tweaking your game plan as the market shifts</a>. With one-click approvals via your phone, you’re in the loop without being chained to a screen. It’s your playbook, running on autopilot, adapting to whatever the market throws at it.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-comprehensive-risk-management">Comprehensive Risk Management</h3>



<p>Crypto’s a risky game. Downturns can hit hard, but AlgosOne’s got your back. Stop-loss orders kick in to cut your losses if prices tank too far. Trade size limits stop you from going overboard on one bet. And diversification? It spreads your money across assets and markets so one crash doesn’t sink you.</p>



<p>On top of that, there’s a reserve fund ready to step in to face any unforeseen event, market or otherwise. It’s peace of mind at its core. No matter how wild things get, you’ve got layers of protection keeping your portfolio from taking a fatal hit.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-results-driven-fee-structure">Results-Driven Fee Structure</h3>



<p>Most platforms charge fees whether you win or lose. AlgosOne?<a href="https://algosone.ai/profitability?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> You only pay when you profit</a>. If a trade flops, you’re off the hook. It’s a setup that puts their skin in the game—they don’t eat unless you do.</p>



<p><a href="https://algosone.ai/trading?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Climb the tiers, and it gets sweeter</a>: lower fees, and higher compensation on losing trades. No hidden gotchas, just a straight-up deal that’s all about your bottom line.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-beyond-trading">Beyond Trading</h2>



<p>Automated trading is not the only way AlgosOne helps you make the most of your crypto. They’ve got extras that grow your stash even when the market is unpredictable.</p>



<p>High-Yield Savings Accounts<br>These accounts act like a boost for your savings—top-tier APYs that compound automatically. While the market’s flipping out, your holdings are quietly growing. It’s a steady, no-stress way to build wealth, crash or no crash.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-aiao-token">The AiAO Token</h3>



<p>Then there’s the<a href="https://algosone.ai/aiao-presale?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AiAO token</a>. It’s not just a coin—it’s your ticket to a series of perks. Early birds can ride its price up as it gains traction through smart sales phases. Holding it scores you dividends, a cut of the platform’s wins. Want a say in how things run? You’ve got governance rights too. And the retrodrop program tosses free tokens for promoting, or bringing friends along. It’s a win-win setup that keeps on giving.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-turning-downturns-into-opportunities">Turning Downturns into Opportunities</h2>



<p>Crypto crashes aren’t the end—most times they’re a launchpad. While others see a mess, sharp traders see a chance to snag bargains and ride the rebound. AlgosOne’s AI hands you the tools: real-time smarts, fast trades, and solid defenses to make every dip work for you. Add in savings accounts and AiAO token perks, and you’re not just playing the game—you’re stacking wins from every angle.</p>



<p>So, why sit on the sidelines?<a href="https://algosone.ai?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a114.020425" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Jump in</a> with AlgosOne’s 14-day, no-strings trial and flip market mayhem into your next big move. With AI in your corner, volatility is just another word for opportunity.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-traders-use-ai-predict-crypto-crashes/">Making Money When the Market Drops: How Traders Use AI to Predict Crypto Crashes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/cover-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1400" height="795" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/cover-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gate.io Futures Trading Risk Control Toolkit: Unveiling Three Essential Alert Features</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-futures-trading-risk-control-toolkit-alert-features/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 12:31:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=682521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the realm of cryptocurrency futures trading, ordinary traders often face multiple challenges. Challenges such as information asymmetry, delayed responses, and ineffective strategy execution frequently put traders in a passive position, causing them to miss opportunities. However, the emergence of alert features provides traders with a suite of proactive risk control tools. Gate.io’s futures trading &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-futures-trading-risk-control-toolkit-alert-features/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-futures-trading-risk-control-toolkit-alert-features/">Gate.io Futures Trading Risk Control Toolkit: Unveiling Three Essential Alert Features</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the realm of cryptocurrency futures trading, ordinary traders often face multiple challenges. Challenges such as information asymmetry, delayed responses, and ineffective strategy execution frequently put traders in a passive position, causing them to miss opportunities. However, the emergence of alert features provides traders with a suite of proactive risk control tools.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a>’s futures trading platform has successfully addressed these challenges by offering a comprehensive and practical set of alert tools, creating a closed-loop risk control system from prevention to execution. </p>



<p>Gate.io provides one of the the most extensive and diverse alert functions, catering to different trading needs. Users can simply update and open the app, enter the futures trading candlestick chart page, and click the alert button at the bottom to start a new trading experience.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-price-alerts-precisely-capture-key-price-levels-farewell-to-passive-copy-trading"><strong>Price Alerts: Precisely Capture Key Price Levels, Farewell to Passive Copy Trading</strong></h2>



<p>Price fluctuations are among the most critical factors for traders. <a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a>’s price alert feature provides traders with a tool to accurately capture key price points, helping them avoid missing opportunities due to emotional trading.</p>



<p>Users can customize price trigger conditions based on their trading strategies and risk preferences, including <strong>price rises to or falls to a certain level, 5-minute rise %, 5-minute fall %, 24-hour rise %, and 24-hour fall %.</strong> Gate.io’s price alert feature also supports multidimensional differential alerts, allowing users to choose the latest price, mark price, or index price as the alert benchmark to accommodate different trading strategies.</p>



<p>Now, Gate.io continues to develop new alert dimensions to enhance traders’ experience. In the future, users will be able to set alerts for price rise, entering channel, and exiting channel, further enriching price alert scenarios and enabling more comprehensive market monitoring. For example, when the price enters or exits a specific price range, traders can promptly adjust their strategies to capture market trends.</p>



<p>In terms of application, the price alert feature can be used for profit-taking and stop-limit strategy, helping traders set key levels in advance to avoid unnecessary losses due to market fluctuations. It also assists in breakout strategies, capturing trend initiation signals. For instance, when BTC breaks a resistance level, traders can promptly adjust their strategies to seize market opportunities.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-high-volatility-alerts-a-shield-against-market-shock"><strong>High Volatility Alerts: A Shield Against Market Shock</strong></h2>



<p>In the cryptocurrency market, high price volatility is the norm, especially in fluctuating conditions where market uncertainty increases. To help traders better navigate such complex situations, Gate.io has introduced the high volatility alert feature. The feature’s core value lies in accurately managing fluctuations, helping traders turn market risks into profit opportunities in futures trading.</p>



<p>The high volatility alert allows users to customize the monitoring period and fluctuation threshold based on their trading strategies. For example, short-term traders can set a shorter monitoring period to capture quick trading opportunities, while long-term traders can set a longer monitoring period to avoid being misled by short-term price changes.</p>



<p>From a risk control perspective, this feature can monitor price fluctuations and issue early warnings for extreme market conditions, helping users quickly stop losses or adjust positions. When the market experiences significant volatility, traders receive alert notifications, allowing them to take timely action to prevent losses. Additionally, this feature helps capture opportunities in rising and falling markets, assisting traders in executing their strategies effectively.</p>



<p>Notably, the high volatility alert focuses more on price fluctuations (ampl) rather than simple price increases or decreases. Even if the price movement within five minutes is minor, the ampl difference could be substantial, indicating potential trading opportunities. Traders may need to adjust their strategies accordingly. For instance, when major cryptocurrencies experience sharp fluctuations, other trading pairs in the market may exhibit correlated movements.</p>



<p>Moreover, newly listed tokens often experience significant short-term volatility, making them suitable for selling high, buying low. With the high volatility alert, traders can immediately detect these opportunities and gain a competitive edge.</p>



<p>The core value of this alert feature is to help traders make trading decisions based on volatility frequency. It can alert traders to arbitrage opportunities arising from extreme fluctuations in the spot-futures price difference or cross-futures price difference. At the same time, upon receiving an alert, users can take emergency actions such as closing positions or adding margin to prevent losses caused by market fluctuations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-funding-rate-alert-the-hidden-tool-for-arbitrage-and-holding-costs"><strong>Funding Rate Alert: The Hidden Tool for Arbitrage and Holding Costs</strong></h2>



<p>The funding rate is a crucial mechanism in Gate.io’s futures trading, reflecting market balance between long and short positions and the impact of funding costs on returns. With the funding rate alert feature, users can receive notifications before or after funding rate settlements, allowing them to adjust their trading strategies in time. This feature also supports alerts for sudden changes in funding rates, such as the inflection point between positive and negative fee rates, and a sudden surge in the absolute fee rate.</p>



<p>In terms of user returns, the funding rate’s positive or negative value represents market sentiment and can be utilized for spot-futures arbitrage. The strategy works as follows: when a positive funding rate alert is triggered, traders can buy spot assets and short perpetual futures to earn the funding fee from short positions. Conversely, during a prolonged negative funding rate period, traders can sell spot assets and go long on perpetual futures to earn funding fees from long positions. When executing these trades, traders can further consider market sentiment and risk-reward ratios to optimize their strategy.</p>



<p>Another key application of the funding rate alert is helping traders manage their holding costs. By staying informed of funding rate changes, traders can adjust their positions and reduce holding costs, ultimately improving long-term trading profitability.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-unlock-benefits-and-experience-smart-trading-now"><strong>Unlock Benefits and Experience Smart Trading Now</strong></h2>



<p>With its comprehensive alert features, Gate.io’s futures trading platform provides traders with an entirely new trading experience. Price alert, high volatility alert, and funding rate alert together form a complete and practical risk control system, effectively helping traders seize opportunities and mitigate risks in a complex market environment.</p>



<p>To fully experience these powerful alert features, users can update the Gate.io app to the latest version and activate them. Additionally, Gate.io offers futures bonus to help users familiarize themselves with the platform’s features. For more details, visit the Gate.io<a href="https://www.gate.io/rewards_hub" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Rewards Hub</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong></p>



<p>The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-futures-trading-risk-control-toolkit-alert-features/">Gate.io Futures Trading Risk Control Toolkit: Unveiling Three Essential Alert Features</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-6.png" medium="image" width="1892" height="1052" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-6.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Start Using AI to Trade Everything from Stocks to Crypto</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/how-to-start-using-ai-trade-stocks-crypto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=681361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>No one can deny that Artificial intelligence (AI) has transformed many industries, and the trading sector is no exception. For investors looking to profit from cryptocurrencies and stocks, AI does offer an incredible edge, providing tools to profit from complex, fast-moving markets through strategies that adapt in real time. AlgosOne, a top-rated AI-powered trading platform, &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-to-start-using-ai-trade-stocks-crypto/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-to-start-using-ai-trade-stocks-crypto/">How to Start Using AI to Trade Everything from Stocks to Crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>No one can deny that Artificial intelligence (AI) has transformed many industries, and the trading sector is no exception. For investors looking to profit from cryptocurrencies and stocks, AI does offer an incredible edge, providing tools to profit from complex, fast-moving markets through strategies that adapt in real time.</p>



<p><a href="https://algosone.ai/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AlgosOne</a>, a<a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/algosone.ai?languages=all&amp;stars=4&amp;stars=5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> top-rated</a> AI-powered trading platform, makes it easy for even beginners to start leveraging AI for trading, without requiring any coding or prior trading experience. With advanced machine-learning algorithms and a range of features designed to drive consistent profits while minimizing risks, AlgosOne is well-suited to help you on your trading journey.</p>



<p>Whether you&#8217;re an experienced investor aiming to turn trading into a passive income stream or a newcomer eager to learn the ropes by observing AI-driven strategies, AlgosOne provides valuable tools and insights for traders of every level.</p>



<p>This guide will walk you through the essentials of AI trading on AlgosOne, the advantages it offers, and how to<a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> get started</a> with an exciting new platform.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-algosone">What is AlgosOne?</h2>



<p>AlgosOne is an advanced AI-driven trading platform that leverages proprietary deep-learning neural networks and advanced Natural Language Processing models similar to LLaMa 2 and GPT-4 to manage trading across cryptocurrency and traditional markets. With tools built to simplify trading for everyone from novices to experts, AlgosOne delivers an intuitive, accessible, and powerful AI-driven trading experience.</p>



<p>AlgosOne’s commitment to accessible AI trading means there is no need for users to have any technical or financial background. With a<a href="https://algosone.ai/faq/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> low minimum investment of just $300</a> and by handling all the complexities behind the scenes, AlgosOne’s AI manages risk, optimizes trade strategies, and consistently adapts to changing market conditions to maximize profits. Whether you&#8217;re aiming to trade cryptocurrencies in the next bull run or venture into stocks and other traditional markets, AlgosOne delivers the results you&#8217;re seeking.</p>



<p>Lastly, AlgosOne has been preparing the launch of its proprietary AIAO token, a unique cryptocurrency that allows users to benefit from the platform’s performance through dividends while offering exclusive governance features.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-it-works">How It Works</h2>



<p>AlgosOne uses generative AI models that rely on Natural Language Processing (NLP) and deep-learning capabilities to scan market data, evaluate sentiment, predict trends, and automate trading in a way that keeps up with rapid market fluctuations. This AI engine continuously learns from market patterns, self-corrects in real time, and ensures users are well-positioned in both bull and bear markets.</p>



<p>Here’s how AlgosOne’s technology drives results:</p>



<p>·  <strong>Automated Diversification:</strong> AlgosOne automatically diversifies users’ portfolios across<a href="https://algosone.ai/markets/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> various financial markets</a> such as stocks, bonds, indices, commodities, cryptocurrencies, and forex, effectively reducing exposure to single assets and improving overall stability.</p>



<p>·&nbsp; <strong>Risk Management Tools:</strong> With 24/7 oversight, stop-losses, take-profit points, and risk caps, AlgosOne mitigates potential losses effectively. Human specialists monitor the markets, stepping in as needed to handle unforeseen events.</p>



<p>·&nbsp; <strong>Real-time Optimization:</strong> The AI adjusts trading strategies instantly in response to market signals, ensuring users capitalize on opportunities without manual adjustments.</p>



<p>·&nbsp; <strong>Self-Improving AI Model:</strong> AlgosOne’s advanced machine-learning algorithms improve continually, enhancing predictive accuracy and profitability as they learn.</p>



<p>With these tools in place, AlgosOne helps users trade confidently, regardless of market conditions.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-advantages-of-algosone">Advantages of AlgosOne</h2>



<p>AlgosOne stands out from other platforms with a suite of benefits designed to maximize user profits and minimize risk. Below are the platform’s key advantages:</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-advanced-machine-learning-technology">Advanced Machine-learning Technology</h3>



<p>AlgosOne’s AI is a generative model that continuously improves its trading strategy based on evolving data. With self-learning capabilities, the AI is always adapting, which enhances profitability and minimizes risk.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ease-of-use">Ease of Use</h3>



<p>AlgosOne’s interface is designed for users of all skill levels, with no coding or trading experience required. This accessibility opens up AI-driven trading to anyone looking to benefit from modern trading technology without needing specialized knowledge.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-consistent-high-profits">Consistent High Profits</h3>



<p>AlgosOne’s technology has a proven track record of consistently achieving high annual returns, surpassing the profit percentages seen in traditional trading platforms. This performance continues to improve as the AI learns and optimizes its strategies.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-competitive-fee-structure">Competitive Fee Structure</h3>



<p>Unlike many trading platforms, AlgosOne doesn’t charge for account setup, deposits, inactivity, or transactions. Instead, fees are solely based on winning trades, and users with losses can access compensation options, giving AlgosOne one of the most competitive fee structures in the market.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-the-reserve-fund">The Reserve Fund</h3>



<p>To protect user funds, AlgosOne maintains a reserve fund – exceeding $50M at the time of writing – that covers potential losses due to market shifts, technical issues, or unexpected events. Users can see the fund balance directly in their dashboard, ensuring transparency.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-comprehensive-risk-management">Comprehensive Risk Management</h3>



<p>AlgosOne incorporates various risk management tools, including trade size caps, hedging strategies, and AI-powered portfolio diversification. Additionally, 24/7 oversight by human specialists ensures continuous support and rapid response during volatile market events.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-regulatory-compliance-amp-security">Regulatory Compliance &amp; Security</h3>



<p>With strict ID verification procedures, account segregation, and client capital protections, AlgosOne adheres to regulatory standards. The platform and its smart contracts are also audited, ensuring a high level of security for all users.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-ongoing-algorithm-improvements">Ongoing Algorithm Improvements</h3>



<p>AlgosOne frequently upgrades its algorithms, incorporating new features and enhancements to maintain a cutting-edge trading experience for its users.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-aiao-token-projected-price-appreciation-amp-passive-income">The AIAO Token: Projected Price Appreciation &amp; Passive Income</h2>



<p>The upcoming launch of the AIAO token is planned for Q2 2025. Exclusive to AlgosOne, the token offers substantial benefits.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-calculated-price-appreciation">Calculated Price Appreciation</h3>



<p>AIAO is structured to always rise in value, ensuring token holders can sell at a profit.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-regular-dividend-payouts">Regular Dividend Payouts</h3>



<p>Users earn regular dividend payouts simply for holding AIAO, providing a steady income stream beyond trading.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-platform-governance">Platform Governance</h3>



<p>AIAO holders can participate in key platform decisions, allowing them to have a voice in AlgosOne’s future developments.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-exclusive-retrodrop">Exclusive Retrodrop</h3>



<p>AlgosOne users earn free tokens through engagement, creating additional value just for being active and promoting the platform.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-to-start-on-algosone">How to Start on AlgosOne</h2>



<p>Looking to give AI trading a try? Follow these steps to get started with AlgosOne:</p>



<p>1. Open an Account: Head to the AlgosOne website and<a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> create an account</a>. There’s no setup fee, and the process is designed to be quick and straightforward.</p>



<p>2. Deposit Your Funds: Once your account is verified, deposit funds into your trading account. You can use these funds to start trading, but also buy AIAO tokens at a later stage.</p>



<p>3. Start Trading: After a deposit of at least $300, the AI will send you trades for approval within 15 minutes. Simply open the notification and click &#8216;Approve&#8217; for 1-click trades. Depending on your trading tier, some trades may even be auto-approved by the AI—no action needed!&nbsp;</p>



<p>4. (Q2 2025) Buy AIAO Tokens, or Claim the Retrodrop: The upcoming AIAO token presale will offer a great opportunity to secure your share of this valuable asset. With calculated price appreciation and dividends, AIAO can serve as a source of passive income with quarterly or yearly payouts, while giving you a say in the platform’s governance.</p>



<p>As an AlgosOne user, you’re eligible for the exclusive<a href="https://algosone.ai/aiao-presale/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> AIAO token retrodrop</a>. Engage with the platform, and you’ll be eligible to receive free tokens, enhancing your returns without additional investment. Just registering and performing some basic actions in the app will already qualify you for the retrodrop. The more actions you perform, the bigger your drop will be.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-new-chapter-in-ai-trading">A New Chapter in AI Trading</h2>



<p>AlgosOne is more than just an online trading platform—it’s a comprehensive AI trading solution. With powerful tools, an intuitive interface, and a range of profit options through both trading and token dividends, AlgosOne makes AI-driven trading accessible to everyone. With an impressive<a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/algosone.ai?languages=all&amp;stars=4&amp;stars=5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> 4.7 Trustpilot rating</a>, whether you’re new to trading or an experienced investor, AlgosOne’s unique combination of AI technology, AIAO token benefits, and hands-free risk management sets it apart in the trading landscape.</p>



<p>For another look at AlgosOne, here is a<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3wtPlyScRS0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> video</a> from crypto YouTuber Crypto Volt. And for more details regarding the technical aspects of the platform’s AI, check out<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tR8aVrWxA04"> this video</a> on AlgosOne’s<a href="https://www.youtube.com/@algosone.AI_Official" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> official YouTube page</a>.Ready to maximize your profits with AI?<a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a113.310325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Open an AlgosOne account</a> today to enjoy a 14-day, no-commitment trial, and take your first step toward smarter trading.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-to-start-using-ai-trade-stocks-crypto/">How to Start Using AI to Trade Everything from Stocks to Crypto</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1401" height="795" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Crypto’s Bullish Patterns: ADA, XRP, SOL, BTC, and Meme Coins Poised for a Rally—Maximize Your Gains with AI</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/crypto-bullish-ada-xrp-sol-btc-meme-coins-ai/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=678717</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A wave of bullish patterns is emerging across key cryptocurrencies, including Cardano (ADA), XRP, Solana (SOL), Bitcoin (BTC), and even meme coins like DOGE and SHIB. These movements could signal an imminent rally as optimism builds in the crypto market. Now might be the perfect time to position yourself to benefit from this surge—and AlgosOne’s &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-bullish-ada-xrp-sol-btc-meme-coins-ai/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-bullish-ada-xrp-sol-btc-meme-coins-ai/">Crypto’s Bullish Patterns: ADA, XRP, SOL, BTC, and Meme Coins Poised for a Rally—Maximize Your Gains with AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A wave of bullish patterns is emerging across key cryptocurrencies, including Cardano (ADA), XRP, Solana (SOL), Bitcoin (BTC), and even meme coins like DOGE and SHIB. These movements could signal an imminent rally as optimism builds in the crypto market.</p>



<p>Now might be the perfect time to position yourself to benefit from this surge—and <a href="https://lp1.algosone.ai/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a112.270325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">AlgosOne’s AI-powered tools</a> could help you seize the moment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-bullish-trends-across-major-cryptocurrencies">Bullish Trends Across Major Cryptocurrencies</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXdJHwRsUzF_KRsJdalxU8fgDAZgn8UHEm5nGiMhfnG9XrVCHo1vExwKu6b8BQpSdKPcOEwIsup40Iz3wtvsOO_TUA2W2XpmUAWYEEHnLCNPMPoYE8_XrYlJY6cSIyg4cAPdSR_yFFkq0p0olauO-yg?key=cTqwfYlm9YxegIYbNUenO5tz" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-ai-can-help-you-profit-from-price-surges-like-cardano-s">How AI Can Help You Profit from Price Surges Like Cardano’s</h2>



<p>AI trading bots are a game-changer for crypto investors looking to capitalize on market trends. AlgosOne offers cutting-edge technology that can analyze vast amounts of market data in real time, predict price movements, and execute trades on your behalf without emotional biases.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-emotion-free-trading">Emotion-Free Trading</h3>



<p>Crypto markets are notoriously volatile, and emotions like greed and fear can cloud decision-making. AlgosOne’s AI bots trade purely on data-driven insights, removing emotional biases that can lead to costly mistakes.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-real-time-data-analysis">Real-Time Data Analysis</h3>



<p>AlgosOne’s algorithms process market data at lightning speed, identifying trends and patterns across assets like Cardano, XRP, SOL, BTC, and meme coins. This capability provides traders with a crucial edge in seizing opportunities.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-accessibility-for-everyone">Accessibility for Everyone</h3>



<p>You don’t need to be an expert in chart analysis or programming to use AlgosOne. With its easy-to-use interface, the platform allows both beginners and experienced traders to set up the account within less than 60 seconds.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-risk-management">Risk Management</h3>



<p>With a potentially volatile market ahead, risk management is critical. AlgosOne comes with built-in stop-loss mechanisms, trade size limits, and portfolio diversification strategies that minimize potential losses.&nbsp; Everything is set and automated by the AI.&nbsp;</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-savings-accounts">Savings Accounts</h3>



<p>For those who prefer a more passive approach to growth, AlgosOne’s high-yield savings accounts offer industry-leading APYs and compound interest. This type of account allows you to grow your portfolio and take advantage of your gains with minimal effort.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXczaaDDuoMVYZem4fjVeBO9BYsQ823Q1akg9sBSKrJGDcrRrSqZNTlZy0jcR4by1os2pZVrgV_KkjwCMCTeOnQN4jPqqNKrhElHfwIH401CwSJ0nA93F3JXSA2sVEJKg3N9UNhUcaYBBIuiGCRCV1o?key=cTqwfYlm9YxegIYbNUenO5tz" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-aiao-token-a-new-way-to-maximize-your-returns">The AiAO Token: A New Way to Maximize Your Returns</h2>



<p>Beyond Cardano’s potential price surge, there is high potential in AlgosOne’s own AiAO token, which is set to play a key role in the platform’s ecosystem.</p>



<p>By holding AiAO tokens, users will unlock regular dividend payouts and governance rights, allowing them to earn rewards as the platform grows. Furthermore, the AiAO token is designed for long-term growth, with inbuilt strategic price appreciation, passive income rewards, and the opportunity to participate in platform decisions.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXc9KI8goCOLPV4rOWo4AQRNXOAoCAGN-hyf5oLBRq3WZoolQ11QRzC6gZnZJICqx1SWfr_B2Y1e257mCPy-VXeKYZuirEe6HrXEIJpEbsW5EaFj8ZuzBd8Ek_eL6XF8AnCJ5NjlYlbZjYFFVanCkzM?key=cTqwfYlm9YxegIYbNUenO5tz" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Users qualify for the retrodrop in a number of ways: using and engaging with the platform, as well as being active within the AlgosOne community.</p>



<p><strong>This is so simple. Seize the Opportunity Today!</strong></p>



<ol class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-decimal list-inside " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Step one</strong>: <a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a112.270325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sign up on the website</a>.</li>



<li><strong>Step two: </strong>Deposit $300 or more using your preferred payment method, including crypto, bank transfer, PayPal, or credit/debit card.</li>



<li><strong>Step three: </strong>That’s it. Within 15 minutes, the AI bot will start trading automatically with an 80% win rate.</li>
</ol>



<p>Their<a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/algosone.ai?languages=all&amp;stars=4&amp;stars=5" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> 4.7 Trustpilot rating</a> is a testament to the thousands of satisfied users already leveraging AlgosOne to make smarter, more profitable trades with ADA, SOL, BTC, Stabecoins and more. Set up your account and enjoy the automated trading experience. </p>



<p>Check this<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyZ5Qlip2DY" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow"> video by a long term user Dirk</a> for a detailed user experience review of AlgosOne.AlgosOne offers a 14-day risk free trial for new users and up to 15% welcome bonus. Don’t miss your chance to profit from the next big crypto trends– <a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a112.270325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">start trading with AlgosOne now</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-bullish-ada-xrp-sol-btc-meme-coins-ai/">Crypto’s Bullish Patterns: ADA, XRP, SOL, BTC, and Meme Coins Poised for a Rally—Maximize Your Gains with AI</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover.png" medium="image" width="1400" height="796" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Profiting From Bitcoin, XRP, and SHIB Volatility? How This AI Bot Makes Bear Markets Lucrative</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/how-algosone-makes-bear-markets-lucrative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AI News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=678718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Prices of cryptocurrencies fluctuate quite often. Expert traders can capitalize on them, but constant market monitoring and adjusting trade strategies are still required, especially during a bear market.  However, with this exciting new platform called AlgosOne, which offers an AI-powered trade automation bot, be it volatility or a bear market, both can become extremely lucrative.  &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-algosone-makes-bear-markets-lucrative/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-algosone-makes-bear-markets-lucrative/">Profiting From Bitcoin, XRP, and SHIB Volatility? How This AI Bot Makes Bear Markets Lucrative</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Prices of cryptocurrencies fluctuate quite often. Expert traders can capitalize on them, but constant market monitoring and adjusting trade strategies are still required, especially during a bear market. </strong></p>



<p>However, with this exciting new platform called <a href="https://algosone.ai?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a111.250325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">AlgosOne</a>, which offers an AI-powered trade automation bot, be it volatility or a bear market, both can become extremely lucrative. </p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s learn more about this exciting new platform and how it can help you profit from the rising prices of Bitcoin, XRP, and SHIB.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-is-algosone">What is AlgosOne?</h2>



<p>AlgosOne is an <a href="https://lp1.algosone.ai/?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a111.250325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">AI-powered</a> trade automation bot that offers exceptional profits from cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin, Ripple XRP, and Shiba Inu, even in a bear market. Users only have to deposit a minimum of $300 and then get on with their day because the bot handles all of the work, which gives users a reliable and stable income. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcXjTomMMJINwqKxhZhbCJ2kwf5lMNyns1hpVWGc_HVg4wyW9PB5Kz20Nmub5gxYHhb8ztIuqRflpuklH0UMrVH6ZgXfv1pR12GiLaSa9zs_7X1Tgi6WdSJzHepQp814AnplXaPgGi4fmcFcoKzZ7o?key=daOfJVERy0vnv7YUA3zb0smb" alt=""/></figure>



<p>The trading bot is powered by machine learning (ML) technology and trained on massive amounts of trading-related data. The bot constantly analyzes current news, top traders and their successful strategies, price action, and expert analysis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like many other traders, you can also sign up now and make the most of AlgosOne’s limited-time 15% bonus on deposits and a <a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a111.250325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">two-week long risk-free</a> trial. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-risk-management-of-algosone">Risk Management of AlgosOne</h2>



<p>Trading in market conditions like a bear market comes with several risks. That’s why AlgosOne offers a comprehensive risk management plan which includes the following:&nbsp;</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Transparency:</strong> It ensures transparency by providing users with clear and straightforward information about its trading process. During the entire journey, it maintains an open line of communication, supported by a dedicated customer support team. Hence, users are aware of where their funds are being invested or traded. </li>



<li><strong>Protection Against Liquidation:</strong> AlgosOne has a liquidation prevention method that ensures only 5% to 10% of the user’s total balance per trade is utilized. This helps prevent the liquidation of the user&#8217;s capital.</li>



<li><strong>Funds Security:</strong> AlgosOne has also partnered with some of the world’s top digital asset security platforms, including Tier-A Banks. Client and company funds are kept in separate accounts spread across different banks, ensuring no single financial institute has full custody of all the capital.</li>



<li><strong>Reserve Fund:</strong> AlgosOne offers a unique Reserve Fund that holds over $40 million. The reserve fund adds a further layer of protection by acting as insurance if things go sideways due to technical or market failure. In his review, Financial Expert Oli talks about the reserve fund and how it works on his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qh9ZKSOPtU8" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">algosone review on youtube.</a></li>



<li><strong>Human Intervention:</strong> Because technology and human experience work best together, a team of financial experts is always present to oversee the entire trading experience. </li>



<li><strong>Assets Diversification:</strong> Lastly, AlgosOne doesn’t only profit from Bitcoin, XRP, and Shiba Inu; rather, it diversifies risk and invests in multiple other financial markets, including stocks, forex, commodities, bonds, and indices. </li>
</ul>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXfFoHeKnOHpMecRY7nBT6XuvEa5IRV649bqDtDLJzfmDs9KAIxmpDT8EEuued7rhTc7xuz28fWeBIi5zQIqy8Z5f3lXwuNC8X56Oq-EcO_hBVhtyopkVSMr8cHeW6uj0Lad_tPNlVlmofNelWT8ag?key=daOfJVERy0vnv7YUA3zb0smb" alt=""/></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-algosone-aiao-token">AlgosOne AiAO Token</h2>



<p>Trading Bitcoin, XRP, and Shiba Inu have many advantages, but AlgosOne’s AiAO token is also designed in a unique way, especially in a bear market, because of its tokenomics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Firstly, the AiAO token offers users a unique governance feature that includes voting rights. These rights allow holders to participate in platform decisions, which helps foster an engaged community. Secondly, the token also offers regular dividend payouts and is designed for value growth. A portion of these dividend payouts come from AlgosOne’s reserve fund.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>AiAO token offers users a great opportunity. Depending on which of the 16 stages a user enters and how early they do, the capital appreciation they will experience can be 500x. This is a return that Bitcoin, XRP, or Shiba Inu may not give.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-positive-response-of-traders">Positive Response of Traders</h2>



<p>Many users have reported high gains after using AlgosOne, even in a bear market. Users also like AlgosOne for its high returns, intuitive design, and proper risk management strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Moreover, they also commend AlgosOne for letting them take the back seat while it does all the technical trading work for them. Long-term user <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5_TDLcrJgrs" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Pieter</a> of AlgosOne also shows this as how easily users can get acquainted with it and start earning profits.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXcZNrjU5Qi0MoBoa3yZDCRetWql84eVfvcj-VnQW2H7W8NTSvdCavuvvN1HcYpygl2rHe0p9WNDD5XdOfpOVFSUG9d8V3_Yuhb0p4m2nFeGCPuZo0C0JI5VOwWaSJGI7oN_dlvtt3mRiS9ry2wY2A?key=daOfJVERy0vnv7YUA3zb0smb" alt=""/></figure>



<p>AlgosOne’s <a href="https://www.trustpilot.com/review/algosone.ai" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">4.7-star rating</a> on Trustpilot and 4.5-star rating on Google reviews show a positive user response. </p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-conclusion">Conclusion</h2>



<p>Profiting from cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin, XRP, and Shiba Inu can be extremely rewarding, but due to increased volatility during a bear market, it can become extremely risky.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why many traders are opting for AlgosOne. This AI-powered trading bot excels in every market condition and performs trade decisions on the user’s behalf with extreme precision and accuracy. With this, users get to enjoy profits without having to do any hard work!&nbsp;</p>



<p>Want to grow your portfolio even in a bear market? <a href="https://app.algosone.ai/registration?utm_source=beincrypto&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_campaign=a0&amp;utm_content=a111.250325" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Sign up</a> for AlgosOne right now and make the most of your funds with no effort! </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/how-algosone-makes-bear-markets-lucrative/">Profiting From Bitcoin, XRP, and SHIB Volatility? How This AI Bot Makes Bear Markets Lucrative</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover.png" medium="image" width="1400" height="796" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/cover.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Comprehensive Analysis of Gate.io Futures: Revealing Trading Strategies in a Market Shock</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/comprehensive-analysis-gate-io-futures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 12:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=678719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the crypto world, a market shock is an extremely complex state characterized by intensified volatility, reduced liquidity, and sluggish market sentiment. The recent price change of BTC is a typical reflection of such market conditions. In this environment, Gate.io Futures trading, with its unique advantages such as two-way profit potential, spot-futures arbitrage, and leverage &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/comprehensive-analysis-gate-io-futures/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/comprehensive-analysis-gate-io-futures/">A Comprehensive Analysis of Gate.io Futures: Revealing Trading Strategies in a Market Shock</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In the crypto world, a market shock is an extremely complex state characterized by intensified volatility, reduced liquidity, and sluggish market sentiment. The recent price change of BTC is a typical reflection of such market conditions.</strong></p>



<p>In this environment, <a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> Futures trading, with its unique advantages such as two-way profit potential, spot-futures arbitrage, and leverage efficiency, has become an essential tool for investors to cope with market fluctuations. Compared to the passive holding strategy of spot trading, futures trading provides investors with more flexible options.</p>



<p>This article aims to provide investors with a comprehensive hedging guide, covering strategies and tools, helping them survive the market shock steadily while achieving returns.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gate-io-futures-a-powerful-tool-for-trading-in-a-market-shock"><strong>Gate.io Futures: A Powerful Tool for Trading in a Market Shock</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-grid-trading-bots-automated-solutions-for-a-volatile-market"><strong>Grid Trading Bots: Automated Solutions for a Volatile Market</strong></h3>



<p>In a market shock, grid trading bots become a reliable assistant for investors. Based on traditional grid trading, <a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> has added multiple bot strategies to meet different users’ trading needs. The creators of these strategies are called “Bot Providers”. Users can copy their strategies with one click to easily experience the charm of bot trading.</p>



<p>By checking the performance of bots created by other users in the “Leaderboard” or “Bot Pool”, users can select reliable traders’ bots to copy based on factors such as annualized returns, total profits, and bot runtime.</p>



<p>In addition, in a market shock, it is also recommended to use the Neutral Futures Grid Bot. This bot adopts a sell-high, buy-low trading model, intelligently handling market fluctuations and bringing stable returns to investors. Backtest data shows that this bot outperforms traditional manual trading strategies under various market conditions. It can automatically identify market fluctuation ranges, buy when prices drop, and sell when prices rise, thereby achieving automated profit accumulation.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-spot-futures-arbitrage-and-hedge-mode-coping-with-market-fluctuations-flexibly"><strong>Spot-Futures Arbitrage and Hedge Mode: Coping with Market Fluctuations Flexibly</strong></h3>



<p>In a market shock, the spot-futures arbitrage strategy is one of the key approaches for investors to deal with market fluctuations. This strategy also provides an effective risk management tool for investors. By simultaneously holding spot and short futures positions, it hedges price fluctuation risks, helping investors reduce or even eliminate potential losses from holding cryptocurrencies, while also earning the corresponding funding fees based on market trends. For example, when investors hold a Bitcoin spot, they can also open a short futures position. If the spot price drops and the funding rate is positive, profits from the futures position can effectively offset the spot losses, while earning the funding fee.</p>



<p>The core advantage of spot-futures arbitrage lies in its strong risk management ability, profit locking, and effective response to market uncertainty. This strategy provides investors with a solid way to protect their asset value, maintaining relative stability even in the face of drastic market fluctuations.</p>



<p>At the same time, the hedge mode strategy also offers investors an effective risk management tool. Gate.io perpetual futures support hedge mode, allowing users to hold long and short positions simultaneously under the same futures.</p>



<p>This mode grants investors greater flexibility, enabling them to capture long opportunities when the market rises while profiting from short positions when the market falls. It also provides strong risk hedging capabilities. By independently managing and adjusting long and short positions, investors can achieve more comprehensive trading control, maintaining steady trading status in a complex and ever-changing market.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-risk-management-tools-steady-handling-of-futures-trading"><strong>Risk Management Tools: Steady Handling of Futures Trading</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-tiered-liquidation-and-margin-ratio-reducing-liquidation-risks"><strong>Tiered Liquidation and Margin Ratio: Reducing Liquidation Risks</strong></h3>



<p>Risk management is a critical aspect of futures trading. Gate.io introduces a tiered liquidation mechanism that provides investors with an effective risk buffer. When users trigger liquidation and the position size is too large, the system will lower the risk limit by one tier and partially liquidate the position exceeding the limit. The core of this mechanism lies in gradually reducing the position size to lower the user’s leverage ratio, thereby easing margin pressure.</p>



<p>At the same time, Gate.io’s tiered margin ratio mechanism also provides investors with a flexible fund management solution. According to the user’s position size, the platform sets different margin ratios. When the user’s position size is small, the margin ratio is relatively low, allowing users to participate in trading with less capital and reducing funding pressure. As the position size increases, the margin ratio will also rise accordingly to ensure sufficient risk coverage.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-take-profit-and-stop-limit-strategies-lock-in-profits-and-control-risks"><strong>Take-Profit and Stop-Limit Strategies: Lock in Profits and Control Risks</strong></h3>



<p>Take-profit and stop-limit are indispensable risk management tools in futures trading. Gate.io offers multiple take-profit and stop-limit strategies, among which the basic option is the trailing take-profit. This strategy automatically adjusts the closing trigger price based on market price fluctuations, making it especially suitable for trending markets. When the price moves in a favorable direction, the trailing take-profit order will adjust the trigger price accordingly, helping users maximize profits.</p>



<p>The upgraded solution, “OCO Orders” (One Cancels the Other), provides investors with a more advanced risk management tool. An OCO order is a combination of a take-profit order and a stop-limit order. Once one order is executed, the other will be automatically canceled. This mechanism allows traders to automatically implement risk management strategies without continuously monitoring the market.</p>



<p>For example, if the price reaches the take-profit level, the take-profit order will be triggered and the stop-limit order canceled, allowing the investor to automatically secure profits. Conversely, if the price hits the stop-limit level, the stop-limit order will be triggered and the take-profit order canceled, effectively limiting losses. OCO orders not only improve risk management efficiency but also help investors maintain trading discipline, avoiding impulsive decisions during intense market fluctuations.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-comprehensive-ecosystem-support-to-assist-trading-decisions"><strong>Comprehensive Ecosystem Support to Assist Trading Decisions</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-beginner-s-guide-simulated-trading-and-copy-trading-protection"><strong>Beginner’s Guide: Simulated Trading and Copy Trading Protection</strong></h3>



<p>For novice investors, Gate.io provides a well-rounded beginner’s survival zone to help them quickly adapt to futures trading. The futures testnet is the best starting point for beginners, allowing users to trade with virtual funds and experience the entire process of futures trading in a zero-risk environment. Through simulation, novice investors can familiarize themselves with the trading process and test strategies without worrying about capital loss.</p>



<p>In addition, the star trader copy trading system provides beginners with another way to learn and grow. With the copy trading protection mechanism, the platform’s lead traders’ risk control systems and copy trading compensation coupons offer additional security guarantees. New investors can choose to follow the strategies of experienced star traders, allowing them to quickly grasp the essence of futures trading.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-advanced-guide-data-driven-decision-support"><strong>Advanced Guide: Data-Driven Decision Support</strong></h3>



<p>For experienced investors, Gate.io offers abundant data support to help them achieve data-driven decision-making. The market big data function provides investors with comprehensive market information, including capital flows, futures positions, long-short ratios, and block orders. These data points enable investors to deeply understand market dynamics and capture potential trading opportunities.</p>



<p>In addition, the platform offers various coin rankings and ecosystem analysis tools. Through these tools, investors can quickly identify market hotspots, analyze market trends, and make more accurate trading decisions based on data. This data-driven decision-making model not only improves trading efficiency but also helps investors maintain a competitive edge in complex market environments, achieving long-term and stable returns.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-survival-rules-summary-three-key-principles-for-steady-trading"><strong>Survival Rules Summary: Three Key Principles for Steady Trading</strong></h2>



<p>In a volatile market, the survival rules for futures trading can be summarized into three key points: low leverage, strict stop-limit, and avoiding forced holding. Low leverage can effectively reduce risks and ensure that investors maintain a stable capital status during market fluctuations. Strict stop-limit settings are crucial for protecting investors’ funds. By reasonably setting take-profit and stop-limit levels, investors can lock in profits and control losses amid market volatility. Avoiding forced holding is an important principle to prevent excessive risk exposure. Investors should avoid blindly holding positions when the market is unfavorable to prevent greater losses.</p>



<p>When facing a volatile market, investors need to remain calm and rational. By combining the strategies and tools provided in this article, they can formulate a trading plan that suits their needs. Through the proper use of risk management tools, flexible adjustment of trading strategies, and full utilization of the platform’s ecosystem support system, investors can survive steadily in complex market environments and achieve profits.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong></p>



<p>The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/comprehensive-analysis-gate-io-futures/">A Comprehensive Analysis of Gate.io Futures: Revealing Trading Strategies in a Market Shock</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-222.png" medium="image" width="1918" height="1068" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-222.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gate.io Staking: From PoS to DeFi, Your Comprehensive Solution for Asset Growth</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-staking-pos-defi-asset-growth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=677893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As blockchain technology continues to surge, the demand for digital asset appreciation has become a key drive of industry development. However, the limitations of traditional financial models and the complexity of on-chain operations present significant challenges for investors.&#160; On one hand, traditional wealth management offers high barriers to entry and low returns, falling short of &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-staking-pos-defi-asset-growth/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-staking-pos-defi-asset-growth/">Gate.io Staking: From PoS to DeFi, Your Comprehensive Solution for Asset Growth</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As blockchain technology continues to surge, the demand for digital asset appreciation has become a key drive of industry development. However, the limitations of traditional financial models and the complexity of on-chain operations present significant challenges for investors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On one hand, traditional wealth management offers high barriers to entry and low returns, falling short of investor expectations for rapid asset growth. On the other hand, the complicated processes and potential risks of on-chain activities deter many users from participation.</p>



<p>Against this backdrop, <a href="https://www.gate.io/staking/list/?ch=GM_stakingbein_20250321&amp;utm_campaign=TR_tI4hJo48&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=Flash+News&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a> Staking provides users a safe, flexible, and high-yield solution for digital asset growth, leveraging innovative financial models and robust technology, trying to redefine the future of on-chain wealth management.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-an-innovative-financial-model-potentially-ushering-in-a-new-era-of-digital-asset-growth"><strong>An Innovative Financial Model Potentially Ushering in a New Era of Digital Asset Growth</strong></h2>



<p>The launch of Gate.io Staking marks a new chapter in digital asset management. By integrating popular Proof-of-Stake (PoS) projects, the platform opens a novel pathway for users to grow their assets. Users can simply stake a certain amount of crypto assets to earn substantial on-chain rewards.</p>



<p>At the heart of this model is <a href="https://www.gate.io/staking/list/?ch=GM_stakingbein_20250321&amp;utm_campaign=TR_tI4hJo48&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=Flash+News&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io</a>’s rigorous project selection and professional evaluation. Every PoS project listed undergoes thorough due diligence by the platform’s expert team, ensuring a solid foundation for user’s asset safety. This innovative approach provides users with diversified staking options and, through its low entry threshold and high-yield features, makes digital asset growth more accessible than ever.</p>



<p>From the perspective of product design, Gate.io Staking stands out with its distinct advantages. The platform gathers the industry’s top PoS projects, offering users a wide selection of premium opportunities and competitive yields. Its flexible staking and redemption mechanism grants users greater control over their investments, allowing them to adjust their asset allocation at any time without worrying about long-term lockups.</p>



<p>Additionally, the platform’s 100% reserve mechanism offers comprehensive protection for user assets, while daily reward distribution ensures users can monitor their earnings in real time with full transparency. These advantages collectively form the core competitiveness of Gate.io Staking, making it an outstanding performer among all the on-chain wealth management platforms.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-embrace-defi-unlock-new-staking-opportunities"><strong>Embrace DeFi: Unlock New Staking Opportunities</strong></h2>



<p>Recently, Gate.io Staking has officially integrated new DeFi protocols, offering users greater asset transparency and lower transaction costs. By leveraging carefully selected on-chain lending, re-staking, and decentralized exchange (DEX) protocols, the platform provides enhanced liquidity and diversified earning opportunities.</p>



<p>Through deep integration with leading DeFi lending protocols such as Compound V3 and Aave V3, users can stake mainstream stablecoins like USDC and USDT to earn multiple token rewards, including USDC, USDT, AVAX, and COMP. This model offers stable and reliable returns, with competitive annualized yields designed to bring better investment experience to users.</p>



<p>In addition, Gate.io Staking integrates the dYdX protocol, enabling users to stake DYDX with a single click on Gate.io to earn yield in USDC stablecoins. This DeFi integration expands earning possibilities while leveraging the transparency and security of decentralized finance, providing users with a safe and reliable investment environment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-diversified-tokens-launched-capture-new-opportunities-of-asset-growth"><strong>Diversified Tokens Launched: Capture New Opportunities of Asset Growth</strong></h2>



<p>Recently, Gate.io Staking is set for a major product upgrade, with the addition of four popular assets: USDT, USDC, DYDX, and AVAX. Alongside this expansion, the platform is launching exclusive bonus rewards, offering annualized yields of up to 9.02%, creating unprecedented earning opportunities for investors.</p>



<p>USDT and USDC staking and yield distribution are enabled through multiple diversified DeFi protocols such as AAVE V3 and Compound V3, each offering unique operation modes and risk-return profiles. Investors can choose their preferred protocols based on individual risk tolerance and investment objectives, enjoying stable returns from digital asset growth.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-rt.googleusercontent.com/docsz/AD_4nXf9wCGj0LP_1xlYMVBf86183qwL4vSBH5_vTjcyrqmANSkXFHGr2ZCk9oYSTD58RMTfcpRYpM3BM3YMYQb6-oHTcWa4JkAgv31Wn69VnbksOpBnVkGXXtl5Zk80WLYB6nmO99cv?key=qUdTXKbInpGmol64WjqLBNdl" alt=""/></figure>



<p>With multi-layered reward mechanisms, Gate.io Staking delivers diversified income streams, further improving its attraction to users and solidifying its position as the go-to platform for digital asset growth. Benefited from the platform’s flexible staking policies, users are able to fully maximize returns on their assets through staking with ease.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-seize-the-opportunity-embark-on-the-digital-asset-growth-journey"><strong>Seize the Opportunity: Embark on the Digital Asset Growth Journey</strong></h2>



<p>In the fast-evolving digital asset landscape, every investor seeks a secure, efficient, and rewarding path to wealth growth. Powered by innovative financial models, robust technology, and a rich selection of projects, Gate.io Staking offers a comprehensive platform to grow digital assets for users.</p>



<p>Now is the time to take action and embark on a new journey of digital asset growth. Register<a href="https://www.gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> today and get a new experience of on-chain wealth management, maximizing your digital asset growth in a secure and transparent environment.</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">User Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-staking-pos-defi-asset-growth/">Gate.io Staking: From PoS to DeFi, Your Comprehensive Solution for Asset Growth</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-193.png" medium="image" width="1524" height="850" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-193.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gate.io Unified Account: A Practical Guide to One-Stop Asset Management</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-unified-account-practical-guide-asset-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dmitriy Maiorov]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 07:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=677292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the digital asset trading space, traditional multi-account management has long been a challenge for traders. Scattered funds, complex operations, and high barriers to cross-market trading significantly hinder trading efficiency. Gate.io Unified Account presents a breakthrough solution to this dilemma. Built on an all-in-one concept, it serves as a centralized trading hub integrating multiple functions, &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-unified-account-practical-guide-asset-management/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-unified-account-practical-guide-asset-management/">Gate.io Unified Account: A Practical Guide to One-Stop Asset Management</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the digital asset trading space, traditional multi-account management has long been a challenge for traders. Scattered funds, complex operations, and high barriers to cross-market trading significantly hinder trading efficiency.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.gate.io/unified-trading-account/?ch=GM_accountbein_20250312&amp;utm_campaign=TR_EM47Oge5&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io Unified Account</a> presents a breakthrough solution to this dilemma. Built on an all-in-one concept, it serves as a centralized trading hub integrating multiple functions, designed to help traders explore new trading possibilities while balancing efficiency and risk. This article provides an in-depth analysis of the Unified Account’s features and practical applications, empowering traders to enhance capital utilization and achieve seamless asset management.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gate-io-unified-account-a-powerful-tool-for-efficiency-and-risk-control"><strong>Gate.io Unified Account: A Powerful Tool for Efficiency and Risk Control</strong></h2>



<p>The core value of <a href="https://www.gate.io/unified-trading-account/?ch=GM_accountbein_20250312&amp;utm_campaign=TR_EM47Oge5&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gate.io Unified Account</a> lies in its ability to offer convenience and profitability to users. With support for 160+ assets collateral as margin, shared margin across different trading products, offsetting profits and losses across positions, and even using unrealized profits as margin, this design maximizes capital efficiency, ensuring that every dollar makes greater value for traders.</p>



<p>At the same time, trading complexity is significantly reduced. Within a Unified Account, users can directly trade Spot, Margin, USDT Perpetual Futures, and Options without the hassle of transferring funds between multiple accounts. This streamlines operations and enhances execution speed.</p>



<p>Another standout feature is centralized risk management. As long as the total assets in the account meet the initial and maintenance margin requirements, users can continue opening or holding positions. The system calculates risk across all positions, effectively preventing liquidation cascades triggered by a single asset.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-four-unified-account-modes-tailored-for-different-trading-needs"><strong>Four Unified Account Modes: Tailored for Different Trading Needs</strong></h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-classic-spot-mode-the-ideal-choice-for-beginners-and-conservative-investors"><strong>Classic Spot Mode: The Ideal Choice for Beginners and Conservative Investors</strong></h3>



<p>The Classic Spot Mode offers a moderate level of risk, learning curve, and capital utilization, making it suitable for the following users:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Beginners who lack experience with margin trading and have a low risk tolerance;</li>



<li>Long-term holders focused on accumulating spot assets;</li>



<li>Fiat traders who only purchase and hold cryptocurrencies using fiat currency.</li>
</ul>



<p>In clear bullish or bearish trends, users can trade spot assets directly without leveraging to amplify gains or risks. For beginners, small-scale test trades help them familiarize themselves with the platform without the complexity of advanced functions. Additionally, stablecoin savings is a key feature of this mode, allowing users to deposit USDT, USDC, and other stablecoins to earn interest without using leverage.</p>



<p>From a strategic perspective, auto-investing in spot is a common approach, where users regularly purchase and hold BTC, ETH, and other major cryptocurrencies to mitigate cost fluctuations and reduce market volatility risks. Grid trading, which automates buy-low and sell-high operations within a defined price range, is ideal for users with some experience. Cross-platform arbitrage is another feasible strategy, allowing users to profit from price differences across exchanges, though it requires manual fund transfers.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-single-currency-margin-mode-a-stable-choice-for-low-leverage-trading"><strong>Single-Currency Margin Mode: A Stable Choice for Low-Leverage Trading</strong></h3>



<p>The single-currency margin mode offers a moderate risk level, learning curve, and capital utilization rate, making it suitable for two main types of users:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>New futures traders who are trying leverage trading for the first time, looking to gain experience while managing risks;</li>



<li>Directional traders with a strong bullish or bearish outlook on a specific asset, aiming to amplify returns through leverage.</li>
</ul>



<p>In terms of trading strategies, this mode supports low-leverage, stable trading. Users can opt for 2-5x leverage, effectively reducing liquidation risks. A fundamental approach in this mode is one-way leveraged trading, where users open long positions when expecting a price increase and short positions when anticipating a decline, using USDT as margin. Additionally, a laddered take-profit and stop-loss strategy is commonly used—by placing incremental orders, traders can lock in profits and manage risks amid market fluctuations.</p>



<p>This mode exclusively supports USDT as margin, isolating spot holdings of other assets for improved risk management and trading convenience.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-cross-currency-margin-mode-a-high-efficiency-strategy-for-multi-asset-trading"><strong>Cross-Currency Margin Mode: A High-Efficiency Strategy for Multi-Asset Trading</strong></h3>



<p>The cross-currency margin mode involves a medium-to-high risk level and learning curve but offers superior capital utilization, making it ideal for:</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Multi-asset holders of BTC, ETH, SOL, and other assets, looking to optimize capital efficiency</li>



<li>Arbitrage traders who are profiting from price discrepancies between different assets, such as BTC/ETH exchange rate fluctuations, as well as those skilled in spot-futures arbitrage or funding rate arbitrage;</li>



<li>Intermediate to advanced traders who are proficient in leverage mechanics and capable of managing multi-currency collateral risks effectively.</li>
</ul>



<p>This mode supports multi-asset collateral loans, allowing users to use BTC or other assets as collateral to borrow USDT for trading other futures pairs, enhancing capital flexibility. Moreover, cross-currency hedging is possible. For example, a user holding ETH spot can open a BTC short position to hedge against systemic market risks. Additionally, this mode eliminates the need for frequent asset conversions, allowing traders to directly use their holdings as margin.</p>



<p>The core strategy in this mode is cross-margin arbitrage—users can collateralize Asset A to open leveraged positions in Asset B, leveraging price discrepancies. Furthermore, traders can engage in a collateral-loan-recollateralize cycle to amplify capital efficiency, though careful risk management is required.</p>



<p>It’s important to note that different assets have varying collateral discount rates, so users must closely monitor collateral price fluctuations to avoid insufficient margin, which may lead to forced liquidation.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-portfolio-margin-mode-the-ultimate-solution-for-professional-trading-and-complex-strategies"><strong>Portfolio Margin Mode: The Ultimate Solution for Professional Trading and Complex Strategies</strong></h3>



<p>The portfolio margin mode involves a high-risk level and an advanced learning curve but offers exceptional capital efficiency, making it best suited for：</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li>Options traders who specialize in options and other sophisticated derivatives;</li>



<li>Institutions and professional traders requiring advanced risk control mechanisms to maximize capital efficiency.</li>
</ul>



<p>A key strategy in this mode is delta-neutral trading, which combines spot, futures, and options to bring the overall delta close to zero, reducing the impact of directional market volatility. Another vital strategy is volatility arbitrage, where users profit from calendar spread arbitrage or strike arbitrage of options.</p>



<p>However, this mode demands a high level of expertise. Users must be proficient in Value-at-Risk (VaR) models and stress testing to manage complex risk exposures effectively. Therefore, portfolio margin mode is recommended only for high-net-worth, highly experienced traders.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-unlock-a-new-era-of-trading-efficiency-and-risk-management"><strong>Unlock a New Era of Trading Efficiency and Risk Management</strong></h2>



<p>Gate.io Unified Account is an essential tool for efficiency-driven traders. By selecting the appropriate mode, users can find the optimal balance between risk control and capital utilization, tailoring their strategies to different market conditions. From beginners to professional traders, Gate.io Unified Account offers tailored trading methods to optimize asset management and enhance trading performance.</p>


<section id="block_67dbca1f0d80f" data-el="bic-block-highlighted-paragraph" data-analytics='{&quot;en&quot;:&quot;highlighted-paragraph&quot;,&quot;ec&quot;:&quot;web:desktop:highlighted-paragraph&quot;,&quot;el&quot;:&quot;highlighted-paragraph-block&quot;,&quot;ev&quot;:&quot;&quot;}' class="c-bic-highlighted-text mb-8 md:mb-12 ">
    <div class="flex items-center gap-5 px-5 py-4 rounded-xl bg-grey-50 text-dark-grey-700">
            <div class="bic-block-highlighted-paragraph-content p3 p3--ns [&#038;_p:last-child]:!mb-0 [&#038;_p]:!leading-6 [&#038;_p]:!font-body [&#038;_p]:!text-4 [&#038;_a]:!text-blue-600">
        <p><strong>Disclaimer: </strong>The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/"> Gate.io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement">User Agreement</a>.</p>

      </div>
    </div>
  </section>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/gate-io-unified-account-practical-guide-asset-management/">Gate.io Unified Account: A Practical Guide to One-Stop Asset Management</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-2-4.png" medium="image" width="2514" height="1400" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/image-2-4.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blockchain for Everyone: Making Decentralization Accessible</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-for-everyone-making-decentralization-accessible/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 09:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blockchain news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=674312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In a rapidly evolving world, few innovations have captured the imagination and transformative potential of people like blockchain. For Alessio Vinassa, CEO of BlockTechGroup, this technology is more than just a breakthrough in digital transactions—it represents an opportunity to foster shared success, bridge gaps, and create a more inclusive future. His vision is simple but &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-for-everyone-making-decentralization-accessible/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-for-everyone-making-decentralization-accessible/">Blockchain for Everyone: Making Decentralization Accessible</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a rapidly evolving world, few innovations have captured the imagination and transformative potential of people like blockchain. For Alessio Vinassa, CEO of BlockTechGroup, this technology is more than just a breakthrough in digital transactions—it represents an opportunity to foster shared success, bridge gaps, and create a more inclusive future. His vision is simple but profound: blockchain should be accessible to everyone, regardless of their background or expertise.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-power-of-shared-success-in-blockchain">The Power of Shared Success in Blockchain</h2>



<p>Alessio Vinassa has long advocated for an approach he calls &#8220;shared success.&#8221; In an industry often focused on individual gains, he believes the true strength of blockchain lies in its ability to bring people together. “Blockchain is more than a financial tool—it’s a connector,” he asserts. “When we embrace collaboration, we multiply the potential for innovation.”</p>



<p>This philosophy extends beyond words. At BlockTechGroup, the principle of shared success is embedded in the company’s foundation. Working with over 35 projects, Alessio and his team foster an environment where knowledge-sharing and collaboration thrive. By encouraging developers, entrepreneurs, and users to support each other, they create a culture of resilience and sustainable growth.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-breaking-down-barriers-to-blockchain-adoption">Breaking Down Barriers to Blockchain Adoption</h2>



<p>One of the greatest challenges facing blockchain today is accessibility. While its potential is immense, the complexity of blockchain technology often deters new users. Alessio envisions a future where onboarding is seamless, and participation is intuitive. “Blockchain has the potential to be as transformative as the internet, but for that to happen, we need to lower the barriers to entry,” he explains.</p>



<p>This means building platforms that are easy to use, offering educational resources, and fostering communities that welcome newcomers. Alessio and his team are committed to simplifying blockchain interactions so that anyone—from first-time users to seasoned developers—can engage with and benefit from decentralization.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-future-of-blockchain-in-everyday-life">The Future of Blockchain in Everyday Life</h2>



<p>Looking ahead, Alessio believes blockchain will become a foundational part of how people interact, transact, and share knowledge. While financial applications are at the forefront today, he sees the real impact emerging in decentralized services that empower individuals. From secure data sharing to peer-to-peer solutions, blockchain’s role in daily life is only beginning to take shape.</p>



<p>“The future of blockchain isn’t just about technology—it’s about people,” Alessio emphasizes. “It’s about creating systems where users have greater control, where transparency is the norm, and where communities drive progress.” He envisions a world where open-source collaboration fuels meaningful solutions to real-world challenges, making blockchain a truly democratizing force.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-a-call-to-action-join-the-movement">A Call to Action: Join the Movement</h2>



<p>For those new to blockchain, Alessio’s advice is straightforward: start with the fundamentals. Understanding key principles like decentralization, transparency, and community-driven innovation provides a strong foundation. More importantly, he encourages individuals to find like-minded communities, ask questions, and actively participate.</p>



<p>“Blockchain is still evolving, and there’s a place for everyone,” he says. “Whether you’re a developer, an artist, or simply curious, you have something to contribute. The key is to learn together and grow as a community.”</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-driving-innovation-with-purpose">Driving Innovation with Purpose</h2>



<p>At the heart of Alessio Vinassa’s work is a commitment to making blockchain more than just a technology—it’s about impact, empowerment, and shared growth. “The real motivation comes from the people,” he reflects. “The visionaries, the builders, and those who believe in blockchain’s potential to create a better future. That’s what drives me forward.”</p>



<p>As blockchain continues to evolve, leaders like Alessio remind us of its core purpose: to unite, empower, and create opportunities for all. The future of decentralization isn’t just about code—it’s about people coming together to shape a more inclusive digital world.</p>



<p>To know more about Alessio Vinassa and his business philosophies, visit his website at <a href="https://alessiovinassa.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">alessiovinassa</a><a href="https://alessiovinassa.io/">.io</a>. You can also find and follow him on the following social media channels:<a href="https://www.instagram.com/alessiovinassa.business" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Instagram</a> – <a href="https://www.facebook.com/alessiovinassa.business" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Facebook</a> &#8211; <a href="https://twitter.com/vinassa_alessio" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blockchain-for-everyone-making-decentralization-accessible/">Blockchain for Everyone: Making Decentralization Accessible</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/IMG_7580.png" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/IMG_7580.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Telegram Mini App with millions of users migrate to Solana</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/telegram-mini-app-with-millions-of-users-migrate-to-solana/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana (SOL) News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Telegram News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=670736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>PAWS, a popular Telegram Mini App, migrates to Solana in reaction to newly imposed requirements by the social media platform. Telegram recently introduced a policy mandating all Mini Apps and third-party crypto wallets on its platform to exclusively operate on TON, sparking debates about decentralization and preventing multichain expansion. Under this arrangement, Telegram Mini Apps &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/telegram-mini-app-with-millions-of-users-migrate-to-solana/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/telegram-mini-app-with-millions-of-users-migrate-to-solana/">Telegram Mini App with millions of users migrate to Solana</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>PAWS, a popular Telegram Mini App, migrates to Solana in reaction to newly imposed requirements by the social media platform.</strong></p>



<p>Telegram recently introduced a policy mandating all Mini Apps and third-party crypto wallets on its platform to <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/telegram-ton-wallet-mandate-crypto-mini-apps" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">exclusively operate on TON</a>, sparking debates about decentralization and preventing multichain expansion. Under this arrangement, Telegram Mini Apps that operated across multiple blockchains had to choose between running solely on TON or leaving the ecosystem altogether.</p>



<p>Among the apps that faced this dilemma is <a href="https://paws.community/app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PAWS</a>, a SocialFi project rewarding users for engagement. Rather than remaining confined to a closed ecosystem, PAWS made the decision to migrate to Solana.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-boosting-the-solana-ecosystem">Boosting the Solana ecosystem</h2>



<p>Moving PAWS’ quickly-amassed user base of 80 millions to Solana resulted in significant additional traffic and boosted the ecosystem. Since the migration, users downloaded over 9 million Phantom crypto wallets and funded more than 1 million new Solana addresses, all happening before PAWS’ token generation event (TGE).</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="581" height="742" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-06_15-00-06.jpg" alt="pawn x" class="wp-image-670785" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-06_15-00-06.jpg 581w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-06_15-00-06-282x360.jpg 282w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/photo_2025-03-06_15-00-06-150x192.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 581px) 100vw, 581px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/learn/what-are-nfts-and-why-are-they-revolutionizing-the-art-world">Non-fungible </a><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/learn/what-are-nfts-and-why-are-they-revolutionizing-the-art-world" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">token</a><a href="https://cointelegraph.com/learn/what-are-nfts-and-why-are-they-revolutionizing-the-art-world"> (NFT)</a> vouchers offered by PAWS also became a significant presence on Solana-based NFT marketplace Magic Eden, sparking more than 100,000 transactions in two weeks. Such developments showcase that a committed community can follow a project through migration to a different chain if the underlying product remains accessible and engaging.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-value-extraction-versus-value-injection">Value extraction versus value injection</h2>



<p>The migration revived a long-standing debate revolving around value extraction and value injection. Many blockchain initiatives rely on short bursts of liquidity or speculative token trading, often resulting in value extraction from underlying ecosystems. These models can drive abrupt capital inflows and outflows, intensifying market volatility and exposing ecosystem participants to sudden risks.</p>



<p>The trend is especially relevant for Solana, where high volatility memecoins and <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/news/solana-memecoin-crime-capital-flow-negative-users-drop-40" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">recent rug pulls</a> caused significant capital flight. In contrast, PAWS <a href="https://cointelegraph.com/explained/is-paws-telegram-mini-app-legit-what-you-need-to-know" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">put emphasis on sustained user participation</a> rather than relying solely on speculative token gains. By presenting a model that focuses on consistent engagement, the project seeks to build an ever-growing community growth.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-building-an-intellectual-property">Building an intellectual property</h2>



<p>The Solana migration involves a rebranding process to turn the project into an intellectual property and position it as a long-lasting Web3 brand. Moving forward, PAWS aims to evolve from a viral Telegram application into a full-fledged Web3 brand with multiple revenue streams and strong community loyalty.</p>



<p>To achieve this, the project plans to grow its ecosystem through DeFi integrations, gaming partnerships and social engagement tools. Realizing the multichain possibility is on the radar as well, with plans to expand across Ethereum, layer-2 chains and beyond.</p>



<p>Beyond the crypto space, PAWS seeks to establish itself as a recognizable brand through real-world activations, strategic partnerships and mainstream media presence. A key part of this vision is a sustainable token economy, where holders and community members actively participate in governance and ecosystem development.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="PAWS OR GET PAWSED" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T3_fYxl14Ow?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>The transition from a highly engaged Mini App to a sustainable Web3 brand can set a large-scale example of how meme culture can evolve into a legitimate business model within the crypto space.</p>



<p>The broader significance of PAWS’ transition lies in its potential to set a precedent: Can Telegram’s retail-heavy user base become active participants in permissionless blockchain ecosystems? If successful, PAWS may serve as a model for future Web3 projects looking to bridge the gap between closed platforms and decentralized networks.</p>



<p><strong>Learn more about <a href="https://paws.community/app" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">PAWS</a>.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/telegram-mini-app-with-millions-of-users-migrate-to-solana/">Telegram Mini App with millions of users migrate to Solana</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/234243-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1450" height="967" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/234243-1.jpg"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
