<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
>

<channel>
	<title>Altcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<atom:link href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/</link>
	<description>Cryptocurrency News</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:41:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/cropped-bic_favic-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Altcoin News Today - BeInCrypto</title>
	<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-news/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Altcoin Season: How Retail Investors Can Find Altcoin Winners After Market Recovery</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-find-altcoin-winners-early/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Harsh Notariya]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=677913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Altcoin season has evolved—indiscriminate gains are gone. Retail investors now need strong research and tools to spot future winners early.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-find-altcoin-winners-early/">Altcoin Season: How Retail Investors Can Find Altcoin Winners After Market Recovery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The crypto market’s “altcoin season” isn’t what it used to be. In past cycles, Bitcoin rallies gave way to altcoin booms, lifting almost every token. Now, new market trends suggest those days of indiscriminate gains are fading.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Analysts predict a more selective altcoin cycle – “the era of everything pumping is over.” In an interview with BeInCrypto, Hitesh Malviya, the founder of the crypto analytical tool DYOR, said that retail investors looking for the next big winner must adapt to these evolving trends.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-to-find-winning-altcoins-amidst-choppy-markets">How to Find Winning Altcoins Amidst Choppy Markets</h2>



<p>Traditionally, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-signs-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">altcoin season</a> meant Bitcoin’s dominance fell, and most altcoins surged. That broad rally may be ending.&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If the idea of a full-blown alt season comes from past cycles, then that’s something I really don’t expect. What we have seen so far in altcoins was simply the blooming and bursting of a bubble that happened over two bull cycles and two bear cycles,” Malviya told BeInCrypto.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Market experts foresee a more nuanced phase where only the strongest projects thrive. In short, instead of a rising tide lifting all boats, the next altcoin season may favor quality (projects with real usage and revenue) over quantity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investors should <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/fundamental-analysis-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">focus on fundamentals</a> like usage, revenue, and community growth—the market now rewards substance over hype. Indeed, interest in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-ai-agent-bear-market-defai/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">speculative sectors</a> such as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/meme-coins-to-watch-today-osaka-vine-meow/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coins</a> has drastically declined since late January 2025.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The adoption curve will take a new shape upwards, while the speculative curve will lose its charm, introducing lower volatility in the market, providing more stable returns, and making the market less correlated to stocks. This will create a new asset class in crypto, which should have two major types of asset offerings—tokenized equities with strong cash flow (e.g., AAVE) and store-of-value assets (BTC, ETH),” Malviya continued.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1510" height="521" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM.png" alt="
Strength of Crypto Narratives" class="wp-image-685865" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM.png 1510w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM-360x124.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM-850x293.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM-768x265.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.24.09 PM-150x52.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1510px) 100vw, 1510px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Strength of Crypto Narratives in the Last 90 Days. Source: <a href="https://app.dyor.ag/market-momentum?topIndex=gamma&amp;theme=relative-strength&amp;historicalChartSelect=Blockchain+Service+Infra-Blue+Chip+DeFi-DeFi+3.0-DePIN-Decentralised+AI&amp;showAs=90D&amp;order=desc&amp;sort=90D_relativeStrength&amp;strength=optimisedRelativeStrength" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DYOR</a></figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow"></blockquote>



<p>A key reason for the evolution of the altcoin season is that liquidity now rotates between different narratives. </p>



<p>Liquidity flows toward compelling stories. There have been mini-cycles where certain themes catch fire – meme coins, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/elon-musk-openai-bid-ai-tokens/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AI tokens</a>, DeFi projects, metaverse gaming, etc. Money chases one hot narrative, then moves to the next.</p>



<p>Savvy investors watch social media, developer activity, and news to catch emerging narratives early and get in before the crowd.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Liquidity will always flow into different narratives at different times, as there are multiple categories within crypto—just like in stocks, where some categories always outperform others. The same market dynamics will be seen in crypto as well,” Malviya stated.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-how-to-find-potential-altcoin-season-winner-identifying-strength-in-downtrends">How to Find Potential Altcoin Season Winner? Identifying Strength in Downtrends</h2>



<p>Malviya believes that investors should watch for altcoins showing relative strength during downturns. If an altcoin can hold its value or even rise while <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-decline-miners-join-selloff/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin slides</a>, that resilience signals strong demand (likely early accumulation).&nbsp;</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“At DYOR, we offer a metric called Optimised Relative Strength, which helps track some of the best coins and narratives that have shown the highest strength in the past 7, 30 and 90 days.&nbsp;Coins that have outperformed against the broader market in the past 30 days have a great chance of rallying when the market finds a bottom and starts a fresh leg up,&#8221; Malviya explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1523" height="646" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM.png" alt="Top Coins by Optimised Relative Strength in the Past 7 Days" class="wp-image-685866" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM.png 1523w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM-360x153.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM-850x361.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM-768x326.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-9.35.08 PM-150x64.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1523px) 100vw, 1523px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Top Coins by Optimised Relative Strength in the Past 7 Days. Source: <a href="https://app.dyor.ag/market-momentum?topIndex=alpha&amp;theme=daily-top-indexes&amp;historicalChartSelect=Blockchain+Service+Infra-Blue+Chip+DeFi-DeFi+3.0-DePIN-Decentralised+AI&amp;showAs=30D&amp;order=desc&amp;sort=90D_relativeStrength&amp;strength=optimisedRelativeStrength" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">DYOR</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Moreover, Malviya also discussed other fundamental metrics to track. These include: </p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>DEX Volume:</strong> Rising trading volumes on decentralized exchanges can push the native token&#8217;s prices higher.</li>



<li><strong>Total Value Locked (TVL):</strong> Growth in deposits and total value locked implies user trust – bullish for the lending protocol’s token.</li>



<li><strong>Derivatives Volume:</strong> Increasing on-chain trading activity means more traders and fees supporting its token.</li>



<li><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><strong>Oracle Total Value Secured (TVS):</strong>&nbsp;Climbing total value secured by an oracle (e.g., <a href="https://beincrypto.com/paypal-support-solana-chainlink/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Chainlink</a>) shows a greater reliance on it, boosting token demand.</span></li>



<li><strong>DePIN Revenue:</strong> Actual revenue from a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/depin-tokenomics-crypto-fluence/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DePIN project</a> (real-world service) signals a sustainable model, not just hype.</li>
</ul>



<p>Furthermore, Malviya also emphasized the tokenomics of a crypto project. He believes that even a great project can falter if its tokenomics are flawed.</p>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/tokenomics-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Tokenomics</a> – a token’s supply and incentive design can make or break an altcoin. Good tokenomics (fair distribution, strong utility) create lasting demand, whereas poor tokenomics (excessive inflation or constant insider unlocks) often doom a project.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Ideally, the community and ecosystem fund should get at least 60% of the supply to generate actual demand for the product by incentivizing developers and users through planned token emissions at different stages. Tokens are actually created to drive real user demand for the product. They can be considered as bribes to get user attention, but since these bribes are also tradable in the market, they can create a ripple effect that could potentially lead to the product&#8217;s failure. This happens because retail sentiment often mixes both the product and the token, where, in most cases, the token price eventually determines how much adoption the product gets,&#8221; Malviya elaborated.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Lastly, he shares tools that can help users potentially find the next winner for the altcoin season.</p>



<ul class="bic-gutenberg-list wp-list list-disc " class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>DYOR</strong> – Users can use DYOR to find relative strength data on more than 200+ coins, detailed demand-side tokenomics data on 70+ coins, and fundamental data on 65+ coins, along with detailed research reports on top projects.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/defillama-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DeFiLlama</a></strong> – It tracks multi-chain DeFi data like TVL and volumes.</li>



<li><strong><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/dune-analytics/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Dune Analytics</a></strong> – It is a community-driven platform offering custom on-chain data dashboards.</li>
</ul>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;The community should learn to use DeFiLlama and DUNE dashboards to uncover some interesting alphas. Most on-chain data is tracked on both of these platforms—all you need to do is find the right dashboard, take notes of the different growth metrics you notice, and build your thesis around a coin using that data to reach better due diligence,&#8221; Malviya concluded.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Those armed with solid research stand the best chance of catching the next altcoin season winner.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-find-altcoin-winners-early/">Altcoin Season: How Retail Investors Can Find Altcoin Winners After Market Recovery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_Altcoin_Season-covers_bull.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_Altcoin_Season-covers_bull.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sonic Blockchain Hits $1 Billion TVL in Just 66 Days Amid Crypto Market Turmoil</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/sonic-blockchain-tvl-capital-flows/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nhat Hoang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 11:41:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=686031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sonic defies 2025's crypto downturn, reaching $1 billion in TVL faster than any major chain. But sustaining this momentum remains uncertain.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sonic-blockchain-tvl-capital-flows/">Sonic Blockchain Hits $1 Billion TVL in Just 66 Days Amid Crypto Market Turmoil</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The crypto market in 2025 is facing intense turbulence. The capitalization of once-hot trends like meme coins has plummeted. Capital has flowed out of decentralized finance (DeFi) protocols, driving DeFi’s total value locked (TVL) down from $120 billion to around $87 billion.</strong></p>



<p>In this context, Sonic stands out. It has consistently hit new TVL highs, reaching $1 billion in April after growing nearly 40 times since the beginning of the year. So, what makes Sonic a bright spot amid a stormy market?</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-investors-are-pouring-capital-into-sonic">Investors Are Pouring Capital into Sonic</h2>



<p>Sonic has made its mark with a rapid TVL growth rate, far outpacing better-known blockchains. According to DefiLlama, Sonic reached $1 billion in TVL within 66 days. In comparison, Sui took 505 days, and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/aptos-crypto-apt/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Aptos</a> needed 709.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1200" height="683" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT.jpg" alt="Race to $1 Billion in TVL. Source: Decentralised " class="wp-image-686033" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT.jpg 1200w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT-360x205.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT-850x484.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT-768x437.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoKzfCBXYAAJoDT-150x85.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Race to $1 Billion in TVL. Source: <a href="https://www.decentralised.co/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Decentralised </a></figcaption></figure>



<p>This achievement reflects strong capital inflows into the Sonic ecosystem despite the broader DeFi trend of capital withdrawal. Data from <a href="https://app.artemisanalytics.com/flows" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Artemis</a> supports this, ranking Sonic as the second-highest netflow protocol this year—trailing only <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-base-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Base</a>, a blockchain backed by Coinbase.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="392" height="494" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-142720.png" alt="Top 20 Net Flows. Source: Artemis" class="wp-image-686034" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-142720.png 392w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-142720-286x360.png 286w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-142720-150x189.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Top 20 Net Flows. Source: <a href="https://app.artemisanalytics.com/flows" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Artemis</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The growth goes beyond TVL numbers. Sonic’s ecosystem is attracting various projects, including derivatives exchanges like Aark Digital and Shadow Exchange and protocols such as Snake Finance, Equalizer0x, and Beets. These projects still have small TVLs, but they have the potential to draw new users and capital, fueling Sonic’s momentum.</p>



<p>However, the question remains: Can this capital inflow remain sustainable while the market fluctuates?</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-andre-cronje-on-sonic-s-potential-and-strengths">Andre Cronje on Sonic’s Potential and Strengths</h2>



<p>Andre Cronje, the developer behind Sonic, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbDN5gXW4yc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">shared</a> his ambition in an interview to push this blockchain beyond its competitors.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Sonic has sub-200 millisecond finality, faster than human responsiveness,” Andre Cronje <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbDN5gXW4yc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>According to Cronje, Sonic isn&#8217;t just about speed. The platform also focuses on improving both user and developer experience. He explained that 90% of transaction fees go to dApp, not to validators, creating incentives for developers to build. </p>



<p>Unlike other blockchains, such as Ethereum, which are limited by long block times, Sonic leverages an enhanced virtual machine that theoretically processes up to 400,000 transactions per second. Cronje acknowledges, however, that current demand has yet to push the network to its full capacity. Still, these technical advantages make Sonic a compelling option for developers seeking more user-friendly dApps.</p>



<p>He also revealed new features on Sonic that have the potential to attract users.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If your first touch point with a user is to download this wallet and then buy this token on an exchange, you&#8217;ve lost 99.9% of your users. They&#8217;ll use their Google off-email password, fingerprint, face, whatever it is, to access the dApp and interact with it, and they&#8217;ll never need to know about Sonic or token,” Andre Cronje <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vbDN5gXW4yc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">revealed</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-risks-and-challenges-ahead">Risks and Challenges Ahead</h2>



<p>Despite reaching impressive milestones, Sonic is not immune to risk. The price of its token, S, has declined significantly from its peak. According to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/sonic-3/">BeInCrypto</a>, it has dropped around 20% in the past month—from $0.60 down to $0.47—mirroring the broader market’s volatility.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1373" height="543" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530.png" alt="Sonic (S) Price Performance. Source: BeInCrypto" class="wp-image-686032" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530.png 1373w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530-360x142.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530-850x336.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530-768x304.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-11-144530-150x59.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1373px) 100vw, 1373px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Sonic (S) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/sonic-3/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Furthermore, Grayscale recently <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-assets-under-consideration-q2-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">removed Sonic</a> from its April asset consideration list. This decision reflects a shift in the fund’s expectations and raises concerns about Sonic’s ability to maintain its TVL should investor sentiment deteriorate.</p>



<p>Sonic also faces fierce competition from other high-performance chains like Solana and Base. Although Sonic holds a clear advantage in speed, long-term user adoption will depend on whether its ecosystem can deliver real value, not just high TVL figures. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/sonic-blockchain-tvl-capital-flows/">Sonic Blockchain Hits $1 Billion TVL in Just 66 Days Amid Crypto Market Turmoil</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bic_fantom_FTM-covers_coins_bullish_neutral.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/bic_fantom_FTM-covers_coins_bullish_neutral.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grayscale Reveals List of 40 Altcoins For Q2 &#8220;Assets Under Consideration&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-assets-under-consideration-q2-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kamina Bashir]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 08:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685982</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Grayscale's Q2 2025 update showcases a reshaped altcoins list with key removals and additions, reflecting the firm's evolving strategy in the crypto market. The focus is on emerging projects with strong growth potential.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-assets-under-consideration-q2-2025/">Grayscale Reveals List of 40 Altcoins For Q2 &#8220;Assets Under Consideration&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Grayscale, a leading digital asset manager, has revealed the latest update to its “Assets Under Consideration” list for the second quarter of 2025.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The list includes a diverse array of altcoins that could likely shape the firm’s future offerings.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-grayscale-removes-kaspa-and-other-key-altcoins-in-q2-2025-update">Grayscale Removes Kaspa and Other Key Altcoins in Q2 2025 Update</h2>



<p>In this latest iteration, Grayscale&#8217;s “Assets Under Consideration” list features 40 altcoins. The update indeed marks a significant overhaul of the<a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-announces-new-investible-digital-assets/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> firm’s January 2025 list</a>, which had 39 assets. Previously, 35 assets were included <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-reveals-35-altcoins-under-consideration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">in the October 2024 version</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We’re excited to share this list of assets under consideration for inclusion in future Grayscale investment products,” the <a href="https://www.grayscale.com/blog/general-updates/assets-under-consideration-current-products" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">blog</a> read.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-table is-style-stripes"><table class="w-full mb-2 table-auto"><tbody><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><strong>Grayscale Crypto Sector</strong></td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left"><strong>Assets Under Consideration</strong></td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Smart Contract Platforms</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Aptos (APT)<br>Arbitrum (ARB)<br>Babylon*<br>Berachain (BERA)*<br>Celestia (TIA)<br>Hedera Hashgraph (HBAR)<br>Mantle (MNT)<br>Monad*<br>Movement (MOVE)*<br>Toncoin (TON)<br>TRON (TRX)<br>VeChain (VET)<br></td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Financials&nbsp;</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Aerodrome (AERO)<br>Binance Coin (BNB)<br>Ethena (ENA)<br>Hyperliquid (HYPE)<br>Jupiter (JUP)<br>Lombard*<br>Mantra (OM)*<br>Maple (SYRUP)*<br>Ondo Finance (ONDO)<br>Pendle (PENDLE)<br>Plume Network (PLUME)<br></td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Consumer &amp; Culture</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Aixbt by Virtuals (AIXBT)<br>Eliza (ELIZA)*<br>Immutable (IMX)<br>Story (IP)&nbsp;<br></td></tr><tr class="border-grey-200  border-y bg-white [&#038;_th]:bg-white"><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Utilities &amp; Services</td><td class="px-2.5 lg:px-4 py-2 lg:py-3.5 p5 p5--medium lg:p4 lg:p4--medium border-r border-white text-left">Akash Network (AKT)<br>Artificial Superintelligence Alliance (FET)<br>Arweave (AR)<br>DeepBook (DEEP)*<br>Eigen Layer (EIGEN)<br>Geodnet (GEOD)<br>Grass (GRASS)*<br>Helium (HNT)<br>Jito (JTO)<br>Prime Intellect*<br>Sentient*<br>Space and Time*<br>Walrus (WAL)* &nbsp;</td></tr></tbody></table><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Grayscale List of Potential Investible Assets. Source: <a href="https://www.grayscale.com/blog/general-updates/assets-under-consideration-current-products" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Grayscale</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>One of the most notable <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/kaspa-guide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">changes is the removal of Kaspa</a> from the list’s currencies section. Notably, this update does not include any assets in this category.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, Grayscale has excluded Sei, Sonic, and Starknet from the smart contract platforms category. The financials sector also saw some changes, with the asset manager dropping THORChain and Injective Protocol from the list.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Consumer and Culture category has also seen removals of Ai16z and Virtuals Protocol. Lastly, Grayscale has eliminated Flock.io, Hyperbolic,<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-worldcoin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> and Worldcoin from the Utilities and Services category</a>. This reduction hints at the firm’s recalibration of what it considers to be foundational utilities in the changing crypto sector.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-new-asset-additions-for-q2-2025">New Asset Additions for Q2 2025</h2>



<p>Meanwhile, these removals have paved the way for the addition of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-vechain" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">several assets, including VeChain</a>. It is now incorporated into the smart contract platforms category, signaling a growing interest in the project’s potential. Moreover, Plume Network was spotted in Financials and Aixbt by Virtuals in Consumer and Culture.</p>



<p>Previously, Grayscale&#8217;s Q2 2025 <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-top-20-list-altcoins-q2/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Top 20 list highlighted Maple Finance, Geodnet, and Story for their strong growth potential</a>. IP, which was previously listed under Utilities and Services, has now been moved to the Consumer and Culture category. Meanwhile, SYRUP has been added to the Financials category, and GEOD has joined Utilities and Services.</p>



<p>Grayscale’s Q2 2025 update also introduces several assets that have yet to be classified under the Grayscale crypto sectors framework. Among these new additions are Babylon, Berachain, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/monad-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Monad, Movement, Lombard</a>, Mantra, Eliza, DeepBook, and Walrus. Prime Intellect, Sentient, Space, and Time, which were featured in the last list, are also included.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We aim to update this list as frequently as 15 days after quarter-end as the crypto ecosystem expands and the Grayscale team reviews or reevaluates additional assets. The list below is as of April 10, 2025, and is subject to change intra-quarter as some multi-asset funds reconstitute and we launch new single-asset products,” Grayscale noted.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Furthermore, two assets that previously appeared on the list, Pyth Network (PYTH) and Dogecoin (DOGE), have now joined Grayscale’s product suite. On January 31, the asset manager<a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-launches-dogecoin-trust/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> launched the Grayscale Dogecoin Trust</a>.</p>



<p>Shortly after, on February 18, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-launches-pyth-trust/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Grayscale <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">introduced</span> its Pyth Trust.</a> Thus, the market now watches closely to see which of the listed assets will transition from consideration to reality.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-assets-under-consideration-q2-2025/">Grayscale Reveals List of 40 Altcoins For Q2 &#8220;Assets Under Consideration&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-1-1.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-1-1.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Market Indicators Suggest Altcoin Season Could Be Near—Here&#8217;s Why</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-signs-2025/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kamina Bashir]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency Market News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=685562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Experts see a potential altcoin rally as Bitcoin Dominance weakens, the Altcoin Season Index drops, and favorable macroeconomic conditions unfold. However, future altcoin seasons may be more selective, focusing on high-liquidity assets.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-signs-2025/">Market Indicators Suggest Altcoin Season Could Be Near—Here&#8217;s Why</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The cryptocurrency market is showing potential signs of an impending altcoin season. Market watchers cite a confluence of technical, sentiment, and macroeconomic factors that could lead to a significant rally in altcoins.</strong></p>



<p>The outlook follows a notable downturn in the altcoin market, which has dropped about 37.6% since its high in early December 2024. As of the latest data, the market cap stands at $1.1 trillion.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-is-altcoin-season-coming-nbsp">Is Altcoin Season Coming?&nbsp;</h2>



<p>From a technical perspective, <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/price/bitcoin/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin (BTC) </a>Dominance, which measures <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-brief-recovery-us-china-tariff-deal-hopes/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin’s market share relative to the total cryptocurrency market</a>, seems to be at a key turning point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A recent chart shared by crypto analyst Mister Crypto on X highlighted that Bitcoin Dominance has reached a resistance following a rising wedge pattern. This pattern is generally seen as a bearish signal, often leading to sharp pullbacks.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1200" height="757" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id.jpeg" alt="Bitcoin Dominance Chart" class="wp-image-685567" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id.jpeg 1200w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id-360x227.jpeg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id-850x536.jpeg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id-768x484.jpeg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GoGtsiQXoAAi-Id-150x95.jpeg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1200px) 100vw, 1200px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin Dominance Chart. Source: <a href="https://x.com/misterrcrypto/status/1910041018856317351" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">X/Mister Crypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Bitcoin Dominance will collapse. Altseason will come. We will all get rich this year!” he wrote.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In addition, another analyst <a href="https://x.com/CryptooELITES/status/1910022397698462008" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">corroborated</a> these findings, noting that Bitcoin Dominance has reached a peak. Thus, he forecasted a subsequent downturn.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However,<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/altcoin-season" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> the Altcoin Season Index has dropped</a> to a low of 16. The index, which analyzes the performance of the top 50 altcoins against Bitcoin, indicated that altcoins are currently underperforming.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2532" height="1242" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM.png" alt="Altcoin Season Index" class="wp-image-685584" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM.png 2532w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-360x177.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-850x417.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-768x377.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-1536x753.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-2048x1005.png 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Screenshot-2025-04-10-at-2.50.20 PM-150x74.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2532px) 100vw, 2532px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Altcoin Season Index. Source: <a href="https://www.blockchaincenter.net/en/altcoin-season-index/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Blockchain Center</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Notably, this level mirrors the<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-are-altcoins" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> bottom for altcoins observed</a> around August 2024. This period preceded a significant altcoin rally, and the index peaked at 88 by December 2024.</p>



<p>Lastly, from a macroeconomic perspective, the 90-day delay in<a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" rel="noreferrer noopener"> President Donald Trump’s tariff implementation</a> has renewed market confidence. This delay is perceived as a positive signal, potentially <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/tariff-pause-crypto-dead-cat-bounce/" rel="noreferrer noopener">encouraging capital inflows into altcoins</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“90 days tariff pause = 90 days of altseason,” an analyst <a href="https://x.com/Darky1k/status/1910033837125419398" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">claimed</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Moreover, analyst Crypto Rover pointed to <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/odds-of-quantitative-easing-crypto-market/" rel="noreferrer noopener">quantitative easing (QE) as a catalyst for an altseason.</a> According to him, when the central bank starts pumping money into the economy (through QE), altcoins could experience a significant price surge, benefiting from the increased liquidity and investor optimism.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Once QE starts. Altcoin season will make a massive comeback!” he <a href="https://x.com/rovercrc/status/1909989177262813501" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, in the latest report, Kaiko Research <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/redefining-altcoin-season-cryptoquant-ceo/" rel="noreferrer noopener">stressed that a traditional altcoin season </a>may no longer be feasible. Instead, any potential rally could be selective, with only a few altcoins experiencing significant upside. The focus will likely be on assets with real-world use cases, strong liquidity, and revenue-generating potential.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Altseasons may become a thing of the past, necessitating a more nuanced categorization beyond just &#8216;altcoins,&#8217; as correlations in returns, growth factors, and liquidity among crypto assets are diverging significantly over time,&#8221; the <a href="https://25446524.fs1.hubspotusercontent-eu1.net/hubfs/25446524/Kaiko%20%20Blockhead%20Are%20Altcoins%20Poised%20for%20a%20Widespread%20Rally.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">report</a> read.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Kaiko Research noted that the growing concentration of liquidity in a few altcoins and Bitcoin may disrupt the typical capital flow into altcoins during market upswings. Furthermore, as Bitcoin becomes more <a target="_blank" href="https://beincrypto.com/us-states-push-crypto-bills-in-march/" rel="noreferrer noopener">widely adopted as a reserve asset</a> by institutions and governments, its position in the market strengthens further.</p>



<p>Ultimately, while the signs point to a potential altcoin rally, it’s clear that the future of altcoins could involve more nuanced market dynamics.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoin-season-signs-2025/">Market Indicators Suggest Altcoin Season Could Be Near—Here&#8217;s Why</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_Altcoin_coin_1-covers_bullish.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_Altcoin_coin_1-covers_bullish.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quantitative Easing in 2025: Analysts Explain What’s at Stake for Bitcoin and Altcoins</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/odds-of-quantitative-easing-crypto-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 09:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inflation News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>With the possibility of the Fed returning to QE, crypto traders are watching for a massive liquidity wave that could spark a historic rally, especially for altcoins.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/odds-of-quantitative-easing-crypto-market/">Quantitative Easing in 2025: Analysts Explain What’s at Stake for Bitcoin and Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Crypto and financial markets, in general, are reeling from renewed volatility and mounting geopolitical pressure. As a result, speculation is intensifying around whether the Federal Reserve (Fed) will pivot back toward Quantitative Easing (QE).</strong></p>



<p>A potential QE would be reminiscent of the aggressive monetary interventions of 2008 and 2020. For crypto, the implications could be enormous, with many traders bracing for a potential V-shaped recovery and a historic rally if QE is revived.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-analysts-share-signals-why-the-fed-could-act">Analysts Share Signals Why the FED Could Act</h2>



<p>Analysts have shared reasons that could prompt the Fed to intervene, with one citing the MOVE Index. This is Wall Street’s “fear gauge” for the bond market. At 137.30, the index is currently within the 130–160 range where the Fed has historically acted during crises.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Now it&#8217;s at 137.30, in the 130–160 range where the Fed might step in, depending on the economy. If they don&#8217;t, they&#8217;ll still cut rates soon because they have to refinance the debt to keep the Ponzi going,” <a href="https://x.com/vandell33/status/1909348024717066271" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> Vandell, co-founder of Black Swan Capitalist.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1292" height="415" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1.png" alt="MOVE Index" class="wp-image-684523" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1.png 1292w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1-360x116.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1-850x273.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1-768x247.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1-150x48.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1292px) 100vw, 1292px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">MOVE Index. Source: <a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/Gn9b9AxXMAAPOQF?format=jpg&amp;name=large" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Vandell on X</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>This signal aligns with other warning signs of financial instability, including global market sell-offs that set the tone for the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-black-monday-liquidations-april-2025/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto black Monday narrative</a>. This prompted the Fed to schedule a <a href="https://beincrypto.com/can-federal-reserve-rate-cuts-revive-crypto-market/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">closed-door board meeting</a> on April 3.</p>



<p>According to analysts, this timing was not random, with mounting pressure likely to see the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-recovery-potential-dxy-drop-fomc/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Fed cave and President Trump having his way</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“With the Fed hinting at QE, everything changes Risk: Reward is now in favor of the bulls. Watch for choppy price action, but do not miss the recovery rally. And remember… it’s easier to trade this market than to hold through it,” <a href="https://x.com/MooninPapa/status/1909452869981663384" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a> Aaron Dishner, a crypto trader and analyst.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This suggests that investors are reading between the lines, particularly with the Fed’s next scheduled policy decision not until May 6–7. JPMorgan recently became the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/5-us-economic-indicators-crypto-april/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">first Wall Street bank to forecast a US recession</a> amid <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/trump-tariffs-crypto-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donald Trump’s proposed tariffs</a>, adding urgency to the conversation.</p>



<p>The bank suggests the Fed may be forced to act sooner, possibly with rate cuts or even QE, before the scheduled FOMC meeting. Against this backdrop, crypto investor Eliz shared a provocative take.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“I honestly think Trump is doing all this to speed up the Fed&#8217;s process to lower rates and QE,” they <a href="https://x.com/eliz883/status/1909312633746117033" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>That may not be far-fetched given that the Fed must also manage over $34 trillion in federal debt. Noteworthy, this becomes harder to service at higher interest rates. According to Polymarket, there is now a 92% chance the Fed will cut rates at some point in 2025.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="765" height="370" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-2.png" alt="Fed rate cut bets" class="wp-image-684526" style="width:1029px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-2.png 765w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-2-360x174.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-2-150x73.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 765px) 100vw, 765px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fed rate cut bets. Source: <a href="https://polymarket.com/event/fed-rate-cut-in-2025?tid=1744089355349" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Polymarket</a></figcaption></figure>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-why-crypto-could-benefit-from-qe">Why Crypto Could Benefit From QE</h2>



<p>Should QE materialize, history suggests crypto could be one of the biggest beneficiaries. BitMEX founder and former CEO Arthur Hayes predicted that QE could inject up to $3.24 trillion into the system, nearly 80% of the amount added during the pandemic.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Bitcoin rose 24x from its COVID-19 low thanks to $4 trillion in stimulus. If we see $3.24 trillion now, BTC could hit $1 million,” he <a href="https://cryptohayes.substack.com/p/kiss-of-death" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This aligns with his recent prediction that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/arthur-hayes-bitcoin-250000-qe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin could reach $250,000 by year-end</a> if the Fed shifts to QE to support markets.</p>



<p>Analyst Brett offered a more measured view, noting that QE typically follows rate cuts rather than precedes them.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“We’re likely going to see rate cuts through mid-2026…like in 2008 and 2020, Powell has said QE doesn&#8217;t come until rate cuts are complete,” Brett <a href="https://x.com/brett_eth/status/1908475676820435221" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">explained</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1079" height="645" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64.png" alt="Fed rate cuts against QE" class="wp-image-684541" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64.png 1079w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64-360x215.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64-850x508.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64-768x459.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/image-64-150x90.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1079px) 100vw, 1079px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fed rate cuts against QE. Source: <a href="https://x.com/brett_eth/status/1908475676820435221" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Brett on X</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>Based on this, the analyst committed to buying selectively but did not expect a V-shaped bounce unless something drastic changed.</p>



<p>That &#8220;something&#8221; could be <a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-tariff-pause-rumors-trigger-crypto-market-rally/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Trump reversing his tariffs</a> or the Fed front running a recession with emergency easing measures. If either happens, the crypto market could rally hard and fast.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-altseason-on-the-horizon">Altseason on the Horizon?</h2>



<p>Meanwhile, Our Crypto Talk <a href="https://x.com/ourcryptotalk/status/1902981715561230787" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">says</a> a Quantitative Easing in May could lay the groundwork for a possible <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coinmarketcap-altcoin-season-index-record-low/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">altcoin season</a>.</p>



<p>Their forecast echoes previous cycles where QE triggered explosive moves in risk assets. When QE kicked off in March 2020, altcoins surged over 100X by the time it ended in 2022.</p>



<p>Traders are now eyeing May as a potential kickoff for the next liquidity wave, with bettors wagering a 75% chance the Fed will hold rates steady. If those odds shift, traders expect the money printer to follow.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="769" height="382" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-3.png" alt="Fed Interest Rates decision in May" class="wp-image-684532" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-3.png 769w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-3-360x179.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-3-150x75.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fed Interest Rates decision in May. Source: <a href="https://polymarket.com/event/fed-decision-in-may-2025?tid=1744089414024" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Polymarket</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>While some anticipate more price “chop” in the short term, most agree that the long-term setup is increasingly favorable.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“If QE really kicks off in May, this chop is just the calm before the giga pump,” <a href="https://x.com/MrBrondorDeFi/status/1903042366929281327" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> MrBrondorDeFi on X.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Even if quantitative easing does not occur immediately, confidence remains strong that it will happen this year. </p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Maybe not May, then later. It will happen this year, which is good for another rally and new highs,” Our Crypto Talk <a href="https://x.com/ourcryptotalk/status/1903044655496761367" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">added</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Therefore, the buck stops with the Fed. Whether it is rate cuts, QE, or both, the implications for crypto are enormous.</p>



<p>If history repeats and the Fed opens the liquidity floodgates again, Bitcoin and altcoins could be poised for a historic breakout. This could eclipse the gains seen during the 2020-2021 bull run.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/odds-of-quantitative-easing-crypto-market/">Quantitative Easing in 2025: Analysts Explain What’s at Stake for Bitcoin and Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_crypto_market_general_5-covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/bic_crypto_market_general_5-covers.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance Delisting Announcement Causes Free Fall for 14 Altcoins</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/binance-delist-14-altcoins-free-fall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 07:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=684464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Binance’s delisting of 14 altcoins causes drastic price declines, with affected users needing to update trading bots before April 16. After June 9, token withdrawals will be unsupported.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-delist-14-altcoins-free-fall/">Binance Delisting Announcement Causes Free Fall for 14 Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Binance, the largest crypto exchange by trading volume metrics, decided to delist 14 altcoins, sending the affected tokens to a free fall.</strong></p>



<p>The platform recently adopted a mechanism to involve its community in the listing and delisting processes.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-to-delist-14-altcoins">Binance To Delist 14 Altcoins</h2>



<p>The exchange revealed the decision on Tuesday, during the early hours of the Asian session. It would delist and cease trading on all <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/spot-trading" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">spot trading</a> pairs for the named tokens starting April 16 at 03:00 (UTC).</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Following the Vote to Delist results and completion of the standard delisting due diligence process, Binance will delist BADGER, BAL, BETA, CREAM, CTXC, ELF, FIRO, HARD, NULS, PROS, SNT, TROY, UFT and VIDT on 2025-04-16,” read the <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/detail/fac9c3e401da4cc8b604566fd261d70c" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">announcement</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The selection of these 14 tokens was reportedly based on a comprehensive evaluation of multiple factors<strong>. </strong>Among them are the level and quality of the development activity, trading volume, and liquidity.</p>



<p>In line with its recent <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-adopts-community-vote-for-token-listing-delist/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decision to involve the community in its listing and delisting plans</a>, the Binance exchange also held a vote. Reportedly, while it received 103,942 votes from 24,141 participants, only 93,680 proved valid.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Community voting results were evaluated after rigorous filtering of ineligible votes and invalid votes,” the exchange articulated.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>In the immediate aftermath of the delisting announcement, the 14 tokens fell over the cliff, with most recording double-digit losses.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="850" height="410" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-850x410.png" alt="BADGER, BAL, BETA, CREAM, NULS, FIRO, TROY, HARD Price performance" class="wp-image-684468" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-850x410.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-360x174.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-768x371.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-1536x741.png 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55-150x72.png 150w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/TROYUSDT_2025-04-08_09-53-55.png 1554w" sizes="(max-width: 850px) 100vw, 850px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">BADGER, BAL, BETA, CREAM, NULS, FIRO, TROY, HARD Price performance. Source: <a href="https://www.tradingview.com/x/0tTxXkyM/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">TradingView</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>The turnout is unsurprising<span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">, as such announcements often cause price d</span>rops for affected tokens. A similar announcement was made recently to delist three altcoins:&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-delisting-announcement-causes-free-fall-for-3-altcoins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">AKRO, BLZ, and WRX</a>. Likewise, their prices dropped by double digits.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-what-binance-users-need-to-do">What Binance Users Need to Do</h2>



<p>Binance said all trade orders will be automatically removed after trading ceases in each trading pair. It will also terminate <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/do-crypto-trading-bots-work" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">trading </a><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;"><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/do-crypto-trading-bots-work" target="_blank" rel="noopener">bot</a>&nbsp;services for the aforementioned spot trading pairs immediately after the delisting occurs</span>.</p>



<p>Based on these guidelines, Binance users should update and/or cancel their trading bots before the delisting to avoid any potential losses.</p>



<p>Notably, once the delisting happens, any outstanding assets will be force-sold at market price or moved to the Spot Account if the amount is unsellable. Similarly, the token&#8217;s valuation will no longer be displayed in users’ accounts after delisting.</p>



<p>Deposits of these tokens will also not be credited to users’ accounts after the delisting time. Meanwhile, withdrawals of these tokens from Binance will not be supported after June 9 at 03:00 UTC.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Delisted tokens may be converted into stablecoins on behalf of users after 2025-06-10 03:00 (UTC),” Binance added.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Meanwhile, it is worth noting that while Binance exchange’s move to involve the community in the listing and delisting bolsters democracy, it drew criticism. As BeInCrypto reported, it drew concerns over whether the exchange gave preferential treatment to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-smart-chain-bsc" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BSC chain tokens</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-delist-14-altcoins-free-fall/">Binance Delisting Announcement Causes Free Fall for 14 Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/bic_warning_crypto_5-covers.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/bic_warning_crypto_5-covers.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Analysts Believe Q2 is a Great Opportunity to Buy Altcoins</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/analyst-believe-q2-will-be-altcoin-season/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nhat Hoang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 21:16:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=683493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As Bitcoin gains dominance, analysts forecast a prime buying opportunity for altcoins in Q2 2025. Could this be the next altcoin season?</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/analyst-believe-q2-will-be-altcoin-season/">Analysts Believe Q2 is a Great Opportunity to Buy Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>As Bitcoin (BTC) continues to dominate with increasing market share, many analysts believe Q2 of 2025 will be the ideal time to accumulate altcoins.</strong></p>



<p>The altcoin market capitalization has dropped 40% from its all-time high (ATH), falling below $1 trillion. Many altcoin investors are facing losses. However, analysts believe this could be the setup phase for an upcoming altcoin season.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-will-q2-see-an-altcoin-season">Will Q2 See an Altcoin Season?</h2>



<p>Joao Wedson, an analyst from Alphractal, pointed out that many altcoins have performed poorly in the current market cycle (2022–2025). </p>



<p>In a post on X, Wedson emphasized that several altcoins have returned to their launch prices. Some of these were once hyped as &#8220;rockets to the moon.&#8221; This indicates a period of accumulation, making it a good time to place buy orders at low prices.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2560" height="1440" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-scaled.jpg" alt="Altcoin Season Index vs Bitcoin" class="wp-image-683496" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-scaled.jpg 2560w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-360x203.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-850x478.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-768x432.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-2048x1152.jpg 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnjS1asXUAAftnG-150x84.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2560px) 100vw, 2560px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Altcoin Season Index vs Bitcoin. Source: <a href="https://x.com/joao_wedson/status/1907506521463755049" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Alphractal</a>.</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Since December 2024, we’ve been in a bear market (actually, the sentiment was already bearish since October). But I still believe that between April and May, the market will heat up for cryptos—even if BTC drops further, as we still have lower targets.” — Joao Wedson, founder of Alphractal, <a href="https://x.com/joao_wedson/status/1907506521463755049" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">predicted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Wedson advises investors to focus on altcoin projects with strong fundamentals and growth potential. He suggests avoiding coins that will be surging in 2024, such as ETH, SOL, and TRX. His strategy is patiently waiting and buying at low prices—a cautious yet promising approach.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, another well-known analyst, Ash Crypto, <a href="https://x.com/Ashcryptoreal/status/1907365414222397860" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">predicts</a> that once Bitcoin&#8217;s dominance reaches 70%, it will signal Bitcoin’s peak. Historically, this level has marked the start of an <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/altcoin-season/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">altcoin season</a> within the following months.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="2048" height="1332" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV.jpg" alt="Bitcoin Dominance Monthly Chart" class="wp-image-683498" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV.jpg 2048w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV-360x234.jpg 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV-850x553.jpg 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV-768x500.jpg 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV-1536x999.jpg 1536w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/GnhSufKWMAA8-fV-150x98.jpg 150w" sizes="(max-width: 2048px) 100vw, 2048px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Bitcoin Dominance Monthly Chart. Source: <a href="https://x.com/Ashcryptoreal/status/1907365414222397860" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Ash Crypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/bitcoin-dominance-chart/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin Dominance</a> (BTC.D) represents Bitcoin’s market capitalization relative to the total crypto market cap. When BTC.D declines, it signals that capital flows into altcoins instead of Bitcoin. </p>



<p>Currently, BTC.D remains above 60% with no signs of weakening. Ash Crypto’s forecast strengthens the belief that Q2 and Q3 of 2025 could begin a significant altcoin rally.</p>



<p>Additionally, experienced trader Merlijn agrees with this outlook. In a recent post on X, he predicted that an altcoin season similar to 2021 is approaching. He highlighted that the next three to six months will be crucial for investors to shape their portfolios.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Altcoin season is setting up—just like in 2021… The next 3–6 months could define your portfolio.” — Merlijn The Trader <a href="https://x.com/MerlijnTrader/status/1906768455598236003" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">predicted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>However, a recent analysis from BeInCrypto reported that the Crypto Fear &amp; Greed Index <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-fear-and-greed-index-recency-bias/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">has dropped to 25 points</a>, indicating &#8220;Extreme Fear.&#8221; Concerns over <a href="https://beincrypto.com/china-imposes-34-tariff-on-us/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">escalating trade wars</a> are intensifying investor anxiety.</p>



<p>Some analysts, such as Coin Bureau founder Nic Puckrin, believe that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/bitcoin-is-far-from-a-bear-market-analysts-claim-us-morning-crypto-briefing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bitcoin is far from a bear market</a>, but the future of several altcoins is questionable. </p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/analyst-believe-q2-will-be-altcoin-season/">Analysts Believe Q2 is a Great Opportunity to Buy Altcoins</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-5.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/bic_altcoins_alt_coins-covers_neutral-5.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Altcoins Break Five-Week Streak of Negative Flows as Crypto Inflows Hit $226 Million</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-break-negative-flows-inflows-hit-226-million/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 13:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News About Ethereum (ETH)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solana (SOL) News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=681518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crypto markets show cautious optimism as altcoins end a five-week streak of outflows, with analysts predicting a potential recovery and rally in the near future.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-break-negative-flows-inflows-hit-226-million/">Altcoins Break Five-Week Streak of Negative Flows as Crypto Inflows Hit $226 Million</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Crypto inflows hit $226 million last week, signaling a cautiously optimistic investor sentiment amid ongoing market volatility.</strong></p>



<p>According to CoinShares data, altcoins broke a five-week streak of negative flows, recording their first inflows in over a month.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-crypto-inflows-hit-226-million-last-week">Crypto Inflows Hit $226 Million Last Week</h2>



<p>This turnout marks a significant slowdown from the previous week when crypto inflows hit <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-inflows-surge-644-million-recovery/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">$644 million</a>, ending a five-week outflow streak. Before that, inflows peaked at $1.3 billion, with <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-inflows-exceed-1-billion-despite-market-crash/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum outpacing Bitcoin in investor demand</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Digital asset investment products saw $226 million of inflows last week suggesting a positive but cautious investor,&#8221; <a href="https://blog.coinshares.com/volume-227-digital-asset-fund-flows-weekly-report-b8acc1fc9411" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">read</a> an excerpt in the report.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The pullback to $226 million last week suggests a more measured approach by investors as they assess macroeconomic conditions and regulatory uncertainties.</p>



<p>Specifically, CoinShares’ researcher James Butterfill ascribes Friday&#8217;s minor outflows of $74 million to core <a href="https://beincrypto.com/us-economic-events-bitcoin-sentiment/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">personal consumption expenditure (PCE) in the US</a>, which came in above expectations.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The Fed&#8217;s preferred measure of inflation (Core PCE) moved up to 2.8% in February &amp; remains well above their 2% target that has yet to be achieved. The market is expecting the Fed to hold rates steady again at their next meeting on May 7 (at 4.25-4.50%),” investor Charlie Bilello <a href="https://x.com/charliebilello/status/1905604401844072575" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">noted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Nevertheless, this turnaround comes after nine consecutive trading days of inflows into <a href="https://beincrypto.com/blackrock-expands-bitcoin-etps-europe/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">crypto ETPs</a> (exchange-traded products).</p>



<p>Despite the slowdown, Bitcoin continued to attract strong inflows of $195 million. Meanwhile, short-Bitcoin products registered outflows of $2.5 million for the fourth consecutive week. This suggests that investors are leaning bullish on Bitcoin, even as altcoins begin to recover.</p>



<p>The CoinShares report shows that altcoins saw $33 million in inflows last week after suffering $1.7 billion in outflows over the past month.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-altcoins-rebound-after-1-7-billion-in-outflows">Altcoins Rebound After $1.7 Billion in Outflows</h2>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/buy-ethereum" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum (ETH)</a> led the recovery, attracting $14.5 million, then <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/what-is-solana" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Solana (SOL)</a> at $7.8 million, while XRP and Sui recorded $4.8 million and $4.0 million, respectively. Market analysts believe altcoins may be bottoming out, creating potential buying opportunities.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Altcoins are oversold. The bottom is close. We&#8217;re ready for a bounce,&#8221; renowned analyst Crypto Rover <a href="https://x.com/rovercrc/status/1903864570210558402" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">highlighted</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Other analysts echoed the sentiment, suggesting growing attention toward altcoins. Among them was trader Thomas Kralow, who <a href="https://x.com/TKralow/status/1903952331600761190" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">said</a>, “altcoins are setting up for a comeback.&#8221; </p>



<p>Adding credence to this bullish outlook for altcoins, project researcher BitcoinHabebe, known for insightful mid-low cap sniper entries, pointed to technical indicators suggesting a market reversal.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;While bears are trying to spread fear &amp; make you sell your altcoins, the TOTAL3 [Altcoins market cap chart excluding Bitcoin and Ethereum] just bounced off an HTF [higher timeframe] retest,&#8221; the analyst <a href="https://x.com/Bitcoinhabebe/status/1903772260827091259" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This means most coins have bottomed out and are expected to start reversing soon. Cole Garner noted a key buy signal in market liquidity metrics, further supporting this view.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Tether Ratio Channel already flashed a double buy signal this month. Now my lower timeframe version is popping off. Fresh capital incoming,” he <a href="https://x.com/ColeGarnersTake/status/1904410239501557889" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">indicated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The Tether Ratio Channel is an on-chain analytical tool that helps traders identify potential buy signals. It tracks the ratio of Bitcoin’s market capitalization to that of stablecoins, acting as a leading indicator for short- to medium-term trends.</p>



<p>When the ratio hits certain levels, it can signal shifts in market sentiment, often indicating whether fresh capital is entering or exiting the market.</p>



<p>While overall crypto inflows have slowed compared to previous weeks, the return of capital into altcoins suggests renewed investor confidence. Analysts see signs of an impending altcoin rally, with market metrics indicating that most coins have bottomed out.</p>



<p>As investors weigh <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-markets-under-pressure-key-us-data/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">macroeconomic uncertainties</a>, the coming weeks could be critical in determining whether the altcoin recovery sustains momentum or if caution prevails.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/altcoins-break-negative-flows-inflows-hit-226-million/">Altcoins Break Five-Week Streak of Negative Flows as Crypto Inflows Hit $226 Million</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_positive_evening_sand_desert_mountains.jpg" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/bic_altcoins_positive_evening_sand_desert_mountains.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Week In Crypto: Pi Network DEX, Trump Media’s Crypto.com Play, Grayscale&#8217;s Altcoin List, and More</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/weekly-crypto-roundup-pi-network-trump-media-grayscale/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meme Coin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News about Bitcoin (BTC)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pi Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trump]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=680872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week in crypto, Pi Network launched PiDaoSwap to combat price manipulation, Trump Media partnered with Crypto.com, and Grayscale expanded its altcoin investments.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/weekly-crypto-roundup-pi-network-trump-media-grayscale/">This Week In Crypto: Pi Network DEX, Trump Media’s Crypto.com Play, Grayscale&#8217;s Altcoin List, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Several big stories and developments have occurred in the crypto space this week, including&nbsp;innovations in the Pi Network ecosystem, Grayscale updating its list of investible altcoins, and Donald Trump’s crypto play.</strong></p>



<p>In case you missed these developments, among others, the following is a roundup of what happened in crypto this week.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-pi-network-introduces-pidaoswap">Pi Network Introduces PiDaoSwap</h2>



<p>Pi Network took a key step in <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/decentralized-finance-and-use-cases" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decentralized finance (DeFi)</a> this week, revealing the development of PiDaoSwap. This community-driven <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/decentralized-exchanges" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decentralized exchange</a> (DEX) is designed to counter price manipulation.</p>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/pi-network-pidaoswap-dex-price-manipulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PiDaoSwap aims to stabilize Pi Coin’s value</a> and enhance trust within its ecosystem by ensuring fair trading mechanisms.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>“</strong>Once completed, the Pi price will be reflected at its true value and will no longer be manipulated by current external exchanges,” Pi Network VietNames&nbsp;<a href="https://x.com/PiNetworkVNes/status/1902917568060592565" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">claimed</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Another positive development in the Pi Network ecosystem this week is the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/pi-network-telegram-crypto-wallet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">integration with Telegram’s crypto wallet</a>. This move could provide access to up to one billion users and expand the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/is-pi-network-a-scam-what-you-need-to-know" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">controversial project’s</a> mainstream adoption.</p>



<p>While this move reflects Pi Network’s growing influence, questions around decentralization and exchange listings continue to loom large. Specifically, the Pi Network remains under scrutiny due to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/pi-network-scrutiny-centralization-supernodes/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concerns about its centralization</a>, particularly its SuperNodes.</p>



<p>Critics argue that a heavily centralized network undermines the core principles of blockchain technology. Adding to the debate, analysts have pointed out that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-coinbase-pi-network-pi-coin-listing/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pi Network’s absence from major exchanges like Binance and Coinbase</a> stems from concerns over its operational transparency.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-trump-media-partners-with-crypto-com">Trump Media Partners with Crypto.com </h2>



<p>Another hot headline this week in crypto <span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">was </span><a href="https://beincrypto.com/trump-media-crypto-com-partnership-cronos-surges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">Trump Media&#8217;s announcement of</span> a partnership with Crypto.com</a>. The collaboration lays the groundwork for launching new ETFs (exchange-traded funds) based on Cronos, Bitcoin, and other assets. </p>



<p>The report inspired a nearly 20% surge in the Cronos (CRO) token, the powering token for the Crypto.com ecosystem. This collaboration added to the list of notable shifts as Trump’s media venture embraces cryptocurrency. </p>



<p>However, blockchain investigator <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-com-cro-token-reissuance-trump-partnership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">ZachXBT raised concerns about Crypto.com’s token manipulation practices</a>, souring sentiment for this partnership. Citing its re-issuance, the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/zachxbt-crypto-scam" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">blockchain sleuth</a> suggested the exchange may engage in opaque financial maneuvers.</p>



<p>Despite these concerns, Crypto.com emerged unscathed as the US SEC (Securities and Exchange Commission) <a href="https://beincrypto.com/crypto-com-sues-sec/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">concluded its investigation</a> without filing any charges.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The SEC’s investigation into Crypto.com has been closed with no action being taken against Crypto.com. I continue to be proud of how this industry and its community have weathered storm after storm… The fact that we not only persevered but became stronger is a testament to our vision and the community supporting it,” <a href="https://x.com/kris/status/1905401337631936684" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">wrote</a> Kris Marszalek, CEO of Crypto.com.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The announcement led to a notable jump in CRO’s price, reaffirming investor confidence in the exchange despite previous regulatory scrutiny.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1211" height="517" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98.png" alt="Cronos (CRO) Price Performance" class="wp-image-680882" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98.png 1211w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98-360x154.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98-850x363.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98-768x328.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-98-150x64.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 1211px) 100vw, 1211px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cronos (CRO) Price Performance. Source: <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/crypto-com-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">BeInCrypto</a></figcaption></figure>



<p>BeInCrypto <a href="https://beincrypto.com/price/crypto-com-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">data shows</a> CRO was trading for $0.11 as of this writing, up by over 4% in the last 24 hours.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gamestop-s-bitcoin-announcement">GameStop’s Bitcoin Announcement</h2>



<p>GameStop, the once-legendary meme stock, also made headlines this week in crypto. It announced an update to its investment policy, revealing that&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-to-buy-bitcoin-after-earnings-report/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">it had added Bitcoin as a Treasury Reserve Asset</a>. In the immediate aftermath of this announcement, the company’s&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/gamestop-bitcoin-purchase-stock-surges/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">stock prices jumped 12%</a>&nbsp;before profit booking set in.</p>



<p>While this could have been a bullish catalyst, Bitcoin’s price remained largely unmoved. Analysts suggest the announcement lacked crucial details to trigger excitement and provoke a significant market reaction.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The announcement lacked key details —most importantly, how much Bitcoin they’re actually buying. While they’re sitting on about $4.8 billion in cash, we’ve seen no indication of what portion, if any, will be allocated to BTC,” Mati Greenspan, Founder and CEO of Quantum Economics, told BeInCrypto.&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Further, the price impact for BTC was muted, given that Bitcoin payments are becoming more common among retailers.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-grayscale-updates-investment-list">Grayscale Updates Investment List</h2>



<p>Adding to the list of what happened this week in crypto, Grayscale updated its list of investable altcoins for Q2 2025. The institutional crypto asset manager added three new tokens, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/maple-finance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Maple Finance</a> (SYRUP), Geodnet (GEOD), and Story Protocol (IP)<strong>,</strong> to its top 20 crypto investments.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“…We believe the revised Top 20 list may offer more compelling risk-adjusted returns for the coming quarter​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​​​​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌​​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌‌‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌​​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​,” the firm <a href="https://research.grayscale.com/market-commentary/grayscale-research-insights-crypto-sectors-in-q2-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">explained</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>This move reflects the company’s ongoing strategy to diversify its holdings and identify emerging digital assets with strong growth potential. At the same time, it truncated three altcoins from the same list- <a href="https://beincrypto.com/akash-network-ai-model-training/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Akash Network (AKT)</a>, Arweave (AR), and&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/jupiter-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jupiter (JUP)</a>.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-binance-embraces-studio-ghibli-meme-coins-frenzy">Binance Embraces Studio Ghibli Meme Coins Frenzy</h2>



<p>Elsewhere, a new <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/meme-coins" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coin craze</a> emerged this week in crypto, drawing inspiration from the beloved Studio Ghibli brand. Binance Alpha responded to the trend by <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-alpha-lists-studio-ghibli-meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">listing two Ghibli-themed tokens</a>, Ghiblification and GhibliCZ.</p>



<p>These tokens have gained rapid traction as part of a broader wave of AI and pop culture-driven crypto speculation. The <a href="https://beincrypto.com/studio-ghibli-openai-meme-coins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ghibli meme coin phenomenon</a> follows a pattern in previous meme-inspired tokens, where hype and social media engagement drive price action more than actual utility.</p>



<p>While some traders see opportunities for quick gains, others caution against speculative bubbles that could lead to rapid market corrections. Nevertheless, Binance&#8217;s involvement reflects how major exchanges capitalize on trending narratives to attract trading volume.</p>



<p>This strategy, which continues to shape the DeFi space, has also drawn criticism as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/mass-token-listings-centralized-exchanges-debate/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">users challenge the listing standards of centralized exchanges</a> (CEXs).</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/weekly-crypto-roundup-pi-network-trump-media-grayscale/">This Week In Crypto: Pi Network DEX, Trump Media’s Crypto.com Play, Grayscale&#8217;s Altcoin List, and More</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/bic_roundup_weekly_news_3.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/bic_roundup_weekly_news_3.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Binance&#8217;s CZ Defends Mass CEX Token Listings While Critics Call for More Transparency</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/mass-token-listings-centralized-exchanges-debate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 12:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binance News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meme Coin News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=680757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The growing trend of mass token listings on centralized exchanges has sparked a debate. Critics worry about declining quality, while others see it as a way to desensitize markets and boost competition.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/mass-token-listings-centralized-exchanges-debate/">Binance&#8217;s CZ Defends Mass CEX Token Listings While Critics Call for More Transparency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Crypto market participants, traders, and investors are increasingly divided over the consequences of mass token listings on centralized exchanges (CEXs).</strong></p>



<p>As the discourse intensifies on token listings on CEXs, some industry figures warn of deteriorating listing standards. Meanwhile, others argue that an open listing approach will ultimately benefit the market.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-analysts-challenge-mass-listings-on-cexs">Analysts Challenge Mass Listings on CEXs</h2>



<p>Benjamin Cowen, a crypto analyst and founder of Cryptoverse, shared his concerns regarding the declining quality of tokens listed on major exchanges. He criticized exchanges for promoting long-term investing while listing low-quality &#8220;shitcoins,&#8221; highlighting their <a href="https://x.com/intocryptoverse/status/1905429403347153123" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">hypocrisy</a> in the crypto market.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Some crypto exchanges are listing shittier and shittier coins. They’ll tell you to focus on fundamentals and long-term investing one day, and then list the most useless garbage no one has even heard of the next,&#8221; he <a href="https://x.com/intocryptoverse/status/1905428308180816301" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">stated</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Another analyst, Colin Talks Crypto, further <a href="https://x.com/ColinTCrypto/status/1905428791305904418" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">argued</a> that the primary motivation behind these listings is to profit from <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/explaining-bitcoin-transaction-fees" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">transaction fees</a> rather than the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/investors-meme-coins-to-altcoins/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">quality of the projects</a>. Other voices in the debate suggested that exchanges focus on listing tokens when trending and remove them when interest fades.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;They want volume and fees and list when it’s hit and delist when it gets cold. CEXs this cycle have been showing us why DEXs are the future,&#8221; an X user <a href="https://x.com/inversedpowers/status/1905429165475561914" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">remarked</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Indeed, this aligns with the hallmark of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/binance-review" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Binance Exchange’s</a> delisting guideline. As BeInCrypto reported, the trading platform commits to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-altcoins-delisting-risk-10-tokens/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">reviewing the performance of its listed trading pairs</a>. It removes tokens and trading pairs not meeting liquidity and volume thresholds.</p>



<p>Recent <a href="https://www.binance.com/en/support/announcement/list/48" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">listings</a> on Binance, including <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/meme-coins" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">meme coins</a> from the BNB Chain, such as <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hyperliquid-jelly-incident-response/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">JELLY</a>, have fueled these criticisms. Against this backdrop, crypto influencer Leonidas expressed frustration with Binance.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>&#8220;Your listing team just spot-listed four low-cap insider-controlled meme coins that nobody has ever heard of&#8230; I&#8217;ve watched for the past year as you guys have listed $10m-$20m garbage meme coins over and over while ignoring the largest market cap memecoins with real communities,” the analyst <a href="https://x.com/LeonidasNFT/status/1905377187555098629" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">lamented</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Others also <a href="https://x.com/its_me_niick/status/1905379016896606318" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">speculated</a> that centralized exchanges might engage in pre-listing accumulation before selling to retail investors. &nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-the-case-for-mass-listings-on-centralized-exchanges">The Case for Mass Listings on Centralized Exchanges</h2>



<p>Despite these criticisms, some experts argue that mass listings could benefit the market in the long run. Jason Chen believes that accelerating token listings will desensitize the market. In his opinion, this would remove the speculative hype around new listings and foster a more competitive trading environment.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“There will no longer be a listing effect, no more premium, and everything will return to a free game state,&#8221; Chen <a href="https://x.com/jason_chen998/status/1905275224427553233" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">explained</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p><a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/changpeng-zhao-guide" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Changpeng Zhao</a> (CZ), Binance&#8217;s founder, agreed with this perspective, noting that listing a coin should not affect the price. While listing provides liquidity, allowing for freer entry and exit, it may influence the price in the short term.</p>



<p>However, according to CZ, this should be very short-term. In the long run, prices should be determined by the project&#8217;s development. This also aligns with Binance’s listing and delisting criteria, which analyze elements such as the team’s commitment to the project, the level and quality of development activity, and the network and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/smart-contracts/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">smart contract stability</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“The DEX model is very good. All coins are listed and people can choose for themselves,&#8221; CZ <a href="https://x.com/cz_binance/status/1905501199924953204" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">added</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Crypto trader Paul Wei also supported this argument but <a href="https://x.com/coolish/status/1905507960941686924" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">cautioned</a> against oversimplifying the relationship between listings and long-term valuations. He also challenged CZ&#8217;s view that coin listings on CEXs like Binance do not influence long-term prices, arguing that listings affect a project&#8217;s &#8220;development&#8221; by enabling freer trading, which shapes price trends.</p>



<p>Meanwhile<span style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px;">, recent controversies, such as the <a href="https://beincrypto.com/hyperliquid-jelly-token-market-manipulation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Hyperliquid JELLY token incident</a>, highlight the growing divide between CEXs and&nbsp;<a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/decentralized-exchanges" target="_blank" rel="noopener">decentralized exchanges</a>&nbsp;(DEXs). BeInCrypto reported allegations of market manipulation</span>. This has fueled skepticism over centralized exchanges&#8217; practices, hence the CEX vs. DEX crypto debate. </p>



<p>Critics argue that such cases demonstrate the advantages of DEXs, where token listings are unrestricted, and market forces dictate valuations without centralized intervention.</p>



<p>Amidst this ongoing debate, CZ articulated that <a href="https://beincrypto.com/coinbase-support-bnb-perpetual-futures/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Coinbase&#8217;s recent decision to list BNB perpetual futures</a> was purely on merit. It is also worth noting that Binance recently resolved to <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-list-delist-bnb-chain-tokens/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">include users in its listing and delisting actions</a>, fostering democracy.</p>



<p>The exchange also <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-secondary-listings-binance-wallet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">adopted a secondary listing mechanism</a>. Instead of exclusively listing new tokens on its&nbsp;centralized exchange, it will <a href="https://beincrypto.com/binance-wallet-pancakeswap-kiloex-tge-collaboration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">leverage Binance Wallet to facilitate token launches</a> on&nbsp;decentralized platforms.</p>




<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/mass-token-listings-centralized-exchanges-debate/">Binance&#8217;s CZ Defends Mass CEX Token Listings While Critics Call for More Transparency</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Changpeng_Zhao_CZ-covers_negative_3.jpg" medium="image" width="1920" height="1080" type="image/jpeg" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/bic_Changpeng_Zhao_CZ-covers_negative_3.jpg"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grayscale Adds 3 Altcoins to Its Top 20 Crypto Investment List for Q2 2025</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-top-20-list-altcoins-q2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lockridge Okoth]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 11:06:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DeFi News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DePin News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokenization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=679666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Grayscale's latest update introduces Maple Finance, Geodnet, and Story Protocol, signaling growth opportunities in decentralized finance, geospatial tech, and IP tokenization.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-top-20-list-altcoins-q2/">Grayscale Adds 3 Altcoins to Its Top 20 Crypto Investment List for Q2 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>Grayscale Research has released its updated Top 20 list of digital assets, identifying key cryptocurrencies with strong potential for the coming quarter.</strong></p>



<p>The firm updates this curated selection quarterly, reflecting its analysis of network adoption, market trends, and fundamental sustainability.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-grayscale-adds-3-altcoins-to-investment-consideration-list">Grayscale Adds 3 Altcoins to Investment Consideration List</h2>



<p>The latest update introduces three new assets—Maple (SYRUP), Geodnet (GEOD), and Story Protocol (IP). This suggests an inclination toward real-world applications in decentralized finance (DeFi), <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/depin-guide/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">decentralized physical infrastructure networks</a> (DePIN), and intellectual property (IP) <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/blockchain-tokenization" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">tokenization</a>.</p>



<p>Grayscale organizes the digital asset market into five distinct crypto sectors: currencies, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/smart-contracts-explainer" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">smart contract</a> platforms, financials, consumer &amp; culture, and utilities &amp; services. This framework allows the firm to track industry trends and assess high-growth opportunities within each category.</p>



<p>With the latest rebalancing, the crypto sectors now encompass 227 distinct assets with a total market capitalization of $2.6 trillion, covering the vast majority of the global crypto market.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="946" height="534" src="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86.png" alt="Grayscale’s Top 20 altcoin features SYRUP, GEOD, and IP​​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌​​​‌​‌‌​‌‌​​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​​​​​​​​&#x200d;​​‌​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌‌‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌​​​‌​‌‌​‌‌​​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​​​​​​​​&#x200d;​​‌​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌" class="wp-image-679668" style="width:1024px;height:auto" srcset="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86.png 946w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86-360x203.png 360w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86-850x480.png 850w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86-768x434.png 768w, https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/BMTUSDT_E7334A_2025-03-11_11-54-20-86-150x85.png 150w" sizes="(max-width: 946px) 100vw, 946px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Grayscale’s Top 20 altcoin features SYRUP, GEOD, and IP​​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌​​​‌​‌‌​‌‌​​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​​​​​​​​&#x200d;​​‌​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌‌‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌​​​‌​‌‌​‌‌​​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​​​​​​​​&#x200d;​​‌​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌. Source: <a href="https://research.grayscale.com/market-commentary/grayscale-research-insights-crypto-sectors-in-q2-2025" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Grayscale</a></figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-maple-finance-syrup">Maple Finance (SYRUP)</h3>



<p>Maple Finance (SYRUP) is a leading <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/decentralized-finance-and-use-cases" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DeFi protocol</a> specializing in institutional <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/cryptocurrency-lending-platform" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">lending</a>. The project operates through two core platforms: Maple Institutional, designed for accredited investors, and Syrup.fi, which serves DeFi-native users.</p>



<p>Over the past year, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/maple-finance/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Maple Finance</a> has grown significantly, reaching $600 million in Total Value Locked (TVL) and $20 million in annualized network fee revenue. The project aims to scale Syrup.fi to $2 billion in TVL by integrating with other <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/top-defi-protocols" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">DeFi protocols</a>, including <a href="https://beincrypto.com/arthur-hayes-sells-pendle/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Pendle (PENDLE)</a>.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-geodnet-geod">Geodnet (GEOD)</h3>



<p>Meanwhile, Geodnet (GEOD) has emerged as a leader in the DePIN space. As the world’s largest real-time kinematic positioning provider, the network offers geospatial data with centimeter-level accuracy. It serves industries such as agriculture, robotics, and autonomous vehicles.</p>



<p>The network has expanded to include more than 14,000 active devices across 130 countries and has seen its revenue grow substantially. Annualized network fees increased by 500% year-over-year (YoY) to $3 million.</p>



<p>Geodnet’s decentralized approach presents a cost-effective alternative to centralized GPS solutions, positioning it as a critical infrastructure provider in the blockchain space.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading" id="h-story-protocol-ip">Story Protocol (IP)</h3>



<p>Story Protocol (IP) is tackling the growing intellectual property space by bringing IP rights onto the blockchain. With AI-generated content sparking copyright disputes, Story Protocol offers a way for companies and creators to monetize their intellectual property. At the same time, it enables investors to trade and earn royalties.</p>



<p>The project has already onboarded high-profile assets, including music rights for Justin Bieber, BTS, <a href="https://beincrypto.com/story-protocol-tokenizes-music-copyrights/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Maroon 5, and Katy Perry</a>. It also launched its dedicated IP-focused blockchain and token in February 2025.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-grayscale-removes-3-altcoins-from-its-list-of-investible-products">Grayscale Removes 3 Altcoins From its List of Investible Products</h2>



<p>The latest update also includes the removal of three assets from the Top 20 list, comprising <a href="https://beincrypto.com/akash-network-ai-model-training/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Akash Network (AKT)</a>, Arweave (AR), and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/jupiter-explained/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Jupiter (JUP)</a>.</p>



<blockquote class="max-w-xl text-4.5 border-l-2 border-blue-600 pl-11 mb-9 select-all [&#038;_p]:!mb-0 wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>“Grayscale Research continues to see value in each of these projects, and they remain important elements of the crypto ecosystem. However, we believe the revised Top 20 list may offer more compelling risk-adjusted returns for the coming quarter​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​​​​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌​​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌‌‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌‌​‌‌​‌​​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​‌​&#x200d;​​‌​‌&#x200d;​​​‌​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌​‌‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌​​​​‌​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌​​​‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌​‌​​​​​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​​‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​​​​‌&#x200d;​‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​‌​​‌​​​​&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌​‌​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​​&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​‌​‌​​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;​​‌​&#x200d;‌‌​​&#x200d;​​&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌‌​‌​​&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌​&#x200d;‌​‌​​‌&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;​‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌‌&#x200d;‌&#x200d;‌‌​‌‌​​‌‌‌‌&#x200d;​&#x200d;‌&#x200d;​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;‌‌​‌&#x200d;&#x200d;​,&#8221; the firm explained.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Beyond these new additions, Grayscale continues to highlight key investment themes. These include <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/layer-2-scaling-solutions" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ethereum scaling solutions</a>, AI-integrated blockchain development, and DeFi and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/crypto-staking" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">staking innovations</a>. The continued inclusion of assets like <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/optimism" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Optimism (OP)</a>, Bittensor (TAO), and <a href="https://beincrypto.com/learn/lido-staked-eth" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Lido DAO (LDO)</a> reflects the firm’s focus on these high-growth areas.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the latest Top 20 update follows Grayscale’s broader expansion into evaluating additional digital assets. In January 2025, the firm revealed <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-announces-new-investible-digital-assets/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">nearly 40 altcoins under investment consideration</a>. Similarly, Grayscale announced a list of <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-reveals-35-altcoins-under-consideration/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">35 assets for potential inclusion</a> in investment products in October.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/grayscale-top-20-list-altcoins-q2/">Grayscale Adds 3 Altcoins to Its Top 20 Crypto Investment List for Q2 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/bic_Grayscale-covers_neutral_3.png" medium="image" width="1280" height="720" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/02/bic_Grayscale-covers_neutral_3.png"/>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Frontier of Altcoin Futures Trading: Gate.io’s Ecosystem Innovation and Market Evolution</title>
		<link>https://beincrypto.com/the-new-frontier-of-altcoin-futures-trading-gate-ios-ecosystem-innovation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Advertorial]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 09:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Altcoin news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gate.io News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://beincrypto.com/?p=674993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the vast landscape of the cryptocurrency market, altcoin futures trading is emerging as a promising new frontier. As competition in major cryptocurrency markets intensifies, trading opportunities become increasingly constrained, bringing the potential of long-tail markets into focus. At the same time, the explosive growth of emerging altcoins is presenting traders with unprecedented opportunities and &#8230; <a href="https://beincrypto.com/the-new-frontier-of-altcoin-futures-trading-gate-ios-ecosystem-innovation/">Continued</a></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/the-new-frontier-of-altcoin-futures-trading-gate-ios-ecosystem-innovation/">The New Frontier of Altcoin Futures Trading: Gate.io’s Ecosystem Innovation and Market Evolution</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the vast landscape of the cryptocurrency market, altcoin <a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">futures</a> trading is emerging as a promising new frontier. As competition in major cryptocurrency markets intensifies, trading opportunities become increasingly constrained, bringing the potential of long-tail markets into focus. At the same time, the explosive growth of emerging altcoins is presenting traders with unprecedented opportunities and challenges.</p>



<p>However, this sector also faces several obstacles: limited trading channels, insufficient liquidity, and inefficiencies in accessing crucial market information. Against this backdrop, Gate.io has established itself as a leader in the altcoin futures trading ecosystem, leveraging its deep expertise and innovative strategies to provide traders with a comprehensive, efficient, and secure trading environment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-core-market-demand-and-pain-points-the-double-edged-sword-of-altcoin-trading"><strong>Core Market Demand and Pain Points: The Double-Edged Sword of Altcoin Trading</strong></h2>



<p>The appeal of altcoin <a href="https://www.gate.io/futures/USDT/BTC_USDT/?ch=GM_futuresbein_20250207&amp;utm_campaign=TR_gWCKoaJq&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=PR&amp;utm_source=CH_KycJ7zKG&amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Futures</a> trading lies in its high volatility, which offers lucrative arbitrage opportunities. However, this same volatility also carries significant risks. While mainstream crypto markets are saturated with intense competition, squeezing traders’ profit margins, the long-tail market remains relatively untapped.</p>



<p>The explosive growth of new altcoins has attracted the attention of numerous investors, yet trading channels remain scarce, preventing many potential opportunities from being fully realized. Additionally, the sector is plagued by several persistent challenges:</p>



<p>First of all, altcoins typically have lower trading volumes and limited market depth, leading to higher slippage costs to traders when executing trades. Second, many exchanges in the market now offer a narrow range of altcoin futures products, lacking diversity in futures genres and flexible trading mechanisms, which restricts traders’ strategic options.</p>



<p>In addition, market information on altcoins is often fragmented, requiring traders to invest significant time and effort in research. Moreover, outdated or inaccurate information can further widen the gap between information access and execution efficiency.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-gate-io-s-ecosystem-innovation-a-breakthrough-in-altcoin-futures-trading"><strong>Gate.io’s Ecosystem Innovation: A Breakthrough in Altcoin Futures Trading</strong></h2>



<p>Amid these market challenges, Gate.io has pioneered innovative solutions to establish itself as a game-changer in altcoin Futures trading. By offering a secure, efficient, and comprehensive trading platform, Gate.io addresses key pain points and fosters a dynamic ecosystem tailored to traders’ needs.</p>



<p><strong>Product Innovation: Expanding Choices and Accelerating Market Response</strong></p>



<p>Gate.io has made bold innovations in its altcoin perpetual futures offerings, providing one of the industry’s most extensive selections of perpetual futures. Whether for trending or newly emerging altcoins, traders can find corresponding perpetual products on Gate.io. This broad selection not only meets diverse trading demands but also increases opportunities for capturing market movements.</p>



<p>Gate.io has introduced a mechanism to simultaneously launch the futures for new coins, ensuring that newly listed altcoins have corresponding perpetual futures offerings at launch. This allows traders to engage in futures trading at the earliest opportunity, fulfilling their need for exposure to emerging markets. Moreover, this mechanism benefits projects by providing enhanced visibility and liquidity, creating a win-win scenario for the platform, traders, and token issuers.</p>



<p>Additionally, Gate.io implements a dynamic listing mechanism, swiftly introducing high-potential altcoin futures based on emerging market trends. This agile response ensures traders can participate in trending altcoin markets without delay, capturing short-term price change and market opportunities.</p>



<p><strong>Liquidity Enhanced: Market-Maker Ecosystem and Efficient Matching</strong></p>



<p>Liquidity constraints have long been a core issue in altcoin trading. To address this, Gate.io has developed an innovative liquidity solution through its Gate.io Market Maker Program (GMMC), fostering a robust market-maker ecosystem.</p>



<p>Eligible trading teams can apply to join the GMMC program, gaining access to competitive market-making fee rates as low as -0.015%, maker rebates on spot and USDT-margined perpetual futures, market-wide maker fee rates of -0.015% for BTC and ETH spot trading, a 400,000 USDT interest-free loan quota, exclusive 1-on-1 VIP client support and quarterly top market maker rewards, and even more rewards.</p>



<p>In addition to this incentive structure, Gate.io has optimized its order-matching system through advanced technology, enabling high-speed execution. This ensures that orders are matched efficiently with minimal latency, reducing slippage and enhancing the overall trading experience. During periods of rapid market fluctuations, this high-performance matching system prevents execution delays, ensuring traders capitalize on optimal entry and exit points.</p>



<p><strong>Intelligent Risk Control: A Solid Foundation for Secure Trading</strong></p>



<p>Risk management is crucial in altcoin futures trading. Gate.io has implemented a multi-layered risk control framework to provide traders with a secure and reliable trading environment.</p>



<p>The tiered liquidation mechanism is a more scientific and rational risk control method. When a user’s position faces liquidation risk, the platform liquidates the position in stages based on the user’s holdings and market conditions, rather than enforcing a full liquidation at once. This mechanism helps minimize user losses to a certain extent and prevents excessive liquidation caused by short-term market fluctuations.</p>



<p>Additionally, Gate.io has introduced a tiered margin rate mechanism, where the platform sets different margin rates according to the user’s position size. The core purpose of this design is to reduce users’ capital pressure and encourage them to manage their position sizes more reasonably.</p>



<p>For example, when a user holds a smaller position, the margin rate remains relatively low, allowing them to trade with less capital. As the position size increases, the margin rate rises accordingly to ensure sufficient risk coverage. Thus, the tiered margin rate mechanism not only meets users’ needs for flexible trading but also effectively controls trading risks, providing a safer and more reliable trading environment.</p>



<h2 class="bic-gutenberg-heading wp-heading wp-block-heading" id="h-empowering-the-altcoin-trading-ecosystem-with-gate-io-s-full-support"><strong>Empowering the Altcoin Trading Ecosystem with Gate.io’s Full Support</strong></h2>



<p><strong>Launch-First Ecosystem Advantage: Deep Diving into Altcoin Trading</strong></p>



<p>Gate.io was among the earliest platforms to establish a strong presence in the altcoin futures trading market. Leveraging its sharp market insight and forward-looking strategies, Gate.io has developed deep expertise and a competitive edge in this space.</p>



<p>Through years of dedicated expansion, Gate.io has built a unique advantage in technology, product offerings, and strategic partnerships with altcoin projects while laying a solid foundation for the platform’s consistent growth.</p>



<p>These collaborations enhance market exposure for token issuers while enriching Gate.io’s trading ecosystem with a broad range of perpetual futures products. By maintaining close partnerships with altcoin projects, Gate.io remains at the forefront of market trends, continuously refining its offerings to deliver superior trading experiences.</p>



<p><strong>Value Empowerment Tools: Professional Research and Data Support</strong></p>



<p>Gate.io has a dedicated research and investment team specializing in the analysis of altcoin markets, providing traders with insights into valuable assets and market trend forecasts.</p>



<p>The research team regularly publishes in-depth analysis reports on trending altcoins, evaluating them from multiple dimensions, including technology, fundamentals, and market sentiment. These professional market research reports help traders better understand the dynamics and trends of the altcoin market, enabling them to make more informed trading decisions.</p>



<p>At the same time, Gate.io leverages multi-dimensional on-chain data and sentiment monitoring to provide traders with comprehensive, real-time market information. On-chain data reflects key indicators such as small-cap trading activity, fund flows, and position distribution, while sentiment monitoring captures shifts in market sentiment and trending topics. By aggregating and analyzing these data sources, traders gain a more holistic understanding of market movements and can identify potential trading opportunities in a timely manner.</p>



<p>Additionally, Gate.io offers an extensive trading strategy knowledge base, built upon the collective experience and insights of the community. Traders can share their own strategies and experiences on the platform while also learning from the successes and failures of others. This community-driven strategy-sharing mechanism helps traders expand their perspectives and refine their trading skills.</p>



<p><strong>More Earning Opportunities: Diverse Events and Cumulative Rewards</strong></p>



<p>On the Futures Event page, Gate.io offers a wide range of promotional activities, along with new listing recommendations and real-time trending altcoin insights. Examples include: participating in new altcoin futures trading to share rewards, joining futures trading events to receive GT airdrops, and enrolling in the futures competition, where traders receive USDT rewards upon registration. These diverse promotional initiatives provide traders with lucrative opportunities to earn additional rewards.</p>



<p>Furthermore, traders can benefit from cumulative earnings by engaging in multiple campaigns simultaneously. For example, while trading new altcoin futures, traders can simultaneously register for the Futures Showdown and participate in trade-check-in events, unlocking multiple layers of incentives. This stacking effect of combined rewards not only enhances overall earnings but also deepens traders’ engagement with trending altcoin markets.</p>



<p><strong>A New Era of Discovery Altcoin Value Discovery</strong></p>



<p>Altcoin futures trading represents a frontier filled with both opportunities and challenges—akin to an untamed new continent awaiting exploration. With its cutting-edge ecosystem, Gate.io is redefining the rules of this space.</p>



<p>Through a comprehensive product suite, deep liquidity, intelligent risk management, and value-driven research tools, Gate.io empowers traders to fully execute their trading skills with a list of futures offerings, digging deep into the potential value of altcoins and achieving wealth growth. Start your altcoin futures trading journey with Gate.io today and unlock an exclusive beginner bonus!</p>



<p><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: The content herein does not constitute any offer, solicitation, or recommendation. You should always seek independent professional advice before making any investment decisions. Please be noted that<a href="https://gate.io/"> </a><a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">Gate</a><a href="https://gate.io/">.</a><a href="https://gate.io/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">io</a> may restrict or prohibit the use of all or a portion of the Services from Restricted Locations. For more information, please read the <a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement">Us</a><a href="https://www.gate.io/zh/user-agreement" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener nofollow">er Agreement</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://beincrypto.com/the-new-frontier-of-altcoin-futures-trading-gate-ios-ecosystem-innovation/">The New Frontier of Altcoin Futures Trading: Gate.io’s Ecosystem Innovation and Market Evolution</a> appeared first on <a href="https://beincrypto.com">BeInCrypto</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<media:content url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-17-at-11.53.09-1.png" medium="image" width="2396" height="1336" type="image/png" />
<media:thumbnail url="https://beincrypto.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/03/Screenshot-2025-03-17-at-11.53.09-1.png"/>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
